<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reports | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/reports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T14:41:51-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Reports Do You Need For Your Podcast?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/14/what-reports-do-you-need-for-your-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T08:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/14/what-reports-do-you-need-for-your-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_podcast_report.png" width="300"></p>

<p>For some, podcasting is a creative outlet. It provides a way for
them to build an audience and create relationships and connections
with other like minded people. For the creative types that do
this for fun, having reports to show them how many listeners
they are getting is nice. They get to see how many people they
are potentially influencing, and it may help to drive them to
do more or do better.</p>

<p>For others, though, podcasting is more than just a hobby or an
outlet. It&rsquo;s a way of creating income, of sustaining themselves
or their family. For these podcaster, reports are critical.
They need to see how many downloads an individual episode has.
They need to see trends on what episodes are most effective.
They need to report these numbers to sponsors and potential
sponsors, so they can continue to bring in the income they
need.</p>

<p>With two very distinct audiences to serve, a report system for
a podcast can become overwhelming or underwhelming quickly. A
podcaster looking for simple reports may not care about having
everything. A podcaster that needs everything may get frustrated
at not having enough. Targeting different levels of reprots at
these two different audiences becomes important. But just having
this split doesn&rsquo;t answer the one fundamental question:</p>

<blockquote><p>What reports do you need?</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<h2>SignalLeaf&rsquo;s Current Reports</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m currently offering two different plans in SignalLeaf, to
differentiate between the two different types of reports that
people will need. This boils down to basic reports and advanced
reports, with the goal of serving the two identified audience
groups from above.</p>

<h3>The Basic Reports</h3>

<p>The cheapest plan offers a few very basic reports. At the
podcast, it will give you a total count of plays broken down
by type (rss, downloaded and SignalLeaf player). It will also
show you the total RSS subscriber count.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/basic_podcast_report.png"></p>

<p>At the episode level, this plan offers episode totals, broken
down by the same categories of RSS, downloads and use of the
SignalLeaf player.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/basic_episode_report.png"></p>

<h3>The Advanced Reports</h3>

<p>At the mid level and advanced plans, you&rsquo;ll get a bit more
information and breakdown in both the podcast and episode
reports. You&rsquo;ll get the same basic information, of course, but
the advanced reports add a little more.</p>

<p>The podcast level report offers a 30 day subscriber history,
so you can see the most recent trend of your subscriber count.
You will hopefully be seeing growth over time, but you will
likely see the numbers bouncing up and down on any individual
day. Not everyone has their podcast player open every day,
which means they are not always checking for new episodes.</p>

<p>Additionally, the advanced report will show you current trends
for episodes at a weekly and monthly level. You&rsquo;ll be able to
see which episodes are getting the most plays for these two
time periods.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_podcast_report.png"></p>

<p>At the episode level, you&rsquo;ll get teh same episode totals, but
you&rsquo;ll also see weekly and monthly counts for the episode.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_episode_report.png"></p>

<h2>Totals: A Breakdown By Listen Type</h2>

<p>One of the advantages that SignalLeaf&rsquo;s reports have over others,
is the breakdown of listens by type: RSS, Download and use of
the SignalLeaf player.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/listen_breakdown.png"></p>

<p>This gives you a more accurate picture of how people are finding
and listening to your podcast and episodes. Getting this breakdown
does require you to take advantage of all of SignalLeaf&rsquo;s
features, though. If you&rsquo;re hosting your own RSS feed and
providing your own media player for blog posts through
PowerPress, for example, you won&rsquo;t be able to get this kind
of breakdown. SignalLeaf&rsquo;s RSS, player and direct download
links all contain a tag that tells me what type of listen
is being used. This allows me to capture all of the information
I need for this report, but it means you have to use the
RSS and media player provided by SignalLeaf to take advantage
of it.</p>

<h3>Why Would You Want To?</h3>

<p>A while back, Pat Flynn from
<a href="http://smartpassiveincome.com">Smart Passive Income</a> went through
<a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">a major redesign of the site</a>.
In the process of doing this, <strong>the first version of his
redesign caused a more than 50% drop in his listens!</strong></p>

<p><sub>(Image from <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat&rsquo;s blog post</a>)</sub>
<img src="http://cdn.smartpassiveincome.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/redesigndrop2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Clearly, this is not what he wanted. And clearly, it would have
been nice to prevent this. But Pat did the right thing, and
fixed the site design so that podcast episodes were easier to
find and play. He quickly reacted, fixed the problem and got
his plays back up to where they should be.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the important lesson, though: <strong>if Pat had been using
a report setup like SignalLeaf provides, he would have known
that his audience was largely finding and listening to episodes
through his website, before going through this redesign!</strong>
Having this information could have helped him make better
decisions up front, instead of having to see this massive
drop in plays, after the first release of the website.</p>

<p>Now
that&rsquo;s not to say it would have prevent the drop. You make
decisions based on the information you have, and you adjust
from there. But having this information up front may have
helped. Knowing where the majority of your audience listens
to your episodes will help you to optimize that experience.
Knowing, not guessing or assuming, is important.</p>

<h2>Building Reports Based On Needs</h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the thing: <strong>I understand that these reports are not nearly
as &ldquo;complete&rdquo; as some other services out there.</strong> This is somewhat
intentional. Honestly, I have a lot more data availabe than what
I&rsquo;m currently showing. But <strong>throwing more data at you, just for the
sake of having more reports is not the answer.</strong></p>

<p>The reports that I have in place, and the breakdown of listens
are here because I saw the need for this based on customer
feedback. This is the key and critical part of the reports
that I&rsquo;m building &ndash; <strong>they are based on your neeeds, not just
tossing more information out there in the hopes that I get
soemthing right</strong> and provide some value.</p>

<p><strong>I want to know what reports you need.</strong> I want to know what
information you need to see, and why. I want to know that the
reports you are getting are serving you the way you need
them to serve you. And I want to build new and better reports
based on your needs that are not yet being met.</p>

<p>So drop a comment here. Send me <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">an email</a>.
Get in touch over <a href="http://twitter.com/signalleaf">twitter</a> or
<a href="https://plus.google.com/+DerickBailey/posts/HoCLiT4TJqH">Google+</a> and let me know:</p>

<blockquote><p>What reports do you want and need for your podcast?</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
