<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: file compression | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/file-compression/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-17T13:02:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Audio vs File Compression, And Why You Need Both]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-10T20:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bandwidth for streaming podcasts is expensive, and using it
up with podcast audio that is too quiet, then too loud, then
too quiet again is a giant waste of money. <strong>Fear not!</strong> Just
toss in a little bit of compression and you can <strong>save money,
conserve bandwidth, and please the ears of your listeners</strong>
all at the same time.</p>

<p>But&hellip; audio compression, or file compression? Wait, what&rsquo;s
the difference? I&rsquo;m already exporting to .mp3 files, and
they&rsquo;re compressed, right? Yes, but that&rsquo;s file compression.
Audio compression is something entirely different, and is
just as important. Knowing when you have enough compression
of both kinds is also important, and knowing what they are
and how they affect your podcast is critical.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>File Compression</h2>

<p>Nearly everyone that knows how to use a computer is familiar
with file compression. You&rsquo;ve seen it and its effects more
times than you can count. Ever had a .zip file? Or a .jpg
file (hint: you&rsquo;re looking at some on this site)? These file
extensions are indications of file compression protocols.
Podcasts that use .mp3 files also use compression. Each of
these compression types offers something different, and
specialized, and there are still hundreds (thousands?) of
other file compression types around.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/mp3-export-settings.png"></p>

<p>Delivering audio in a .mp3 file allows files to be much
smaller than other uncompressed formats. But this comes at
a cost. The mp3 format uses a lossy compression algorithm:
a means of compression that reduces the audio quality in order
to reduce the amount of information being stored in the file.
Smaller files come from less information being stored.</p>

<h4>How Much File Compression?</h4>

<p>The effect of a .mp3 file saved at a very low bit rate
is terrible sounding audio in some cases, but not in others.
This is what makes compression somewhat tricky.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re
recording human voices for a podcast, for example, you can
get away with a much lower quality file (lower bit rate).
There isn&rsquo;t a lot of dynamic range of content, or overlapping
content in a human voice &ndash; even with multiple people
speaking at the same time.</p>

<p>When recording musical
instruments, however, low quality audio becomes apparent
very quickly. If you choose a low bit rate for music,
high pitch sounds become distorted in odd ways
and low pitch sounds become muffled and muted. Mid range
sounds can do ok, still, but get mixed up with each other when
multiple instruments are in the same frequency range.  Music
demands a higher bit rate, but not alway the highest.</p>

<h4>Avoid &ldquo;A Copy Of A Copy&rdquo; Syndrome</h4>

<p>One thing you also need to be aware of: if you&rsquo;re importing
existing audio files in to your screencast, be sure they are
high quality to start with.</p>

<p>Why, you might ask? Have you ever made a photocopy of a
photocopy of a photocopy? Compressing already compressed audio
has the same effect. Starting with high quality sound will
ensure the file version sounds as good as possible.</p>

<h2>Audio Compression</h2>

<p>Audio compression can also have a dramatic effect on the
quality of audio, but in a very different way.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/garage-band-compression-settings.png"></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve ever heard a song or a podcast or a radio station
where literally everything came out at exactly the same
volume level &ndash; not matter whether the person was wispering,
or the music was supposed to be subdued and quiet &ndash; you&rsquo;ve
heard the ill-effects of over-compressing audio.</p>

<p>On the opposite end of the spectrum, is classical music. If
you&rsquo;ve ever tried to listen to classical music in a car or
on public transport systems, you&rsquo;ve probably been frustrated
by the near impossible to hear quiet moments followed by
ear-splitting loud moments. This is the effect of no audio
compression at all.</p>

<h4>Controlling Signal Levels (Volume)</h4>

<p>Audio compression is a means of flattening the signal level
for the audio track(s) being compressed. It makes the quiet
parts louder so you can still hear them, and makes the loud
parts quieter so they don&rsquo;t blow your ear drums out.</p>

<p>Too much compression makes everything sound flat. It removes
all of the dynamics of the audio, preventing the natural
ebs and flows of volume differences. It tends to make things
sound over-produced. Radio stations tends to use a ton of
audio compression to compensate for road noise and other
ambient noises in the typical radio lisening environment:
transportation. Classical music, on the other hand, tends
to opt for purity and intent of the conductor and
orechestra, leaving off any audio compression of any kind.
Because of this, classical music is usally best experienced
in quiet places.</p>

<h4>Audio Compression And Podcasts</h4>

<p>You need a minimum amount of audio compression in your
podcasts &ndash; whether it&rsquo;s a music podcast or a spoken / voice
podcast. Without it, your podcast will simply come out too
quiet most of the time, with sudden and bothersome loud
moments. But at the same time, you don&rsquo;t want to over-compress
your audio. This tends to create the appearance of yelling
all the time, because there are no dyanmics or variance in
your volume levels.</p>

<h4>Learning Through Practice</h4>

<p>There are no right and wrong settings for everyone, when
it comes to audio compression, though. Each persons voice
and speech patterns are unique, creating a need for variance
in how much compression is used. You&rsquo;ll want to practice some
with different levels of compression to find out what
works best for you.</p>

<h2>Where Do I Go From Here?</h2>

<p>The topics of what settings to change for what purpose in
both audio compression and file compression are worthy of
their own blog posts. Getting the high level idea of what
these things are and how the affect your podcast is an
important step in the right direction, though. Without this
basic understanding, having all the knowledge of what settings
to change won&rsquo;t mean much.</p>

<p>For tips and advice on audio compression settings,
check out <a href="https://gist.github.com/scottburton11/3222152">Scott Burton&rsquo;s post on audio compression</a>.
This is a great starting point with advice on what the different
settings for audio compression will do. This is a post that
deserves your attention &ndash; one that I wanted to write, but
would rather share Scott&rsquo;s quality work.</p>

<p>For info on file compression, bit rates and the effects that
they have on your .mp3 file exports, <strong>be sure to subscribe
the mailing list, below</strong> and the RSS Feed for this blog!
I&rsquo;ll be recording a sample podcast soon, and running it
through various bit rates for .mp3 file export. You won&rsquo;t
want to miss that post!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
