<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: intro | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/intro/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-17T14:16:10-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome! And Episode 1 Of Signals And Leaves]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> blog!
Consider this the obligatory &ldquo;hello world!&rdquo; blog post for the
new blog: Signals And Leaves. Read on for a little bit of info
on what SignalLeaf is, what it provides, and what I&rsquo;ll be doing
with the Signals And Leaves podcast and blog!</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>About SignalLeaf</h2>

<p><a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> is a small, but growing podcast audio hosting service.
Other podcast hosts want to up-sell you on features like
content management, advertising inserts, specialized podcasting
apps, and other bits that you won&rsquo;t need. SignalLeaf is different
in that I focus solely on four critical features that you need
for your podcast:</p>

<ol>
<li>.mp3 file hosting</li>
<li>RSS feed generation for podcast subscribers</li>
<li>Bandwidth for streaming episodes to your listeners</li>
<li>Traffic and analysis reports</li>
</ol>


<p>This pin-point focus on the services that SignalLeaf offers means
you are free to build a website that fits your needs, without
worrying about whether or not your podcast will fit in to it.
You can use any platform and any tools to build your site, and
embed podcast episodes from SignalLeaf, with ease!</p>

<p>Already have a blog or a site? Setting up a blog with
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-wordpress">WordPress</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-tumblr">Tumblr</a>?
Building a site on your own, using the
tools and skills that you already posess will not stop you from
adding a podcast. Just grab
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-the-signalleaf-media-player">the emded code</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-your-own-media-player">host the episode in your own media player</a>
on your site!</p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re ready to get started with the easiest way to host your
podcast audio and RSS feed, head over to <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a>
and sign up for you free trial!</p>

<h2>About The Blog</h2>

<p>Signals And Leaves is a blog about podcasting, building and running
a podcasting service, and everything that entails. You&rsquo;ll hear tips
and tricks for podcasting. You&rsquo;ll find podcast episodes that SignalLeaf
hosts and produces. You&rsquo;ll get pointers to the right equipment, and
see a lot of other bits about hosting, producing and making the most of
a podcast.</p>

<p>Subscribe to <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" title="">the blog RSS feed</a>
to keep up to date with the latest and greatest in podcast audio hosting,
tips and tricks, and other information to keep you on the forefront
of podcasting!</p>

<h2>About The Podcast</h2>

<p>In addition to this being a blog, I&rsquo;m also running a podcast by the
same name: Signals And Leaves. I&rsquo;ve only recorded one episode so far,
but will be recording and publishing additional episodes, soon.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52374abd66f52c0200000005/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Be sure to subscribe to the podcast through <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the RSS feed</a>
directly, or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">subscribe through iTunes</a>
to hear the latest on what&rsquo;s happening with SignalLeaf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
