<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T09:22:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 1 Thing You Need To Know About Your RSS Feed]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/03/21/the-1-thing-you-need-to-know-about-your-rss-feed/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-21T08:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/03/21/the-1-thing-you-need-to-know-about-your-rss-feed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of debate around whether or not you should &ldquo;rent
or own&rdquo; your podcast&rsquo;s RSS feed these days. Should you be
completely responsible for it? Should you own it &ndash; host it on
your website? Or should you rent your RSS
feed&rsquo;s delivery through a 3rd party service? While the debate
rages on with good arguments on either side of the fence, there&rsquo;s
ultimately only one thing that matters &ndash; just one thing you
need to ensure, that will make or break your RSS feed and your
podcast.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/rss-icon-itunes.jpg" class="center"></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The 1 Thing You Need To Know</h2>

<p>Let&rsquo;s face it, <strong>the one and only thing that you need to know
about your RSS feed is that it works</strong>. It needs to work
consistently and constantly. It needs to be available at all
times. When someone wants to check for your latest episode,
it can&rsquo;t be down. <strong>Your RSS feed needs to work. Always.</strong></p>

<p>There are a lot of factors that go in to keeping your RSS
feed up all the time, including whether you &ldquo;own&rdquo; or &ldquo;rent&rdquo;
your RSS feed and distribution. I&rsquo;m taking the terms from
real-estate here, where you either rent a
house/apartment/condo/whatever, or you buy
it and own it, paying a mortage (or flat out buy it if you&rsquo;re
wealthy enough). The analogy isn&rsquo;t perfect, but it illustrates
both the befits and drawbacks of both ideas.</p>

<h2>To Own Your RSS Feed?</h2>

<p>Owning your RSS feed means having it served from your website.
When someone wants to subscribe to your RSS feed, they go to
your website and get a URL that points to your domain name
for the feed. The feed is built and served by your website. This
is similar to owning a house. Once you own it, you&rsquo;re responsible
for it.</p>

<h3>Benefits Of Ownership</h3>

<p>There are two primary benfits of owning your RSS feed
distribution:</p>

<ol>
<li>Traffic goes to your site</li>
<li>A 3rd party service going down won&rsquo;t take your feed down</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>The primary benfit is being in complete control over your
feed.</strong> There is never a third party involved in getting your
feed distributed to other people. When you get a lot of traffic
on your blog and / or podcast, you are the one that gets the
traffic on your site.</p>

<p><strong>If a third party site that hosts your
RSS feed goes down for some reason, you may be out of luck
while you wait for it to come back up.</strong> Owning your RSS feed
means you are not waiting on a third party service to fix
their stuff.</p>

<p>There are some other small benefits as well, but these are the
major ones that you&rsquo;ll get. Unfortunately, though, there are also
downsides to ownership.</p>

<h3>Downsides Of Ownership</h3>

<p>While the major benefit of ownership is being in complete
control of your feed, there are downsides as well.</p>

<ol>
<li>You are responsible, not someone else, when it breaks</li>
<li>You may not get the best statistics for your RSS</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>The major downside is that you are
completely responsible for your feed!</strong> Again, it&rsquo;s like home ownership. The moment you go from renting
your home/apartment/whatever, to owning it, you are suddenly
responsible for it. Yes, you can hire someone else to maintain
it for you, but <strong>it&rsquo;s ultimately up to you make sure the
maintenance happens</strong>.</p>

<p>When was the last time you had a plumbing leak in your house?
Was it fun to call plumbers and get charged $150/hr or more?
<strong>When your website goes down, guess who gets to fix it&hellip; or at
least has to call someone to fix it.</strong> And guess how much they&rsquo;ll
charge you to fix it?</p>

<p>The last major downside is statistics. Unless you have a great
log analyzer service, you&rsquo;re not going to get very good statistics
from your own RSS feed. It takes a fair amount of work to
analyze logs from your website and create something meaningful
from it. Chances are, you&rsquo;ll be using a third party for the
analytics, anyways.</p>

<h2>To Rent Your RSS Feed Distribution?</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Renting&rdquo; your RSS feed is similar to renting an apartment or
house. It means you have *a third party involved and the RSS
feed that people subscribe to is not directly on your website**.
There is a service you&rsquo;re using to host your podcast audio,
and generate your RSS feed for you. All of the major podcast
hosts, including SignalLeaf, will do this for you.</p>

<h3>Benefits Of Renting</h3>

<p>There are two primary benefits to renting:</p>

<ol>
<li>You are not responsible for the feed going down</li>
<li>You can get better stats from a 3rd party service</li>
</ol>


<p>Owning your RSS feed delivery sounds great, until you realize
that you are solely responsible for keeping the feed up and
running. If you are distributing the RSS feed from a third party
service, though, then that party becomes responsible.</p>

<p>Services
like FeedBlitz specialize in keeping systems up and running. They
have a very large infrastructure dedicated to this. They will
make sure that your RSS feed is avaialble all the time. How
much money are you willing to spend on your own servers to
ensure they are always up?</p>

<p>Statistics and analytics for your RSS feed are also important.
You need to know how many subscribers you have on your RSS
feed and be able to compare that to your downloads for episodes.
Having your RSS feed hosted by the service that also hosts your
podcast audio means you&rsquo;ll be able to get better stats on your
subscribers.</p>

<h3>Downside Of Renting</h3>

<p>There are 3 major downsides to renting your RSS feed:</p>

<ol>
<li>Third party goes down, you go down</li>
<li>Someone else gets the RSS feed traffic</li>
<li>Changing your RSS feed is hard</li>
</ol>


<p>The primary problem of using a third party is the possibility
for them going down. If they go down, you are waiting for them
to come back up before your RSS works again. I honestly don&rsquo;t
think this is much of a problem. The podcast hosting and
RSS generating services out there are going to be solid. They
won&rsquo;t get much business if they aren&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>The second problem is that someone else gets the RSS feed
traffic. You are trading traffic to your site for the security
of having someone else host your RSS feed, basically. This is
ok by me, as the RSS traffic isn&rsquo;t that important. You need
people to see your website and your content, and for that
you want traffic on your site. But when it comes to RSS? It
doesn&rsquo;t matter as much. RSS is consumed by computers, not by
people.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re using a 3rd party podcast hosting service for your
RSS feed and you want to switch away from them, you may run
in to some problems. Several of the big name players in podcast
hosting make it very difficult for you to migrate somewhere
else and keep your RSS feed and subscribers. It&rsquo;s a difficult
problem to solve, and some of the services out there make it
more difficult on purpose. They don&rsquo;t want you to leave because
they lose money. That&rsquo;s a horrible thing to do to customers,
even if the problem of migrating to another host is difficult.</p>

<h2>The Best Of Both?</h2>

<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of debate about owning vs renting, and for
good reason. There are positives and negatives of both. Personally,
I prefer a middle ground approach where I have a third party
service syndicating my RSS feed.</p>

<h3>Rent The Distribution!</h3>

<p>Two good examples of 3rd parties that let you &ldquo;rent&rdquo; RSS
distribution are Feedburner and FeedBlitz. Both of these services
will take your RSS feed from wherever you generate it, and
syndicate it to as many subscribers as you need.</p>

<p>By having a 3rd party syndication service, you get several
benefits:</p>

<ol>
<li>You&rsquo;re not responsible for the maintenance</li>
<li>You can change the source of your RSS feed any time</li>
<li>If your site goes down, the RSS stays up</li>
</ol>


<p>I&rsquo;m not willing to spend much money on server farms and large
operations to keep my websites up and running, honestly. I just
don&rsquo;t have the money to do this. I&rsquo;d rather pay to rent space
on someone else&rsquo;s service so that they can be responsible
for it. This can be detrimental to my RSS feed, though. So I
prefer to have a 3rd party distribution service, like FeedBlitz,
handle the distribution of my RSS feed.</p>

<p>With a service like FeedBlitz or FeedBurner, migrating to a new
blog platform or website service is also easy. I can change the
source of my RSS any time I want. I don&rsquo;t have to worry about
losing subscribers, because FeedBlitz is going to have the
same URL for my RSS all the time. I just point FeedBlitz at
my new RSS source, and all of my subscribers are instantly
seeing the feed from the new location. The subscribers don&rsquo;t
have to do anything.</p>

<p>Lastly, if my site goes down, the RSS feed for my subscribers
won&rsquo;t go down with it. I can have my blog down for hours or
days on end (which I don&rsquo;t want to do, of course) and my
subscribers will still be able to get to the RSS feed because
the 3rd party syndication service is handling it.</p>

<h2>Remember The 1 Thing You Need To Know</h2>

<p>In the end, there is one thing that you need to know about
your RSS. You need to know that it works. Beyond that, there
is still plenty of room for debate about
whether or not you should own your RSS feed and it&rsquo;s syndication.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re going to own the RSS feed, I personally think it&rsquo;s a
good idea to use a 3rd party syndication service. Even if
you&rsquo;re using a 3rd party syndication, though, I think it&rsquo;s a
good idea to have your podcast RSS served by the podcast host
so that you can get the best possible stats off the RSS feed.
If (when) you need to change podcast hosting services, the
3rd party will be there to ensure you don&rsquo;t lose subscribers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[50 Reasons Why You Need To Blog Every Podcast Episode]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/26/50-reasons-why-you-need-to-blog-every-podcast-episode/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-26T13:44:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/26/50-reasons-why-you-need-to-blog-every-podcast-episode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blogging is soooo last decade, right? It&rsquo;s the old, new media
revolution. Everyone built a blog and wrote about what they had
for breakfast. And didn&rsquo;t blogging get replaced by social media
sites dedicated to your favorite food pics?</p>

<p>Truth is, blogging is more important than ever. If you&rsquo;re
trying to build an audience of any kind, you need a blog. Of
course you might not want to fill your blog will your instamatic
style, vintage food photos &ndash; unless your blog is focused on
that. Your blog should be focused and reflect the content that
the audience want, wants to read. And yes, your audience of
podcast listeners also need you to have a blog.</p>

<p>If aren&rsquo;t already doing this, you need to start blogging
every episode of your podcast. And I&rsquo;ve got 50 reasons why
you need to start, today.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/signals-and-leaves-blog.png" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Reason #1: Summary, Show Notes And Transcript</h2>

<p>The most important thing to do with each podcast episode is
blog an episode player, show summary and show notes at a minimum.</p>

<p>The summary is usually just a paragraph or two that explains what the episode is about.
You&rsquo;ll want to include an introduction for your guest, the
range of topics covered, and any interesting bits of information
that the episode contains. You can get in to as much detail
as you want, but remember that this is supposed to be a summary.
People will read this to get an idea of whether or not they
want to listen to the episode.</p>

<p>Beyond a summary, show notes are a great idea. This will be
more detailed items from the discussions and points in the
show. The major difference here, is that the notes don&rsquo;t need
to be standard prose. They can be bullet points, links, or
anything else that makes sense. Think of this as taking notes
in a meeting or class &ndash; you don&rsquo;t write down everything, only
the important points that will remind you what to look at
later.</p>

<p>Lastly, a transcript of the episode can go a long way if you
have the time do it or the money to outsource having this
done. Having a transcript with your show notes and links will
provide an alternative way for your audience to get the
information they need. It also lets people copy &amp; paste
quotable things, instead of having to transcribe for
themselves.</p>

<h2>Reason #2: Search Engine Optimization (SEO)</h2>

<p>The more information you pack in to your summary, show notes
and transcript, the better you will rank in search engine
traffic. Google and other search engines need content to
index. Content for podcast episodes comes from the show
notes, links and transcripts.</p>

<p>If you have at least a section for a summary and notes /
links, then search engines will have something more valuable
by which you can be found. You&rsquo;ll start ranking higher in
search results, concerning the subject matter of your podcast.
Higher search engine traffic means building a larger audience.
Building a larger audience means getting better sponsors
(if that&rsquo;s your thing) and having more influence and credibility.</p>

<h2>Reason #50%: Half Of Your Audience Will Listen via The Blog Post</h2>

<p>Ok, I lied. This is actually the #1 reason that you should
blog every episode. While #1 and #2 listed above are great
reasons, they ultimately lead to this one very important
statistic:</p>

<p><strong>50% of your audience will listen via your blog</strong></p>

<p>I first heard about this via <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat Flynn&rsquo;s blog post on
redesigning his website</a>.
In that post, he talks about how the first version of
the site redesign dropped his podcast listening traffic
by 50%!</p>

<p><sub>(Image from <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat&rsquo;s blog post</a>)</sub>
<img src="http://cdn.smartpassiveincome.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/redesigndrop2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Following up on that thought, I dug in to the podcasts that
I&rsquo;m hosting on <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> and
confirmed this statistic in a majority of cases.</p>

<p>My own Signals And Leaves podcast, for example, shows a 51%
bias for listening to episodes via my blog posts.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/signals-and-leaves-51percent-embed.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>After seeing that confirmed on my podcast, I dug in to a few
others and saw the trend.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-52percent-embed.png" alt="" />
<img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-56percent-embed.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Of course, not every podcast shows this trend. One in particular
doesn&rsquo;t use the embedded player that I provide. Instead,
they post to Facebook and want people to listen via RSS. They&rsquo;ve
experimented with an embedded player a few times, but
haven&rsquo;t used it much.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-65percent-rss.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>But with a majority of the podcasts that I analyzed having
50% + of their plays coming through their website, it&rsquo;s
rather plain to see that a blog post per episode is absolutely
critical for your audience.</p>

<h2>How Do I Get Embed vs RSS Reports?</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in getting the same level of reporting
that I&rsquo;ve shown here &ndash; the ability to know what percentage
of podcasts are coming from your blog posts, direct downloads
or through your RSS feed &ndash; you&rsquo;re in luck! <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a>
provides these reports for you, when you take advantage of
the SignalLeaf generated RSS feed and the SignalLeaf Player
for your blog posts.</p>

<p><strong> <a href="https://www.signalleaf.com/#plans">Sign up for SignalLeaf today</a>, and start seeing where your episode plays
are happening.</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Reports Do You Need For Your Podcast?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/14/what-reports-do-you-need-for-your-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T08:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/14/what-reports-do-you-need-for-your-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_podcast_report.png" width="300"></p>

<p>For some, podcasting is a creative outlet. It provides a way for
them to build an audience and create relationships and connections
with other like minded people. For the creative types that do
this for fun, having reports to show them how many listeners
they are getting is nice. They get to see how many people they
are potentially influencing, and it may help to drive them to
do more or do better.</p>

<p>For others, though, podcasting is more than just a hobby or an
outlet. It&rsquo;s a way of creating income, of sustaining themselves
or their family. For these podcaster, reports are critical.
They need to see how many downloads an individual episode has.
They need to see trends on what episodes are most effective.
They need to report these numbers to sponsors and potential
sponsors, so they can continue to bring in the income they
need.</p>

<p>With two very distinct audiences to serve, a report system for
a podcast can become overwhelming or underwhelming quickly. A
podcaster looking for simple reports may not care about having
everything. A podcaster that needs everything may get frustrated
at not having enough. Targeting different levels of reprots at
these two different audiences becomes important. But just having
this split doesn&rsquo;t answer the one fundamental question:</p>

<blockquote><p>What reports do you need?</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<h2>SignalLeaf&rsquo;s Current Reports</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m currently offering two different plans in SignalLeaf, to
differentiate between the two different types of reports that
people will need. This boils down to basic reports and advanced
reports, with the goal of serving the two identified audience
groups from above.</p>

<h3>The Basic Reports</h3>

<p>The cheapest plan offers a few very basic reports. At the
podcast, it will give you a total count of plays broken down
by type (rss, downloaded and SignalLeaf player). It will also
show you the total RSS subscriber count.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/basic_podcast_report.png"></p>

<p>At the episode level, this plan offers episode totals, broken
down by the same categories of RSS, downloads and use of the
SignalLeaf player.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/basic_episode_report.png"></p>

<h3>The Advanced Reports</h3>

<p>At the mid level and advanced plans, you&rsquo;ll get a bit more
information and breakdown in both the podcast and episode
reports. You&rsquo;ll get the same basic information, of course, but
the advanced reports add a little more.</p>

<p>The podcast level report offers a 30 day subscriber history,
so you can see the most recent trend of your subscriber count.
You will hopefully be seeing growth over time, but you will
likely see the numbers bouncing up and down on any individual
day. Not everyone has their podcast player open every day,
which means they are not always checking for new episodes.</p>

<p>Additionally, the advanced report will show you current trends
for episodes at a weekly and monthly level. You&rsquo;ll be able to
see which episodes are getting the most plays for these two
time periods.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_podcast_report.png"></p>

<p>At the episode level, you&rsquo;ll get teh same episode totals, but
you&rsquo;ll also see weekly and monthly counts for the episode.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_episode_report.png"></p>

<h2>Totals: A Breakdown By Listen Type</h2>

<p>One of the advantages that SignalLeaf&rsquo;s reports have over others,
is the breakdown of listens by type: RSS, Download and use of
the SignalLeaf player.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/listen_breakdown.png"></p>

<p>This gives you a more accurate picture of how people are finding
and listening to your podcast and episodes. Getting this breakdown
does require you to take advantage of all of SignalLeaf&rsquo;s
features, though. If you&rsquo;re hosting your own RSS feed and
providing your own media player for blog posts through
PowerPress, for example, you won&rsquo;t be able to get this kind
of breakdown. SignalLeaf&rsquo;s RSS, player and direct download
links all contain a tag that tells me what type of listen
is being used. This allows me to capture all of the information
I need for this report, but it means you have to use the
RSS and media player provided by SignalLeaf to take advantage
of it.</p>

<h3>Why Would You Want To?</h3>

<p>A while back, Pat Flynn from
<a href="http://smartpassiveincome.com">Smart Passive Income</a> went through
<a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">a major redesign of the site</a>.
In the process of doing this, <strong>the first version of his
redesign caused a more than 50% drop in his listens!</strong></p>

<p><sub>(Image from <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat&rsquo;s blog post</a>)</sub>
<img src="http://cdn.smartpassiveincome.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/redesigndrop2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Clearly, this is not what he wanted. And clearly, it would have
been nice to prevent this. But Pat did the right thing, and
fixed the site design so that podcast episodes were easier to
find and play. He quickly reacted, fixed the problem and got
his plays back up to where they should be.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the important lesson, though: <strong>if Pat had been using
a report setup like SignalLeaf provides, he would have known
that his audience was largely finding and listening to episodes
through his website, before going through this redesign!</strong>
Having this information could have helped him make better
decisions up front, instead of having to see this massive
drop in plays, after the first release of the website.</p>

<p>Now
that&rsquo;s not to say it would have prevent the drop. You make
decisions based on the information you have, and you adjust
from there. But having this information up front may have
helped. Knowing where the majority of your audience listens
to your episodes will help you to optimize that experience.
Knowing, not guessing or assuming, is important.</p>

<h2>Building Reports Based On Needs</h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the thing: <strong>I understand that these reports are not nearly
as &ldquo;complete&rdquo; as some other services out there.</strong> This is somewhat
intentional. Honestly, I have a lot more data availabe than what
I&rsquo;m currently showing. But <strong>throwing more data at you, just for the
sake of having more reports is not the answer.</strong></p>

<p>The reports that I have in place, and the breakdown of listens
are here because I saw the need for this based on customer
feedback. This is the key and critical part of the reports
that I&rsquo;m building &ndash; <strong>they are based on your neeeds, not just
tossing more information out there in the hopes that I get
soemthing right</strong> and provide some value.</p>

<p><strong>I want to know what reports you need.</strong> I want to know what
information you need to see, and why. I want to know that the
reports you are getting are serving you the way you need
them to serve you. And I want to build new and better reports
based on your needs that are not yet being met.</p>

<p>So drop a comment here. Send me <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">an email</a>.
Get in touch over <a href="http://twitter.com/signalleaf">twitter</a> or
<a href="https://plus.google.com/+DerickBailey/posts/HoCLiT4TJqH">Google+</a> and let me know:</p>

<blockquote><p>What reports do you want and need for your podcast?</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Of The Worst Things To Do When Starting A Podcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/06/4-of-the-worst-things-to-do-when-starting-a-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-06T20:32:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/06/4-of-the-worst-things-to-do-when-starting-a-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The web is full of great information on what you should be doing
when starting a podcast. There are hundreds, if not thousands,
of blog posts and web sites dedicated to helping you get up
and running &ndash; this one included. It doesn&rsquo;t take much more than
a google search or asking on twitter to find what you need to
know!</p>

<p>But this isn&rsquo;t another one of those feel-good, tell me what
I need posts. Rather, I want to mention a few of the things
that you should avoid doing when you&rsquo;re starting out. Understanding
what you should <em>not</em> do is just as important as understanding
what you <em>should</em> be doing &ndash; sometimes more important. These are
the things that will drive you to drink, if you&rsquo;re not careful.
These are the things that you should avoid doing, at all costs.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/stop_drinking.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>#4: Stop Waiting To Start</h2>

<p><strong>This is the first great mistake that people make when starting
a podcast.</strong> They wait. They wait some more. They push things
back, and they delay yet again.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easy to get sucked in to
the idea that you&rsquo;re not ready. It&rsquo;s easy to fall victim to
procrastination, and to make yourself look busy without making
any actual progress.</p>

<p>Unforunately, it&rsquo;s in our nature to procrastinate. Even the
most amazing podcasters, like <a href="http://eofire.com">John Lee Dumas</a>,
have fallen victim to the delays. In <a href="http://launchingcreative.com/episode-1/">his interview with the Launching Creative podcast</a>
[starting at 31:25], John talked about how he was delaying and delaying until his
mentor finally said that he would be dropped as a client if he
didn&rsquo;t release the first episode that day. In the end, John
realized that the delays he put on himself were only setting
him back, not helping him.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Get out there. Launch. Fail. Make mistakes. Improve.&rdquo; &ndash; John Lee Dumas</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>There is nothing that will demotivate
you faster than not getting your podcast published and live
for the world to hear.</strong> The sense of accomplishment and having
produced something is a tremendously motivating thing. You&rsquo;ll
find that once you start the work &ndash; once you start recording
and publishing episodes &ndash; you&rsquo;ll want to do more.</p>

<p>Getting started and getting your first episode published is
by far the most important thing you can do for your podcasting
career or hobby.</p>

<h2>#3: Don&rsquo;t Obsess Over Your Stats (Listeners And Subscribers)</h2>

<p>Unless you&rsquo;re already internet famous, you&rsquo;re not going to launch
to a massive audience. You won&rsquo;t have thousands of downloads,
instantly. Chances are, you&rsquo;re not even going to have hundreds
of downloads until you&rsquo;re at least a few episodes in to the
podcast.</p>

<p><strong>Stop. Watching. Your. Reports.</strong></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the deal, and the reason this is so important: podcasts
are an inconsistent stream of traffic per episode. You might see a
number that you like after the first week of your first episode.
You might even see a bump after the second week. But once you
release that second or third episode, the numbers won&rsquo;t be as high.
And the next episode? Even lower. <strong>THIS IS NORMAL!</strong></p>

<p>The average shelf life of a podcast episode is 6 weeks. <strong>6
weeks.</strong> This means your first episode will continue to accrue
traffic for around 6 weeks. You&rsquo;ll stil get traffic hitting it
after that, but it won&rsquo;t be as steady. During that 6 weeks of
life for your first episode, your other episodes won&rsquo;t have
as much traffic. You&rsquo;ll see a natural dip in the numbers
because those episodes haven&rsquo;t been around as long and won&rsquo;t
instantly catch up or shoot past your first one.</p>

<p><strong>It takes time for the numbers to settle in and level out.
Only after the shelf life of your first episode will you be able
to see that your audience is growing.</strong> And it&rsquo;s the slow, steady
growth of a continuing podcast, week after week, that you want to see.</p>

<h2>#2: Don&rsquo;t Wait For Listeners To Find You</h2>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;If you build it, they will come&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>the Field Of Dreams Fallacy
has cursed a generation of movie lovers in to thinking that
they will have instant fans and stardom.</strong> The idea is that
if you just build it and ship it, people will find it and love
you. <strong>This couldn&rsquo;t be further from the truth.</strong> But you
know what? That&rsquo;s ok.</p>

<p><strong>You&rsquo;re not doing this for instant
celebrity status</strong>, and the drug-rush of watching your stats
fly off the meter. And believe me &ndash; this is a habbit forming
drug. I suffer from this as much as anyone else I know. It&rsquo;s
the curse of the always-on, data-filled digital lives that
we live. We want to see every time someone hits our site, listens
to our podcast, or tells us something on twitter, facebook,
and every other site in the world.</p>

<p><strong>Get 10 episodes published, first</strong> &ndash; not just &ldquo;done&rdquo;, but
actually published. Talk about the episodes on twitter, facebook,
pinterest and everywhere else. Blog about the episodes &ndash; <strong>every
episode gets a blog post</strong>, in fact. Find places with people
that would benefit from your podcast and tell those
people about it. Do this for 10 episodes and then
start looking at your stats. You&rsquo;ll see growth, instead of flat
or falling numbers.</p>

<p>Once you see growth, you know you&rsquo;ve started to show up on
people&rsquo;s radar. <strong>Listeners will start to find you. But that
doesn&rsquo;t mean your done.</strong> The reason people are starting to find
you now is because you did the leg work of putting yourself
in front of them. <strong>Don&rsquo;t stop doing the leg work. Keep it up.
Your audience will grow.</strong></p>

<h2>#1: Don&rsquo;t Stop!</h2>

<p>This, above all other things, is the biggest mistake that new
podcasters make.</p>

<p><strong>The average podcast only makes it to episode 6 or 7 before it
stops.</strong> There are a lot of reasons for this, but in my
experience and in talking with others, it usually comes down to
time committment and what looks like a lack of growth in
audience. It just doesn&rsquo;t seem to be worth the effort, and
your day job is getting stressful again while the spouse and/or
kids are starting to wonder where you&rsquo;re at in the evenings&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>It&rsquo;s easy to get overhwelmed.</strong> And it&rsquo;s easy to think that
you need to have a regular and set schedule in order to be
a podcaster. After all, most of the podcasting industry tells
you this. <strong>Don&rsquo;t believe it for a minute.</strong> This is your
podcast; this is your story; your life; your work. You and only
you are in charge of how often you release an episode.</p>

<p>Just because you missed a week (or 7), or you only have time to
release one episode every month, doesn&rsquo;t mean you should
give up. Schedule the time for your podcast, like you would
do with anything else in your life. Set time aside, but
only time that you are comfortable with. <strong>Don&rsquo;t push yourself
to do more just because some podcasting &ldquo;professional&rdquo;
says you have to.</strong> You don&rsquo;t need to stop podcasting just
because you can&rsquo;t get this episode done and released &ldquo;on time&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Most Importantly: Have Fun!</h2>

<p>Podcasting is the new media revolution for this decade. Much
like blogging was in the previous decade, there will be alot of
growth and change in the industry. Join the growing community
and let your voice be heard. Build intimate connections with
your audience and allow them to know you, on your terms. This is
an exciting new media opportunity on many fronts, and <strong>it should
be something you enjoy!</strong> It may be hard work &ndash; well, it <em>will</em>
be hard work at times &ndash; but <strong>nothing worth doing is easy</strong>.</p>

<h2>Want To Know More?</h2>

<p>Like what you read here? Want more info to help you get past your
hurdles and podcast like a pro? <strong>Sign up for the mailing list,
below</strong> and you&rsquo;ll receive the latest news, tips and articles!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Remove Background Noise With Audacity]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/31/how-to-remove-background-noise-with-audacity/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T09:50:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/31/how-to-remove-background-noise-with-audacity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Noise from ventilation systems, cars driving down the street,
keeping yourself warm with a heater or even the hum of
flourescent lighting &ndash; these are all sources of background
noise that can make or break your audio quality.</p>

<p>Having a
constant hum or buzz in the background can be very distracting
and cause people to turn away from your podcast. Fortunately,
the <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a> audio
editing app can help you get rid of the noise in a few&hellip;
not quite so straight forward steps. Not to worry, though &ndash;
while the 2 step process may be a little bit odd when you
first see it, it is not difficult to understand or accomplish.</p>

<p><a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net"><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/Audacity-logo.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Video</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve put together a short video to demonstrate how to use
Audacity to clean up your audio. It&rsquo;s 7 minutes of step by
step instructions, including a demonstration of the original
audio and the cleaned up audio. Check it out on
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sT-Yk9zHKf4">my Youtube channel</a>,
or watch it here, embedded in this blog post.</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/sT-Yk9zHKf4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h2>The Audio</h2>

<p>In addition to the video on how to use Audacity to clean up
your audio, I&rsquo;ve also got two podcast episodes to demonstrate
the difference.</p>

<h4>The Original</h4>

<p>In this original source file, you will hear a constant hum
in the background, from a ventilation intake right outside of
my office. You may have to turn up the volume a bit to hear
it, but it is unmistakably there.</p>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves-Special-Editions/52ebcc6c4d17c40200000010/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h4>The Cleaned Up</h4>

<p>Now in this second version of the same audio file, I&rsquo;ve used
Audacity to clean up the background noise. The effect is
dramatic &ndash; the noise is gone during the quiet periods of the
episode. But, it is not perfect. If you have high quality
headphones, you will be able to hear a little bit of
distortion or noise in the low-end frequencies while I am
speaking. You may not hear it if your headset is not of
high enough quality, or if there is too much noise where you
are listening, but it is there.</p>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves-Special-Editions/52ebccbd4d17c40200000012/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h4>Additional Cleanup?</h4>

<p>Note that it is possible to do additional cleanup of the
remaining low frequency noise during my speaking. I left this
as-is, though, to demonstrate some of the limitations of what
the noise removal tool are. I may, at some other point, show
how to do additional processing to clean this up a bit more,
but that will be another post for another time.</p>

<h2>Professional Audio Cleanup</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s fairly simple to add at least a modest amount of audio
clean to your process, as you&rsquo;ve seen here. However, there
are some limitations to what Audacity can do, and it does take
a lot of practice and experience to really get things perfect.
You may find yourself in a situation where you don&rsquo;t have time
to learn all the tricks, or you need some additional expertise
in cleaning up and doing post-production audio work. If that&rsquo;s
the case, you might want to look in to an audio production
service such as <a href="http://www.podcastfasttrack.com/">PodcastFastTrac</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.podcastfasttrack.com/"><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/podcastfasttrack.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>PodcastFastTrack is a service that can handle all of your
podcast production needs, including editing, splicing in music
and intros, audio clean up and more. <strong>The combination of
post-production work from PodcastFastTrack, plus hosting
services from <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a></strong> may be
just what you need to keep yourself production and focused on
your podcast, instead of having to worry about the technical
and production side of thigs.</p>

<h2>Want To Know More?</h2>

<p><strong>Be sure to subscribe to my mailing list</strong>, below, if you&rsquo;d like
to get more tips, hear interviews from other podcasters, and
keep up to date with the podcasting industry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 5 With Rob Conery: Don't Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/26/episode-5-with-rob-conery-dont-suck/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-26T12:28:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/26/episode-5-with-rob-conery-dont-suck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode of the Signals &amp; Leaves podcast, I have the
pleasure of interviewing <a href="https://twitter.com/robconery">Rob Conery</a>
&ndash; a well known software developer,
<a href="http://wekeroad.com">blogger</a>,
<a href="http://tekpub.com">screencaster</a> and
<a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com">podcaster</a>.</p>

<p>Rob has an amazing
ability to create compelling stories out of interviews and
additional information that he gathers while researching a
subject. He has a knack for finding what he calls &ldquo;the truth&rdquo;
in an interview &ndash; that deep down part of the story where
the person talking is lost in thought, expressing their
inner-most sense of themselves in whatever they are talking
about. And I was lucky enough to get Rob to share how he
approaches story tellign in podcast, how he digs further for
the truth of the story, and how he puts it all together to
create something wonderful.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Show</h2>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves/52e5567fd97de30200000004/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>The Interview</h2>

<p>Along the path of this interview, Rob turns the tables on
me and shows how he approaches this by interviewing me about
this podcast. He talks about what it&rsquo;s like to keep digging
and to really listen for that moment when the speaker&rsquo;s voice
changes &ndash; the nuance that says the speaker is finally down to
the point where they are speaking from the heart of the
matter.</p>

<p>There more to it the interview than just the art of story
telling, though. We cover teaching, editing, adding dramatic
pause and affecting the over-all story as well.</p>

<p>Lastly, and perhaps most importantly, you&rsquo;ll also find out
what Rob means when he tells you, &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t suck.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t suck
at podcasting. Don&rsquo;t suck at conversations. Just don&rsquo;t suck.
It sounds like a rude awakening, and it may be for some. But
the point he makes is tremendously valuable.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/robconery">@robconery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wekeroad.com">Rob&rsquo;s Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://tekpub.com">Tekpub.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/">Scott Hanselman</a></li>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com">HanselMinutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/">This American Life</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast Spotlights: Pop Culture, Video Games And Being A Prepared Idiot]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/16/podcast-spotlights-pop-culture/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-16T08:17:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/16/podcast-spotlights-pop-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s good to be heard, to have your voice out there and share
your knowledge and experience with the world. Even better is
having some traffic so that you can know that you are being
heard. Sharing your favorite podcasts with your friends and
fellow bloggers and readers helps you become an authority on
the things you love, but also helps to spread the love by
giving those that deserve an audience a chance to be heard by
more people.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I&rsquo;ve got a few new podcasts that I want to
share with you today. With these, you&rsquo;ll pick up on some
pop culture references, plenty of video games, and you may even
walk away being a little more prepared for life.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Prepared Idiot</h2>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/prepared-idiot.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Richard Barna is putting together a great show under the nanme
<a href="http://preparedidiot.com">The Prepared Idiot</a> &ndash; A how-to guide
for life, &ldquo;Asking the dumb questions so you don&rsquo;t have to!&rdquo;
He&rsquo;s got a few episodes recorded already, but only has one up
on the site and in <a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/The-Prepared-Idiot/rss">his RSS feed</a>,
but even the prologue episode is worth a listen to get you
in the mood for the great topics that he has lined up.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a huge fan of this approach to teaching and engaging people.
I use the tactic of asking the dumb questions, myself. If you
are wondering, I guarantee someone else is wondering the same
thing. Speaking up and asking the questions helps others more
than you think, and Richard&rsquo;s approach to his podcast is going
to be great because of this.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://preparedidiot.com">PreparedIdiot.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/The-Prepared-Idiot/rss">RSS Feed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-prepared-idiot/id796449625?mt=2">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/preparedidiot">Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/preparedidiot">Twitter</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>FragCast</h2>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/frag-castle.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>The guys at <a href="http://fragcastle.com/">FragCastle.com</a> have put
together a podcast to talk about their life and business as
independent game developers. Having won a game development
challenge sponsored by GitHub, these guys definitely know how
to get a game done and released.</p>

<p>In the first episode, they talk about their history, where they
came from, where they are goign and more. I was especially fond
of the story behind the game titled &ldquo;Rock Kickass&rdquo;, and the
stories about PAX and working on a game to demo at that
event.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re in to video games and indy games especially, you&rsquo;ll
want to check out the FragCast.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://fragcastle.com">FragCastle.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/FragCast/rss">RSS Feed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/fragcast/id796282162?mt=2">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FragCastle">Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/fragcastle">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCB8a1AS5k43x5aaxrdX4SJw">YouTube</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>World Conquest</h2>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/world-conquest.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>&ldquo;Two guys talk about movies, video games, comics, nonsense, etc.
Yes, it&rsquo;s really that good.&rdquo; :) The description says it all.</p>

<p>This is two guys putting together
a fun, pop-culture, video game filled podcast and it&rsquo;s a ton of
fun. The first episode provides a little bit of background on the hosts &ndash;
cousins that developed their own little language to talk to each
other. They go in to a lot of talk about video games &ndash; everything
from Contra to Metal Gear and Guitar Hero.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for an entertaining podcast that brings back
memories from childhood video games and movies, you&rsquo;ll want to
check this one out.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/WCpodcast">Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/world-conquest/id796625394?mt=2">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/World-Conquest/rss">RSS Feed</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>More To Come</h2>

<p>This is the first post of podcast spotlights, but many more will
come. If you want to stay up to date with all the latest news
and spotlights, sign up for the mailing list below!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 4 With Craig McKeachie]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/14/episode-4-with-craig-mckeachie/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-14T07:53:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/14/episode-4-with-craig-mckeachie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Signals And Leaves, Episode 4 with <a href="http://www.funnyant.com/">Craig McKeachie</a>.</strong></p>

<p>Craig is starting up a new podcast on front-end web development
and is going through all the usual steps of getting started,
getting episodes recorded and getting them published.</p>

<p>This episode was recorded live at <a href="http://codemash.org">CodeMash 2014</a>
in a room that was full of noise from ventilation and other
environmental things. I used <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a>
to clean up the noise, which worked surprisingly well. There is
some noise leftover during louder portions of the audio, though.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves/52d548eba8606a0200000004/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h3>Podcast Pro-tip</h3>

<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t forget your guests&#8217; name or credentials.</strong></p>

<p>This one is rather embarassing, I must say. Right as I was
starting the episode with Craig, I forgot his name. My brain
went completely blank. We laught it off at the beginning of
the episode, but it makes for a bad start to the episode.</p>

<h3>Equipment</h3>

<p>This episode was recorded entirely with a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003IJ3WIW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B003IJ3WIW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">Roland R05</a>.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B003IJ3WIW" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h3>Notes</h3>

<p>Podcasting is a great way to build an audience. It creates a
more intimate connection with listeners, vs written words.</p>

<p>Having multiple forms of media, such as book, blog, podcast,
etc, helps you build authority.</p>

<p>Podcasts introduce conversation instead of monologue. It&rsquo;s
easier to generate ideas, create something more valuable and
get more out of a conversation than a monologue, at times.</p>

<p>Choosing a name is hard &ndash; don&rsquo;t want to be too narrow, but
also want to identify and serve your audience, and deliver
value.</p>

<p>Getting feedback from trusted resources can give you confidence.
Even if you figure things out, find resources that teach you
and verify what you&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p>Podcast hosting eats up a lot of bandwidth. Be sure you have
a host that can handle the bandwidth. Find <a href="http://signalleaf.com">a podcast host</a>
when possible.</p>

<p>Average life of a podcast episode is 6 weeks. Bandwidth is
typically measured per month, but bandwidth for an episode can
be estimated from the 6 week download trend for past episodes.</p>

<p>Be careful of Feedburner and other free services. Feedburner
limits you to 512K feed size, and will drop episodes to keep
it small. FeedBlitz and other paid services won&rsquo;t introduce
this type of limit.</p>

<p>Your podcast needs RSS that is compatible with as many devices
and directories as possible. If your podcast hosting doesn&rsquo;t
ensure this, you will want to use a third party feed distribution
system like FeedBlitz.</p>

<p>Find a podcast / RSS host that provides the analytics you
need. <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> gives you a breakdown of
RSS vs embeded player vs downloads, for traffic reports.</p>

<p>Trade iTunes directory reviews with other podcasters. Find podcasts
that you&rsquo;re interested in. Listen to a few episodes, then contact
the author and ask them to review your podcast in exchange for
you reviewing them.</p>

<p>You need a blog for your podcast, whether it&rsquo;s part of your
primary website or a separate blog. Write a post for each
episode with a short list of notes from the episode, at least.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<p><a href="http://funnyant.com">Craig McKeachie / FunnyAnt</a></p>

<p><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com">Cliff Ravenscraft / Podcast Answerman</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.softwarebyrob.com/">Rob Wahling</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Pat Flynn / Smart Passive Income</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mixergy.com">Mixergy</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.entrepreneuronfire.com/">Entrepreneur On Fire</a></p>

<p><a href="http://jsjabber.com">JavaScript Jabber</a></p>

<p><a href="http://feedblitz.com">FeedBlitz</a></p>

<p><a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetUpAndCode.com</a></p>

<p><a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Other Podcasters' Resources]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-11T09:18:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/equipment">my own equipment list</a>, my <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast">how to get started</a>
and more info on this blog. It&rsquo;s the place where I&rsquo;m putting toghether info
from my experiences and experiments, to try and help people that are new
to podcasting get up and running quickly. But there&rsquo;s also a ton of other
resources out there, from other podcasters. I&rsquo;ve oftend looked at these
blog posts and page for equipment ideas, how-to info, and more. And I wanted
to share some of these so that you could also benefit from the knowledge
and experience that I&rsquo;ve been able to benefit from.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Scott Hanselman</h2>

<p><a href="http://hanselman.com">Scott Hanselman</a> is a well known software developer and technologist, and is
a host of several podcasts that I know and love, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">Hanselminutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com/">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratchetandthegeek.com/">Ratchet &amp; the Geek</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you&rsquo;re in to technology and/or software development, you should check out the
podcasts that Scott hosts. They&rsquo;re great.</p>

<p>He also has a great blog posts about the equipment, software, process and
services that he uses for his podcats, titled:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/HowToStartYourFirstPodcastEquipmentEditingPublishingAndMore.aspx">How to start your first podcast &ndash; equipment, editing, publishing and more</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The title says it all, really &ndash; if you want to know what Scott uses and how he
works, check out this post. It is full of equipment recommendations, quick tips
and ideas that will help you get things up and running pretty quickly.</p>

<h2>Cliff Ravenscraft</h2>

<p>Cliff Ravenscraft is known as the <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/">Podcast Answerman</a>
for a good reason. His podcast, podcast tutorials, courses and other information
have become one of the defacto-standards in the podcasting industry. If you&rsquo;re
not familiar with Cliffs work, you need to check it out. He has a great list of
equipment, videos, tips and other resources all over his site, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/equipment/">Equipment</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/resources/">Resources</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/atoz/">Podcasting, A to Z</a> (paid course)</li>
</ul>


<p>And be sure to check out <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/category/podcastanswerman/">Cliff&rsquo;s podcast</a>
which is a wealth of knowledge and information on all things podcasting.</p>

<h2>Pat Flynn</h2>

<p>Pat Flynn&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Smart Passive Income</a> podcast,
blog and other resources are a place that I like to go when I&rsquo;m looking for
information on running and growing a small business. His podcast episodes and
blog posts have provided a lot of inspriation for me and ideas for figuring out
what I&rsquo;m doing with SignalLeaf, and more.</p>

<p>In addition to his podcast on small business, Pat has a great <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/resources/">resources</a>
 page that lists not only info about podcasting, but about small business and
services that he uses and recommends for online business and blogging.</p>

<p>For his recommendations and tutorials on how to get started in podcasting,
checkout his page:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/how-to-start-a-podcast-podcasting-tutorial/">How to Start a Podcast  Pats Complete Step-By-Step Podcasting Tutorial</a></p></blockquote>

<p>This page covers podcasting with a series of videos and other links to podcasting
resources, including Pat&rsquo;s podcast equipment list in video #1.</p>

<h2>Ray Ortega</h2>

<p>Ray Ortega runs <a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/">The Podcasters&#8217; Studio</a>
as well as <a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">The Podcasters&#8217; Roundtable</a>.
If you&rsquo;re a podcaster, or want to become one, you should be looking at what
Ray is producing.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s Podcasters&#8217; Roundtable is a great format where he gets multiple podcasters
together on Google+ to discuss thoughts on specific podcasting topics, often
leading to debates and disagreements &ndash; though always professional and
courteous. If you&rsquo;d like to hear a wide range of opinions and debates on
podcasting topics, you should check out the Podcasters&#8217; Roundtable.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s other podcast, The Podcasters&#8217; Studio, focuses on all things podcasting.
He shares his experience and knowlege so, and offers tips on how to get your
podcast to the next level. This is one podcast you don&rsquo;t want to miss, when
you have yours up and running and you want to know what the pros are doing
to keep things running smoothly.</p>

<p>Check out Ray&rsquo;s recommended gear and his podcasts, here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://rayortega.com/gear/">Recommended Gear</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/thepodcastersstudio/">The Podcasters&#8217; Studio</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/podcastquicktips/">Podcast Quick Tips</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">Podcasters&#8217; Roundtable</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>What Resources Do You Pay Attention To?</h2>

<p>I know there are a ton of other great resources out there &ndash; including some that
I&rsquo;ve looked at but am not listing here. I&rsquo;d love to hear what your favorite
reosources are. <strong>Drop a comment below and link back to your site&rsquo;s equipment
list, your podcast tips, and your favorite resources from your favorite
podcasters!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Mike And Mike Can Teach You About Mics]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/31/learn-about-mics-from-mike-and-mike/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-31T10:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/31/learn-about-mics-from-mike-and-mike</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was watching <a href="http://espn.go.com/espnradio/show?showId=mikeandmike">Mike And Mike</a>
recently (with a guest host in this case, I think), and paying attention to
the microphones they were using. At
some point in watching them, I noticed how incredibly close they were
to their mics so I snapped a couple of photos from my phone. There&rsquo;s a
few interesting things you can learn from watching these guys talk, to
help you learn better mic position for yourself, among other things.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/mike-and-mike.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Eat The Mic</h2>

<p>The first thing you&rsquo;ll notice is that they are basically eating the
mic, the entire time. They keep the mic right next to their mouth the
entire time that they are talking, and even when they are not talking.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/mike-and-mike-2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This is an important point to make. Keeping your mouth close to the
mic gives you the best possible audio quality for your individual voice.
It will pick up the high end and low end better than if you were
further away, and it will also allow you to keep the room noise to
a minimum.</p>

<p>When you have the mic close to your mouth, you need to keep the input
level low, so you don&rsquo;t get distortion. Keeping the input level low
means the mic will pick up less noise from the room. Even if you&rsquo;re in
a room full of echo, you can reduce this by eating the mic.</p>

<h4>On Not Eating The Mic</h4>

<p>In a previous post / podcast episode, I talked about keeping the mic
around 4 inches away from my mouth. This is what I tend to do, as it&rsquo;s
what I learned in my audio engineering courses in college. I&rsquo;ve seen
more and more people getting the mic right up to their mouth, over the
years, though.</p>

<p>Bringing your mouth up to the mic like this can have some drawbacks, such
as excessive mouth noises. I tend to have a problem with this, personally,
 but not everyone does. Do some tests. Practice a bit. See if this type
of positioning works for you.</p>

<h2>Chew With Your Molars</h2>

<p>There&rsquo;s an important aspect of mic position, when keeping the mic close
to your face. These hosts are not putting mic directly in front of their mouth.
Rather, they are almost always putting
the mic off to the side of their mouth, with the mic diaphragm pointing in to
their mouth.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/mike-and-mike-3.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Doing this keep the pops from your P and T sounds down to a minimum. When
you say words with strong P and T sounds, there is a small burst of air
that comes out of your mouth. If that burst of air hits the diaphragm
directly, you will get a loud booming sound or pop in the audio. This is
incredibly distracting, at minimum, and worse if the audio distorts because
of it. Keeping the mic to the side of your mouth cuts this down incredibly.</p>

<h4>Where&rsquo;s The Pop Screen?</h4>

<p>Most recording studios use a pop screen to cut down the pops from P and T
sounds, but there isn&rsquo;t one on these mic sets. There is either a pop screen
built in to the mic, or they are using external audio equipment to squash
the pops when they do happen.</p>

<p>In this case, they are using a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000Z7LLQ0/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&camp=1789&creative=390957&creativeASIN=B000Z7LLQ0&linkCode=as2&tag=signalleaf-20">Electro Voice RE-20 Cardioid Microphone</a>
which does have a pop filter built in to it.</p>

<h2>Movement Doesn&rsquo;t Decrease Quality</h2>

<p>If you watch a video of the hosts, you&rsquo;ll notice that they do move around
a bit when they get excited or passionate about something. Yet when they do
this, the quality of audio &ndash; including the volume &ndash; does not diminish. This
is the result of a few things:</p>

<ul>
<li>Audio Compression</li>
<li>Not moving more than a few inches away</li>
</ul>


<p>Audio compression, <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/">as I&rsquo;ve talked about before</a>,
is an important aspect of
audio quality. Keeping the high volume and low volume portions of your
podcast relatively close in volume is going to improve the over-all perception
of quality in your audio. Listeners won&rsquo;t be turning the volume up to hear
things, and then blowing their ear drums out when it gets loud again.</p>

<p>But even the best audio compression can&rsquo;t correct you moving too far away
from the mic. You need to stay within a small distance of the mic, even when
you do get animated. Staying within a small range of your mic, no matter
your average distance, is important. It allows you to add a reasonable
amount of compression to your audio, and not destroy the quality of the audio.</p>

<h2>Shock Mounts</h2>

<p>During the portions of the broadcast where the camera is pulled away from the
hosts, you can often see the hosts banging their hands on the desk &ndash; but you
will never hear those bangs in the audio. A good shock mount, which you can
clearly see the micrphones mounted in, will cut the desk and arm noise from
your audio. You&rsquo;ll be able to bang on the desk or mic stand a bit, and
you won&rsquo;t have that noise transferring through the mic stand in to the mic
itself.</p>

<h2>Learn From The Pros</h2>

<p>Paying attenting to your favorite broadcasters can yield some great tips on
how to improve your own mic position and audio quality. The more you watch others,
the more you&rsquo;ll be able to pick out the techniques and tips from body
position and mic position and mount. It&rsquo;s more difficult to know what the
back-end electronics look like, of course, but there certainly are plenty of
places where you can find this info &ndash; it&rsquo;s usually just a few clicks
 away on your favorite search egine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Waiting For The Right Equipment. Start Podcasting Now!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/29/stop-waiting-for-the-right-equipment/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-29T06:48:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/29/stop-waiting-for-the-right-equipment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s not shortage of people and websites claiming that they
have &ldquo;the right equipment&rdquo; for you to get started with your
podcast. Even <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/equipment">this blog</a>
has an equipment list. And there seems to be a constant clammor
for more, all around the internet. I&rsquo;ll make it simple
for you, though: <strong>start with what you have, or pick something
quickly and move on</strong>.</p>

<p>Choosing the right
equipment or the right software is a waste of time right now.
You need to be more concerned with preparing and producing the
content of your podcast at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The &ldquo;Right Equipment&rdquo; Is The Wrong Idea</h2>

<p>When you were learning to ride a bicycle, did your parents buy
you a $10,000 racing bike and enter you in the Tour de France?
When you were teaching your child to walk, did you buy them a
$300 pair of running shoes and ask them to run the Boston
Marathon? Of course not! The idea of that is ridiculous! Why,
then, do we expect people to buy new equipment and &ldquo;do it
right&rdquo; when they are starting out with podcasting?</p>

<p>Wait&hellip; you don&rsquo;t believe that this is happening? A casual search
on twitter reveals a number of people frustrated or waiting
because they don&rsquo;t have the right equipment, or asking about what
equipment they should get before they start.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> I have been researching this for weeks now and everything I have read has said the complete opposite to not start cheap. Lol</p>&mdash; Michael Wright (@MrWrightNow78) <a href="https://twitter.com/MrWrightNow78/statuses/417126714884780032">December 29, 2013</a></blockquote>


<p>These tweets often look like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>I want to start a podcast, but I don&rsquo;t have the right equipment</p></blockquote>

<p>Or</p>

<blockquote><p>What equipment do I need to start a podcast?</p></blockquote>

<p>These are questions on which people often get stuck. They assume
that you need a setup that looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/recording-studio.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m going to let you in on a little secret&hellip; <strong>your podcast
&ldquo;studio&rdquo; is going to look more like this, when you start</strong>:</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/laptop.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Let me make this very clear: <strong>if you have a computer with a mic and an internet connection, you
already have the right equipment.</strong></p>

<h2>A Reward With No Effort</h2>

<p><a href="http://getupandcode.com">John Sonmez</a> summed up the problem quite nicely:</p>

<blockquote><p>Most people have it backwards.
They buy a treadmill thinking they will run because they spent $1k.
Or they buy new running shoes or a guitar.</p>

<p>The ones who actually succeed, run in old sneaker and tell themselves that when they have been running for 3 months they can buy real running shoes.
The ones who don&rsquo;t give up early are the ones who borrow a friend&rsquo;s piece of crap guitar and promise themselves that once they learn 10 songs they&rsquo;ll buy their own guitar.</p>

<p>When you already have the reward, you lack the motivation and you don&rsquo;t appreciate the instrument.
How do you appreciate $5,000 golf clubs if you never played with $50 golf clubs?</p></blockquote>

<p>The same is true of any reward, or any nice equipment for any purpose. Buying
the right equipment now is not a guarantee that you are going to produce a
great podcast. Wait until you have gone through the first experimental stages
and you know that you want to continue, having proven that you can produce
content.</p>

<p><strong>Once you have shown that you can produce content and get it delivered,
reward the effort with better equipment.</strong> But don&rsquo;t rely on the equipment to
make your job easy. It takes effort, no matter what equipment you are using.
The reason others make it look effortless, is not because of the equipment
they have. It is because they have struggled through
the learning curve and have mastered the tools and processes; they have earned
the equipment, the effortless production, and the audience.</p>

<p><strong>So get started now, with what you have.</strong> Earn the rewards of better equipment,
and build your audience and skillset through your efforts.</p>

<h2>A Computer, A Mic, And Internet Connection</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re reading this, you&rsquo;re using a computer.
Your computer may be called an iPhone or an iPad, it may be
an Android or a laptop of some sort. There are a lot of different
computers with a lot of different names. But they are all
computers and most of them can be used for recording your
podcast. <strong>The easiest computer to use for your first episode
is going to be a laptop, but nearly any computer and microphone
will work</strong>.</p>

<p>Speaking of microphones, that is something you need to
have in order to record your podcast. But,
nearly every computer comes with some sort of microphone built
in to it these days. If you have a headset with a mic, for gaming
or to use for Skyp and other chat services, that&rsquo;s even
better! You&rsquo;ll get better sound out of a headset than you will
out of a laptop mic. But <strong>I wouldn&rsquo;t let a laptop mic stop you
from starting your podcast</strong>. If it can record your voice, it can
be used to produce your podcast.</p>

<p>Lastly, <strong>you&rsquo;ll need access to the internet with a
fair upload speed</strong>. Smart phones, tablets, laptops and PCs of all sorts
have built-in internet connections that let us get online and
find everything we never wanted to know, and more! This same
internet connection is needed for uploading your podcast
episode to your podcast hosting service. But don&rsquo;t worry too
much about this. <strong>The connection is only really needed when you
are uploading your episode</strong>. You won&rsquo;t need a connection to
record a podcast, if you are only recording yourself or if
you have all of your guests in the same room as you.</p>

<h2>No More Excuses</h2>

<p>The truth is, <strong>a lot of people use the idea of not having &ldquo;the
right equipment&rdquo; as an excuse</strong> &ndash; even if they don&rsquo;t realize it.
It&rsquo;s easy to hide behind the
idea that you need to spend a lot of money on equipment. It&rsquo;s
easy to say that you&rsquo;ll get started once you save up enough to
get the right microphone. It&rsquo;s easy to put this off, because
it takes no effort. It takes no work. There is no committment
involved in not doing anything. Talk is cheap, and talking
about how you want to do this, but can&rsquo;t because you don&rsquo;t
the right equipment, is the cheapest of the cheap.</p>

<p><strong>The first podcast experience that you have is more about you
than anything else</strong>. It&rsquo;s about you getting comforable with the
idea of recording, of producing something, and putting your
thoughts out there for the world to hear. It&rsquo;s not about the
equipment that you do or don&rsquo;t have.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like <a href="http://jennybrewster.com/podcasting-equipment/">Jenny Brewster</a>
said:</p>

<blockquote><p>Record in the Cupboard if thats where youre happy</p></blockquote>

<p>Sure, if you happen to have
some equipment already, it might make your first episode sound
better. But it&rsquo;s not about the quality, when you&rsquo;re starting
out. <strong>Starting is all about getting up and running quickly.</strong></p>

<p>Yes, there is at a bare minimum amount of
equipment that you do need. The good news is that you
have everything you need, already.</p>

<h2>Published And Flawed Is Better Than Not Published</h2>

<p>This really is the point of what I&rsquo;m trying to say: it&rsquo;s far
better to have published a flawed podcast with less than perfect
audio quality, than to wait for the right equipment.</p>

<p><strong>Podcasting is like any other skill &ndash; it takes practices, not
money, to get good at it</strong>. Producing your first podcast may
feel awkward, but this is normal. Everyone goes through this
the first time they record something. But you&rsquo;ll find
that over time, your podcast quality will naturally improve.
You&rsquo;ll get better at speaking. You&rsquo;ll get better at positioning
the microphone. You&rsquo;ll be become more comfortable, and you&rsquo;ll
enjoy the process much more.</p>

<p><em>Don&rsquo;t wait for the right equipment. Use the equipment that you
have right now, and get started!</em></p>

<h3>Want To Know More About Getting Started?</h3>

<p>This blog post is the first chapter from my e-book,
<a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast">Prepare, Produce, Publish: Your first podcast, in 3 easy steps!</a>.
If you&rsquo;d like to know more about getting started, <strong>how to record your
first episode, where to publish the files and how to get your
podcast online quickly</strong>, get the e-book! <strong>It&rsquo;s FREE</strong> when you
sign up to receive all the latest podcasting news and tips! <strong>Just drop
your email address in to the form below and you&rsquo;ll receive the e-book
at no charge</strong>.</p>

<script async src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MP3 Bit Rates, File Size, And Audio Quality]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-18T07:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/">a previous blog post</a>
I talked about the need for both file and audio compression
on your podcasts. At the end of that post, I linked out to
<a href="https://gist.github.com/scottburton11/3222152">an article from Scott Burton on audio compression</a>,
but did not have any information on MP3 file compression at
the time.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/c-clamp-mp3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Well, I have all the MP3 file compression information, along with
bit rates and my own judgement on audio quality vs file size now.
And you might be surprised at the results! I know I was!</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Episode Content And Bit Rates</h2>

<p>I recorded a 32 minute podcast episode that contains 2 things:</p>

<ol>
<li>A musical introduction</li>
<li>A lengty spoken track</li>
</ol>


<p>The musical introduction takes not quite a minute, with the
spoken audio taking up the rest of the 32 minutes. The spoken
audio is not a complete episode, however. It is only a 1+
minute description of the episode&rsquo;s purpose, repeated over
and over and over again to get a podcast episode of
approximately average length. In other words, <strong>don&rsquo;t bother
listening past the first minute and a half</strong>. It just repeats
for a long time to make the point of file size vs content
length.</p>

<p>After recording the episode, I exported it under 10
separate bit rate settings, using <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Aadacity</a>.
With all of these bit rate exports, I create a special
podcast on SignalLeaf just for these episodes. You can
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/52b10a635b56000200000011/rss">subscribe to the podcast RSS feed</a>
and listen to each of the episodes in iTunes and other
podcast players, or you can use the embedded players here.</p>

<h2>Constant Bit Rate Versions</h2>

<p>These episodes were exported at a constant bit rate &ndash; a rate that stays the same
throughout the entire encoding, regardless of the amount of data that there is to
encode.</p>

<h4>16K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10ade4cacd40200000050/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 16K Constant bit rate with 20K sampling (max supported by 16K file bit rate). The effect is quite horrible. Everything sounds muffled, warbly, and like its in a tin can with ear muffs. The file is quite small, at 3.9Megs, though.</p>

<h4>32K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10cf04cacd40200000051/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 32K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. The effect is still pretty bad. Everything sounds warbly and slightly muffled, though not as bad as the 16K file. The highs are especially off, and a lot of the stereo effect in the opening music is gone. The file is still pretty small, at 7.7Megs.</p>

<h4>64K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10d824cacd40200000053/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 64K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. The quality drop in this file is negligible. There are some points in the opening music where some slight warbles can be heard on the high end sounds. Additional guitar sounds and other instruments tend to have a more pronounced warbled sound at this bit rate. The file size is still quite reasonable and may be considered &ldquo;small&rdquo; by some standards, at 15.5Megs.</p>

<h4>128K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10e6e5b56000200000017/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 128K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. The net effect of this bit rate is no noticeable degradation in audio quality, throughout the podcast episode. If additional instrumentation were present, there would be little to no loss of audio quality. The quality comes at a trade off in file size, though, with the file being 31Megs in size. This size is hardly acceptable for a podcast that is only 32 minutes in length.</p>

<h4>256K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b110185b56000200000018/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 256K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. At 62 megs, this file size is completely unacceptable for distributing a podcast of only 32 minutes in length. The sound quality, however, is near impeccable. There is little chance that anyone would be able to pick up any distortions in the quality of audio.</p>

<h2>Variable Bit Rate Versions</h2>

<p>Variable bit rate encoding allows the bit rate to change based on the amount of information
that needs to be encoded. If there is less audio signal to encode, the bit rate goes down.
If there is more, it goes up. This can reduce the file size while still maintaining quality,
in many cases.</p>

<h4>48K &ndash; 85K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b111a44cacd40200000059/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 48K-85K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is very little distortion in this file, even in the musical introduction. A direct comparison of the 64K Constant bit rate yields a slight increase in audio quality over that export. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 15.5Megs down to 13Megs. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is quite nice.</p>

<h4>80K &ndash; 120K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b115e44cacd4020000005a/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 80K-120K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is little to no perceivable distortion in this audio even in the musical introduction. A larger assortment of musical instruments comprising a full band or orchestra may exhibit some minor issues, but not enough to cause serious displeasure. A direct comparison of the 128K Constant bit rate yields approximately the same audio quality, though it is technically slightly less. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 31Megs down to 18.4Megs for a mostly spoken audio file. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is quite nice.</p>

<h4>145K &ndash; 185K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b117d94cacd4020000005c/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 145K-185K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is little to no perceivable distortion in this audio even in the musical introduction. A larger assortment of musical instruments comprising a full band or orchestra may exhibit some minor issues, but not enough to cause serious displeasure. A direct comparison of the 128K Constant bit rate yields a technically higher quality audio file, but with little perceivable difference (if any). The file size, in comparison, dropped from 31Megs down to 26Megs for a mostly spoken audio file. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is acceptable for music based podcasts, but may be slightly larger than desired for spoken podcasts.</p>

<h4>170K &ndash; 210K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b119354cacd4020000005e/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 170K-210K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is little to no perceivable distortion in this audio even in the musical introduction. A larger assortment of musical instruments comprising a full band or orchestra should not exhibit any noticeable distortion, except in extreme cases. A direct comparison of the 128K Constant bit rate yields a higher quality that is imperceptibly improved with a spoken podcast. A full orchestra or other large arrangement of instruments may show some perceived improvements. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 31Megs down to 30.4Megs for a mostly spoken audio file &ndash; a negligible difference, at best. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate may be acceptable for music based podcasts, but is too large for spoken podcasts.</p>

<h4>220K &ndash; 260K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b11a315b56000200000022/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 220K-260K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. Good luck finding any perceivable audio quality problems with this one. A direct comparison of the 256K Constant bit rate yields approximately the same audio quality, though it is technically slightly less. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 62Megs down to 39.2Megs for a mostly spoken audio file &ndash; a significant reduction. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is not acceptable for streaming. The file is simply too large for the amount of content contained within it.</p>

<h2>The (Somewhat Surprising) Results</h2>

<p>As you would expect, the low-end results of the 16K bit rate
are attrocious. If it wasn&rsquo;t for the ridiculously small
file size, this would never even be an option. In fact, I&rsquo;m
going to call it not an option anyways, in spite of the file
size. The audio quality is simply horrible. I wouldn&rsquo;t inflict
that on anyone.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always known that a variable bit rate .mp3 file was going
to be smaller, but I had never directly compared the file size
and audio quality with a constant/variable counterpart before.
The ability to keep roughly the same file size while increasing
the over-all quality was a nice effect when comparing 64K Constant
to 80-120K Variable, for example. The Variable is slightly
larger, but with the increase of quality and negligible file size
gain, this was a huge win for variable bit rates!</p>

<p>The other surprising result is how little difference there is,
if there is any perceivable difference, between 128K and
anything above it. At least with spoken podcasts I don&rsquo;t see
any need to ever use anything above 128K Constant rate, or
the near equivalent quality of 80K-120K Variable rate.</p>

<h2>Revised Recommendation: 96K or 128K Constant Bit Rate</h2>

<p>I had originally written this post to recommend 80K-120K
Variable Bit rate, based on the audio quality and file size.
But I need to revise that based on some conversation with
<a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/">Ray Ortega</a> and Rob Walch
(from <a href="http://libsyn.com">LibSyn</a>) over on <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/+DerickBailey/posts/AWQvwWf5c4n">my Google+ post</a>.</p>

<p>Rob points out several problems with audio players as recent
as IOS6, and links to several posts where problems and solutions
are discussed.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://forum.audacityteam.org/viewtopic.php?f=16&amp;t=4249">MP3 Export, CBR=Good VBR=Bad Length</a> (from the Audacity forums)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.schillmania.com/projects/soundmanager2/doc/technotes/">SoundManager 2: Technical Nodes</a></li>
</ul>


<p>In the SoundManager 2 note, specifically, Rob points out the
following for the SoundManager 2, HTML5 player.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;MP3 Format Caveats</p>

<p>Additionally, some very low and very high bitrate MP3s, and Variable Bitrate (VBR) MP3s may play either too quickly or too slowly (see &ldquo;the chipmunk problem&rdquo;); if you are encountering this issue, try re-encoding at a different bitrate (between 64 kbps and 192 kbps, for example.) Using Constant Bitrate (CBR) encoding may also alleviate this problem.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>Given that, I&rsquo;m going to revise my recommendation:</p>

<p><strong>Use 128K or 96K Constant Bit Rate</strong> unless you have a good
reason not to.</p>

<h4>On Variable Bit Rates</h4>

<p>Even after revising my recommendation, I&rsquo;m going to leave
this note here, as to what my original recommendation was. At
the very least, it will let you the reader see where I was
coming from originally vs now.</p>

<blockquote><p>If I were going to recommend one signal bit rate to encode
your podcast .mp3 files, it would be 80K-120K Variable bit
rate. The audio quality vs file size is superb, with little
to not distortion or wobbles in a mostly spoken podcast.</p>

<p>If you press me hard enough, I&rsquo;ll admit that I want the
145K-185K Variable rate for music based podcasts. The additional
layers of sound found in music can present some warbles
and distortion on the high end frequencies at lower rates.
Honestly it&rsquo;s probably not going to bother anyong at the
80K &ndash; 120K rate, but I prefer to be safe when it comes to
my music encoding.</p></blockquote>

<p>And even at this, there are podcasters out there who have
switched over to variable bit rates with no issues.
<a href="https://twitter.com/jongalloway">John Galloway</a>
for example, has been serving more than 9,000 listeners of
his podcast in variable bit rate for over a year.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> Thanks. I was using CBR until last year for that reason, but switched to VBR and didn&#39;t get one complaint. Roughly 9k listeners.</p>&mdash; Jon Galloway (@jongalloway) <a href="https://twitter.com/jongalloway/statuses/414159229755219968">December 20, 2013</a></blockquote>


<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> I think the turnover rate in MP3 players - esp with phones - is high enough that it&#39;s no longer an issue.</p>&mdash; Jon Galloway (@jongalloway) <a href="https://twitter.com/jongalloway/statuses/414159430633021440">December 20, 2013</a></blockquote>




<script async src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<h2>One Size Does Not Fit All</h2>

<p>Clearly there is some dispute over the constant bit rate
vs variable bit rate. I&rsquo;m inclined to lean toward what
Rob Walch from LibSyn is saying at this point. But I&rsquo;m also
a technologist that understands the curve of old technology
falling off the market and being replaced by newer standards.
In the end, you should compress your audio files according to
your podcast needs, weighing file size vs audio quality and
available bandwidth. Whether this means constant or variable
bit rates is up to you.</p>

<p>Happy podcasting, all you Signalers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare, Produce, Publish: Stop Waiting And Start Podcasting!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/17/announcing-the-prepare-produce-publish-ebook/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-17T13:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/17/announcing-the-prepare-produce-publish-ebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You want to start a podcast. You&rsquo;ve got something to say,
and you know that people want to hear it. So what are you
waiting for? <strong>Stop wasting your time, waiting for the right mic or the
right co-host!</strong></p>

<p>With nothing more than a laptop and an
internet connection, you can join the new media revolution and publish
your voice, your thoughts and your opinions to the world!</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast" target="_blank" class="center"><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/prepare-produce-publish-cover.png"></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Publish Your First Podcast, TODAY</h2>

<p>Today. I mean, today! With my e-book,
&ldquo;<a href="https://leanpub.com/prepare-produce-publish/packages/book/purchases/new">Prepare, Produce, Publish: Your First Podcast In 3 Easy Steps!</a>&rdquo;,
you will be up and running and have your first episode
published in no time at all!</p>

<p>This book is all about getting you started in the world of
podcasting &ndash; from the equipment that you need (<em>and don&rsquo;t need!</em>)
to using Audacity for recording your first episode, and how
to publish your podcast through a hosting service, this book
covers it all for for the new podcaster.</p>

<h2>GET IT FREE! WITH FREE UPDATES!</h2>

<p>This e-book, which would cost $10 if you decide to buy it,
can be yours for free by <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/mailing-list">signing up for the SignalLeaf mailing list</a>!</p>

<p>In addition to this informational and step-by-step guide
to publishing your first podcast, you&rsquo;ll get updates and
news from the podcasting world. From blog posts, to tips
and tricks, from podcasters and professionals to those that
are just starting out, you&rsquo;ll hear all the latest news
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/mailing-list">right here</a>.</p>

<h2>A Work In Progress</h2>

<p>This ebook is currently a work in progress. That means it is
not yet complete, but it still provides a ton of value as-is.
That also means that <strong>you, dear podcaster, get to purchase the
book at a discounted price!</strong> Better hurry, though&hellip; this
discount won&rsquo;t last forever! Once I&rsquo;ve got the book completed,
the price will jump!</p>

<p>In addition to getting it cheaper, you will also get all of
the updates, free! As soon as I publish an update to the book
you will have it available in your downloads, guaranteed. That
means you&rsquo;ll get all of the step by step instructions, tips
and tricks to publish your podcast as I write them!</p>

<h2>Get Your Podcast Published</h2>

<p>I know you&rsquo;ve been thinking about starting a podcast, so
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/mailing-list">join the SignalLeaf mailing list</a>
and get the guide to publishing
your podcast, FREE!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Audio vs File Compression, And Why You Need Both]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-10T20:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bandwidth for streaming podcasts is expensive, and using it
up with podcast audio that is too quiet, then too loud, then
too quiet again is a giant waste of money. <strong>Fear not!</strong> Just
toss in a little bit of compression and you can <strong>save money,
conserve bandwidth, and please the ears of your listeners</strong>
all at the same time.</p>

<p>But&hellip; audio compression, or file compression? Wait, what&rsquo;s
the difference? I&rsquo;m already exporting to .mp3 files, and
they&rsquo;re compressed, right? Yes, but that&rsquo;s file compression.
Audio compression is something entirely different, and is
just as important. Knowing when you have enough compression
of both kinds is also important, and knowing what they are
and how they affect your podcast is critical.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>File Compression</h2>

<p>Nearly everyone that knows how to use a computer is familiar
with file compression. You&rsquo;ve seen it and its effects more
times than you can count. Ever had a .zip file? Or a .jpg
file (hint: you&rsquo;re looking at some on this site)? These file
extensions are indications of file compression protocols.
Podcasts that use .mp3 files also use compression. Each of
these compression types offers something different, and
specialized, and there are still hundreds (thousands?) of
other file compression types around.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/mp3-export-settings.png"></p>

<p>Delivering audio in a .mp3 file allows files to be much
smaller than other uncompressed formats. But this comes at
a cost. The mp3 format uses a lossy compression algorithm:
a means of compression that reduces the audio quality in order
to reduce the amount of information being stored in the file.
Smaller files come from less information being stored.</p>

<h4>How Much File Compression?</h4>

<p>The effect of a .mp3 file saved at a very low bit rate
is terrible sounding audio in some cases, but not in others.
This is what makes compression somewhat tricky.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re
recording human voices for a podcast, for example, you can
get away with a much lower quality file (lower bit rate).
There isn&rsquo;t a lot of dynamic range of content, or overlapping
content in a human voice &ndash; even with multiple people
speaking at the same time.</p>

<p>When recording musical
instruments, however, low quality audio becomes apparent
very quickly. If you choose a low bit rate for music,
high pitch sounds become distorted in odd ways
and low pitch sounds become muffled and muted. Mid range
sounds can do ok, still, but get mixed up with each other when
multiple instruments are in the same frequency range.  Music
demands a higher bit rate, but not alway the highest.</p>

<h4>Avoid &ldquo;A Copy Of A Copy&rdquo; Syndrome</h4>

<p>One thing you also need to be aware of: if you&rsquo;re importing
existing audio files in to your screencast, be sure they are
high quality to start with.</p>

<p>Why, you might ask? Have you ever made a photocopy of a
photocopy of a photocopy? Compressing already compressed audio
has the same effect. Starting with high quality sound will
ensure the file version sounds as good as possible.</p>

<h2>Audio Compression</h2>

<p>Audio compression can also have a dramatic effect on the
quality of audio, but in a very different way.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/garage-band-compression-settings.png"></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve ever heard a song or a podcast or a radio station
where literally everything came out at exactly the same
volume level &ndash; not matter whether the person was wispering,
or the music was supposed to be subdued and quiet &ndash; you&rsquo;ve
heard the ill-effects of over-compressing audio.</p>

<p>On the opposite end of the spectrum, is classical music. If
you&rsquo;ve ever tried to listen to classical music in a car or
on public transport systems, you&rsquo;ve probably been frustrated
by the near impossible to hear quiet moments followed by
ear-splitting loud moments. This is the effect of no audio
compression at all.</p>

<h4>Controlling Signal Levels (Volume)</h4>

<p>Audio compression is a means of flattening the signal level
for the audio track(s) being compressed. It makes the quiet
parts louder so you can still hear them, and makes the loud
parts quieter so they don&rsquo;t blow your ear drums out.</p>

<p>Too much compression makes everything sound flat. It removes
all of the dynamics of the audio, preventing the natural
ebs and flows of volume differences. It tends to make things
sound over-produced. Radio stations tends to use a ton of
audio compression to compensate for road noise and other
ambient noises in the typical radio lisening environment:
transportation. Classical music, on the other hand, tends
to opt for purity and intent of the conductor and
orechestra, leaving off any audio compression of any kind.
Because of this, classical music is usally best experienced
in quiet places.</p>

<h4>Audio Compression And Podcasts</h4>

<p>You need a minimum amount of audio compression in your
podcasts &ndash; whether it&rsquo;s a music podcast or a spoken / voice
podcast. Without it, your podcast will simply come out too
quiet most of the time, with sudden and bothersome loud
moments. But at the same time, you don&rsquo;t want to over-compress
your audio. This tends to create the appearance of yelling
all the time, because there are no dyanmics or variance in
your volume levels.</p>

<h4>Learning Through Practice</h4>

<p>There are no right and wrong settings for everyone, when
it comes to audio compression, though. Each persons voice
and speech patterns are unique, creating a need for variance
in how much compression is used. You&rsquo;ll want to practice some
with different levels of compression to find out what
works best for you.</p>

<h2>Where Do I Go From Here?</h2>

<p>The topics of what settings to change for what purpose in
both audio compression and file compression are worthy of
their own blog posts. Getting the high level idea of what
these things are and how the affect your podcast is an
important step in the right direction, though. Without this
basic understanding, having all the knowledge of what settings
to change won&rsquo;t mean much.</p>

<p>For tips and advice on audio compression settings,
check out <a href="https://gist.github.com/scottburton11/3222152">Scott Burton&rsquo;s post on audio compression</a>.
This is a great starting point with advice on what the different
settings for audio compression will do. This is a post that
deserves your attention &ndash; one that I wanted to write, but
would rather share Scott&rsquo;s quality work.</p>

<p>For info on file compression, bit rates and the effects that
they have on your .mp3 file exports, check out
<a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates/">the post on MP3 bit rates, file size, and audio quality</a>.
In this post, I export the same podcast episode using 10
different bit rates (5 constant, and 5 variable) and look
at the results.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 3: Tips On Podcasting With Podcaster, John Sonmez]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, I have the pleasure of interview my friend
and fellow podcaster, John Sonmez from <a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a>.
We talk about his podcast at <a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetupAndCode.com</a>
&ndash; a podcast that combines fitness and programming &ndash; and dig in
to his lessons learned, success and failures in podcasting. It&rsquo;s
a great episode full of useful tips for those that are just
starting as well as those that have already started to get on
a roll with a podcast.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52a2b2fd9903dd0200000021/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Podcast Pro-Tip</h2>

<p>Use the &ldquo;clap trick&rdquo; to sync separate tracks recorded from
different computers. One person counts to 3, and on 3, everyone
in the podcast claps. Then you can sync the separate audio
tracks to the clap at the beginning.</p>

<p><strong>Listen to the first minute of the episode for a demonstration
of this technique!</strong></p>

<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>Niche-down to find your target audience &ndash; don&rsquo;t try to be
everything to everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Coordination with cohost requires planning and commitment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>have a backup episode in case you can&rsquo;t make it for some reason</li>
<li>decide on a release cadence that you can handle, and stick with it no matter what</li>
</ul>


<p>Don&rsquo;t wait for perfect. Get something done and released</p>

<p><strong>Nerves are expected when you start</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s new</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s different</li>
<li>that&rsquo;s ok</li>
<li>you will improve over time</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mistakes happen &ndash; move on</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s a conversation between you and the host / guest</li>
<li>keep the content focused and relevant</li>
<li>just relax and have fun</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You know something others don&rsquo;t</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>if it&rsquo;s just your experience and perspective</li>
<li>your perspective is valuable</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Being new gives you a very valuable perspective</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>share your fears and mistakes with others</li>
<li>build the audience of people that are also new</li>
<li>help others learn with you</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>John&rsquo;s 3 lessons for someone just starting:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Streamlining: get all the infrastructure prep work (logo, domain name, blog, etc) done before you start recording. Start out professionally, with intro music, logo, etc (checkout fiverr.com for stuff like this)</li>
<li>Understand the process before you start. Practice by recording yourself and working through the process before you produce a real podcast. iTunes will not host your episodes (see blog.signalleaf.com for info on this)</li>
<li>Set up process, with consistency, ahead of time. Don&rsquo;t be left hanging after you record your first episode. You need to be consistent in order to grow a returning audience.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Have Your Own Tips To Share?</h2>

<p>If you have a podcast, then yes, you have lessons learned and info to
share with a growing audience. I want to interview you on
the Signals And Leaves podcast!</p>

<p><strong>So, <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">get in touch</a>
and let me know you want to be on the show!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Free Hosting Isn't "Free"]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/04/why-free-hosting-isnt-always-free/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-04T21:31:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/04/why-free-hosting-isnt-always-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found <a href="http://webmasters.stackexchange.com/questions/52046/podcast-site-serve-audio-files-with-cdn/55791">a question on the StackExchange network</a>
regarding podcast hosting and the use of a CDN, with one answer
suggesting the use of SoundCloud for hosting.</p>

<blockquote><p>I am managing a small podcast website hosted on a shared server. Currently there are only eight or nine episodes, each of which are about 50 MB, so bandwidth is not really an issue at the moment.</p>

<p>However, looking forward, would it be feasible to use a &ldquo;free&rdquo; CDN like Cloudflare to serve the audio files? If so, how would I set this up?</p>

<p>I took a quick look at it before, and it seems you have to have your whole site routed (is that the right term?) through the CDN rather than just specific files or filetypes. I&rsquo;d like some clarification on this.</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s an interesting question and idea, but one that
comes with a lot of potential problems.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you&rsquo;re not familiar with the idea behind a CDN, don&rsquo;t
worry about that. It&rsquo;s not something that most people need to
know about. If you&rsquo;re interested, though, check out
<a href="http://www.kendoui.com/blogs/teamblog/posts/13-11-07/know-when-to-cdn.aspx">my article on using CDNs in web development</a> (external link).</p>

<h2>Reduce Your File Size</h2>

<p>Before I address the hosting concerns, you should really try
to reduce your file size for the podcasts. Unless your podcast
episodes are 2 to 4 hours long, each, you shouldn&rsquo;t be
reaching 50 megs per file. Try reducing the audio quality in
your mp3 files (and use .mp3 file compression if you&rsquo;re not
already &ndash; it&rsquo;s the podcast industry standard). If you have a
45 minute podcast, you should be able to get your .mp3 file
down to around 15 to 20 megs, tops, without any significant
reduction in sound quality for spoken voice podcasts. Music
podcasts may be different, and you probably want higher
quality, but those are the exception where voice based
podcasts tend to be the rule.</p>

<h2>Free Hosting Is Almost Never &ldquo;Free&rdquo;</h2>

<p>When it comes to bandwidth and hosting, you really want to
avoid free if possible.</p>

<p>On the bandwidth side, free tends to be awful. CDNs are not
meant to be used for very large files that are downloaded
frequently, like podcast files. CDNs are typically meant for
smaller files, like static HTML, JavaScript, CSS and images.
You&rsquo;ll quickly realize just how &ldquo;free&rdquo; a free CDN is when
your downloads get throttled down to slow speeds or your
account gets shut off because you&rsquo;re using too much bandwidth.</p>

<p>In addition to bandwidth and even file size limitations on
free accounts, you will likely end up with ads placed on your
content, when using free hosting services for things like
podcasts. Maybe you don&rsquo;t mind ads being placed on your
podcast, to get free hosting. But there are some real dangers
in this <a href="http://schoolofpodcasting.com/how-to-avoid-vibrator-commercials-on-your-podcast-say-no-to-free-media-hosting/">when your podcasts suddenly have ads for sex toys in them</a>!</p>

<p>(Note: that link is mostly safe for work. It&rsquo;s an article
about the dangers of free hosting, including a story that
is rather shocking, but has no unsafe images in it).</p>

<p>Finally, there is always a risk that your free account will
be taken out from under you, for no reason. Service providers
are not obligated to continue providing free service to
anyone, in the vast majority of cases. They may decide that
they can no longer afford it, and yank the rug out from
everyone that is hosted for free, or simply close up shop and
disappear. It happens more than people want to admit.</p>

<h2>SoundCloud Has Limits On Free</h2>

<p>One of the comments on the question suggested using SoundCloud
as a podcast host. This is a common thing to do, actually.
SoundCloud offers a unique spin on hosting audio and even
provides RSS and stats for podcasts. The reponder even note
that StackExchanged used SoundCloud (which may or may not
be accurate anymore&hellip; that should be verified).</p>

<p>StackExchange may use SoundCloud for it&rsquo;s podcast hosting,
but I guarantee they don&rsquo;t use a free account. Perhaps they
have some deal with SoundCloud where they don&rsquo;t get charged
anything, but this type of discount arrangement is very
different than the free account that SoundClod offers.</p>

<p><a href="http://help.soundcloud.com/customer/portal/articles/247820-what-s-the-difference-between-each-subscription-level-">From SoundCloud&rsquo;s website</a>,
you can see exactly what limitations you will run in to with
the free account:</p>

<blockquote><p>Free</p>

<ul>
<li><p>2 total upload hours</p></li>
<li><p>100 downloads/sound</p></li>
<li><p>Unlimited playlist creation</p></li>
<li><p>Some stats (see the amount of plays, downloads, comments and favorites of your tracks)</p></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<h2>Free Trial and &ldquo;Freemium&rdquo; Are Legit</h2>

<p>There are other types of &ldquo;Free&rdquo; accounts than &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll give you
something for nothing&rdquo;, though.</p>

<p>Many services offer free trials
that give you a set time limit for using the service. This
type of &ldquo;free&rdquo; is usually legit. It gives you a way to try
out a service without having to pay anything, knowing that
if you like the service you&rsquo;ll have to pay to continue with
it. There&rsquo;s nothing wrong with free trials, and I actually
encourage people to try as many free trials as they need to,
to figure out what service fits their needs the best.</p>

<p>Other services, like SoundCloud, offer a &ldquo;freemium&rdquo; service
type. This is a service that gives you free service, typically
supported by ads or other monetiziation means. The free
service will have strict limitations on what you can and
cannot do, but won&rsquo;t stop your service after a certain period
of time. The idea is that after you get in to the service,
you&rsquo;ll be hooked and you&rsquo;ll want to pay for the services to
get the better features.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s some debate about &ldquo;freemium&rdquo; services these days, with
a lot of companies saying it&rsquo;s not viable, and even some
companies going out of business because of it. Now imaging
how bad that would be if you were a paying customer of a
service and all the free accounts caused the service to go
out of business! I&rsquo;d be pretty upset about that.</p>

<h2>Your Best Option: Paid Podcast Hosting Service</h2>

<p>In the end, your best option is to pay for podcast hosting
services. There are a lot of great services available,
<strong>including my own at <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a></strong>,
LibSyn, Blubrry, and many more. These services start cheap &ndash;
very cheap &ndash; usually with a free trial before you actually
have to pay for anything. My <strong>SignalLeaf</strong> service has a
rather lengthy trial period compared to most. This gives you
plenty of time to figure out if you want to continue with the
service or not.</p>

<p>At only a few $ a month, paid podcast hosting services are
going to give you all the space you need for file storage and
bandwidth, provide an iTunes and other podcast app compatible
RSS feed, and give you all the stats and feedback that you
need for your podcast.</p>

<p>All of these paid services host their files on servers that
are going to stream your audio more reliably than any free
service you would find. By paying a company to host your
files, you are giving them incentive to make sure they are
keeping you happy and doing the best job possible to keep
your podcast rolling smoothly. SignalLeaf, for example,
uses Amazon S3 storage and streaming of all podcast files.
There&rsquo;s no way your listeners are going to use up the
bandwidth of S3. You&rsquo;ll never see a slow-down in delivery,
or have problems with file storage reliability.</p>

<p>Stats are also important if you&rsquo;re looking for motivation
to continue podcasting, or want sponsors. You&rsquo;re not going
to get the stats you need without paying for service, either.
Generating stats is not as simple as most people thing, which
is why it always takes a more expensive paid account to get
great stats.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Start Your Free Trial, Now!</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re serious about your podcasts, do yourself a favor
and get <a href="http://signalleaf.com">a podcast hosting service</a> to
handle the heavy lifting and distribution of your content.
You&rsquo;ll never be happier than if reduce your own burden so
that you can focus on the content, not the content delivery.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 2: Mic Positioning And Room Are More Important]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you think the quality of the microphone is going to make
or break your podcast? If you do, I&rsquo;d like to show you that
it won&rsquo;t. And if you already don&rsquo;t, then why are you still
obsessed with getting &ldquo;the right mic&rdquo;? Is it just another
excuse to not start that podcast?</p>

<p>In Episode 2 of the Signals And Leaves podcast, I&rsquo;ll show you
how the room your in, and the positioning of the mic, will
have far more impact on the quality of the recording that
you are getting.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/528d042ea88e1f020000000f/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>As you can hear in this episode, having a quality mic does
make a difference in the audio recording. But that is not
the most important thing when you&rsquo;re starting your podcast. You
would be better served to find the right room in which to
record, than to go out and spend money on a top quality mic.</p>

<p>Now that doesn&rsquo;t mean a quality mic doesn&rsquo;t make a difference.
You will hear the difference in this episode. But you&rsquo;ll also
hear the difference between an office, an ultra-echoy bathroom,
and a closet with near-perfect sound.</p>

<p>Having a good position for your microphone is also of importance,
and can make a huge difference even if you have a quality
mic to start with. At the end of the episode, I&rsquo;ll give you
several examples of good and bad mic positioning.</p>

<h4>Show Highlights</h4>

<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t worry about the quality of mic</li>
<li>Worry about the room you&rsquo;re recording in</li>
<li>Worry about the microphone positioning</li>
<li>Wait until you have a few episodes under your belt before buying a quality mic</li>
</ul>


<p>When you are ready to buy, I highly recommend
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000JM46FY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000JM46FY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Rode Podcaster</a>.
This is the mic I use, and I love it. This is the industry
standard for podcasting and screencasting. You can&rsquo;t go wrong
with the Rode Podcaster.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B000JM46FY" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>If you need high quality for a little less money, though,
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002VA464S/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B002VA464S&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Blue Yeti</a>
is also a great podcast microphone. I know a lot of people that
use this one, and it&rsquo;s a great mic.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B002VA464S" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Subscribe And Share This Episode!</h2>

<p>If you like this episode, be sure to subscribe to
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the Signals And Leaves RSS feed</a>,
or <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/signals-and-leaves/id739095095">subscribe in iTunes</a>.</p>

<p>And while you&rsquo;re at it, submit this episode to
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/submit">Hacker News</a>
and the <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/podcasts/">/r/podcasts sub-Reddit</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can't I Just Host My Podcast on iTunes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-18T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was talking with someone about a podcast
they are starting, recently, and I asked if they already had a
plan for hosting it. The response I got was surpising:</p>

<blockquote><p>we have not yet gotten to the question of hosting the podcast yet.
i was assuming we would do it though iTunes, but i haven&rsquo;t thought farther than that.</p></blockquote>

<p>This seems to be an common misunderstanding about iTunes,
unfortunately. Your subscribers find you through iTunes, right?
So, isn&rsquo;t that where you host your podcast?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Sorry, but no &ndash; podcasts distribution doesn&rsquo;t work like that.
Instead of uploading podcast episodes directly to iTunes, it&rsquo;s
only a network for finding and subscribing to podcast RSS feeds.
You still need your own host, bandwidth for streaming and RSS
for your podcast.</p>

<h2>iTunes And Google Maps</h2>

<p>Think of iTunes like Google Maps for podcasts. With Google
Maps, you can quickly and easily find
an address and a business, but Google Maps won&rsquo;t actually
take you there. You have to walk, drive, fly, or otherwise get
yourself to the real location that the map shows you.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/google-maps.png" width="400"></p>

<p>Podcasts in iTunes work the same way. iTunes will list your podcast
like Google Maps lists a business with an address and phone
number. You can quickly and easily find a podcast that iTunes
has listed, but your computer is only finding the address and
description of the podcast. The computer then has to travel to
the actual podcast location &ndash;  where the RSS feed is hosted.</p>

<p>When you subscribe to a podcast through iTunes, the podcast
listing that you found in iTunes was only the map for your
computer to find the actual podcast and subscribe to it.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/getupandcode.png" width="400"></p>

<p>In the case of <a href="http://getupandcode.com">Get Up And Code</a>, as
shown in the above screenshot, your computer will be redirected
to the RSS feed hosted at <a href="http://GetUpAndCode.com">http://GetUpAndCode.com</a> to create the
subscription and to get updates from their RSS feed.</p>

<h2>So, How <em>Do</em> I Host My Podcast?</h2>

<p>You can&rsquo;t host your podcast directly in iTunes, but there are
plenty of services and other options for hosting. The choices
come down to a few basic things:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do it all yourself</li>
<li>Get a podcasting plugin for a blogging platform</li>
<li>Pay for a podcast hosting service</li>
</ul>


<h4>DIY</h4>

<p>The &ldquo;do-it-yourself&rdquo; crowd tends to be the software developer and
techie person that can build the software and services needed
for hosting. If you&rsquo;re not a software developer, I don&rsquo;t recommend
this path. If you <em>are</em> a software developer, I still don&rsquo;t
recommend this path. It&rsquo;s tedious and painful, and fraught with
problems.</p>

<h4>Blogging Plugins</h4>

<p>If you&rsquo;re an avid blogger and you&rsquo;re already deeply entrenched
in to WordPress or any of the other major blogging platforms, you
can find plugins to make podcast hosting easy. You can upload a
file, use the <code>&lt;audio&gt;</code> tag in your post and be done with it. But
unless you&rsquo;re hosting your own servers and/or uploading your
episodes to another service, you&rsquo;re probably going to run in to
bandwidth and other limitations.</p>

<p>Everyone that I have spoken to,
that says they are hosting a podcast on WordPress, says they
eventually ran in to problems. It can be done for small podcasts,
and it can be cheap and easy. But with substantial growth in the
populartiy of the podcast comes potential for substantial cost
and problems.</p>

<h4>Podcast Hosting Services</h4>

<p>The last option listed, paying for a podcast host, is going to
be the best option for any serious podcast. You don&rsquo;t want to
manage file security. You don&rsquo;t want to deal with server
configuration. You don&rsquo;t want to build traffic reports, manually.
You just want to podcast.</p>

<p>There are a lot of options for hosting your podcast episodes,
including SignalLeaf. I don&rsquo;t claim
to be the one-and-only solution, or the one that fits everyone&rsquo;s
needs. I do have a very simple, very flexible solution, though.
If you&rsquo;re looking for a podcast host that focuses solely on
providing storage, bandwidth, RSS feed generation and traffic
analysis, then <strong>SignalLeaf is a great choice for you</strong>.</p>

<h2>Start Your Podcast Today!</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re starting a podcast, or are looking for a new host,
then you&rsquo;re in the right place! SignalLeaf offers a range
of flexible plans, with top-of-the-line podcast hosting and
streaming services.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://signalleaf.com/plans">Start Your Free Trial, Today!</a></strong>
You can get your podcast submitted to the iTunes &ldquo;map&rdquo; and
get subscribers driving to your new address, in minutes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome! And Episode 1 Of Signals And Leaves]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> blog!
Consider this the obligatory &ldquo;hello world!&rdquo; blog post for the
new blog: Signals And Leaves. Read on for a little bit of info
on what SignalLeaf is, what it provides, and what I&rsquo;ll be doing
with the Signals And Leaves podcast and blog!</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>About SignalLeaf</h2>

<p><a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> is a small, but growing podcast audio hosting service.
Other podcast hosts want to up-sell you on features like
content management, advertising inserts, specialized podcasting
apps, and other bits that you won&rsquo;t need. SignalLeaf is different
in that I focus solely on four critical features that you need
for your podcast:</p>

<ol>
<li>.mp3 file hosting</li>
<li>RSS feed generation for podcast subscribers</li>
<li>Bandwidth for streaming episodes to your listeners</li>
<li>Traffic and analysis reports</li>
</ol>


<p>This pin-point focus on the services that SignalLeaf offers means
you are free to build a website that fits your needs, without
worrying about whether or not your podcast will fit in to it.
You can use any platform and any tools to build your site, and
embed podcast episodes from SignalLeaf, with ease!</p>

<p>Already have a blog or a site? Setting up a blog with
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-wordpress">WordPress</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-tumblr">Tumblr</a>?
Building a site on your own, using the
tools and skills that you already posess will not stop you from
adding a podcast. Just grab
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-the-signalleaf-media-player">the emded code</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-your-own-media-player">host the episode in your own media player</a>
on your site!</p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re ready to get started with the easiest way to host your
podcast audio and RSS feed, head over to <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a>
and sign up for you free trial!</p>

<h2>About The Blog</h2>

<p>Signals And Leaves is a blog about podcasting, building and running
a podcasting service, and everything that entails. You&rsquo;ll hear tips
and tricks for podcasting. You&rsquo;ll find podcast episodes that SignalLeaf
hosts and produces. You&rsquo;ll get pointers to the right equipment, and
see a lot of other bits about hosting, producing and making the most of
a podcast.</p>

<p>Subscribe to <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" title="">the blog RSS feed</a>
to keep up to date with the latest and greatest in podcast audio hosting,
tips and tricks, and other information to keep you on the forefront
of podcasting!</p>

<h2>About The Podcast</h2>

<p>In addition to this being a blog, I&rsquo;m also running a podcast by the
same name: Signals And Leaves. I&rsquo;ve only recorded one episode so far,
but will be recording and publishing additional episodes, soon.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52374abd66f52c0200000005/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Be sure to subscribe to the podcast through <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the RSS feed</a>
directly, or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">subscribe through iTunes</a>
to hear the latest on what&rsquo;s happening with SignalLeaf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
