<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-17T22:31:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MP3 Bit Rates, File Size, And Audio Quality]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-18T07:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/">a previous blog post</a>
I talked about the need for both file and audio compression
on your podcasts. At the end of that post, I linked out to
<a href="https://gist.github.com/scottburton11/3222152">an article from Scott Burton on audio compression</a>,
but did not have any information on MP3 file compression at
the time.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/c-clamp-mp3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Well, I have all the MP3 file compression information, along with
bit rates and my own judgement on audio quality vs file size now.
And you might be surprised at the results! I know I was!</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Episode Content And Bit Rates</h2>

<p>I recorded a 32 minute podcast episode that contains 2 things:</p>

<ol>
<li>A musical introduction</li>
<li>A lengty spoken track</li>
</ol>


<p>The musical introduction takes not quite a minute, with the
spoken audio taking up the rest of the 32 minutes. The spoken
audio is not a complete episode, however. It is only a 1+
minute description of the episode&rsquo;s purpose, repeated over
and over and over again to get a podcast episode of
approximately average length. In other words, <strong>don&rsquo;t bother
listening past the first minute and a half</strong>. It just repeats
for a long time to make the point of file size vs content
length.</p>

<p>After recording the episode, I exported it under 10
separate bit rate settings, using <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Aadacity</a>.
The bit rates include:</p>

<ul>
<li>16K Constant Rate</li>
<li>32K Constant Rate</li>
<li>64K Constant Rate</li>
<li>128K Constant Rate</li>
<li>256K Constant Rate</li>
</ul>


<p>And:</p>

<ul>
<li>48K &ndash; 85K Variable Rate</li>
<li>80K &ndash; 120K Variable Rate</li>
<li>145K &ndash; 185K Variable Rate</li>
<li>170K &ndash; 210K Variable Rate</li>
<li>220K &ndash; 260K Variable Rate</li>
</ul>


<h2>The Episodes</h2>

<p>With all of these bit rate exports, I create a special
podcast on SignalLeaf just for these episodes. You can
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/52b10a635b56000200000011/rss">subscribe to the podcast RSS feed</a>
and listen to each of the episodes in iTunes and other
podcast players, or you can use the embedded players here.</p>

<h4>Constant Bit Rate Versions</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10ade4cacd40200000050/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10cf04cacd40200000051/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10d824cacd40200000053/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10e6e5b56000200000017/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b110185b56000200000018/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<p>&nbsp;</p>


<h4>Variable Bit Rate Versions</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b111a44cacd40200000059/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b115e44cacd4020000005a/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b117d94cacd4020000005c/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b119354cacd4020000005e/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b11a315b56000200000022/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>The (Surprising) Results</h2>

<p>As you would expect, the low-end results of the 16K bit rate
are attrocious. If it wasn&rsquo;t for the ridiculously small
file size, this would never even be an option. In fact, I&rsquo;m
going to call it not an option anyways, in spite of the file
size. The audio quality is simply horrible. I wouldn&rsquo;t inflict
that on anyone.</p>

<p>I had always thought that a variable bit rate .mp3 file was going
to be smaller, but I had no idea just how much smaller they
would be &ndash; especially when comparing the file audio quality
near their counterpart in the constant rates.</p>

<p>The other surprising result is how little difference there is,
if there is any perceivable difference, between 128K and
anything above it. At least with spoken podcasts, I don&rsquo;t see
any need to ever use anything above 128K Constant rate, or
the near equivalent quality of 80K-120K Variable rate.</p>

<h2>Final Recommendation 80K-120K Variable Rate</h2>

<p>If I were going to recommend one signal bit rate to encode
your podcast .mp3 files, it would be 80K-120K Variable bit
rate. The audio quality vs file size is superb, with little
to not distortion or wobbles in a mostly spoken podcast.</p>

<p>If you press me hard enough, I&rsquo;ll admit that I want the
145K-185K Variable rate for music based podcasts. The additional
layers of sound found in music can present some warbles
and distortion on the high end frequencies at lower rates.
Honestly it&rsquo;s probably not going to bother anyong at the
80K &ndash; 120K rate, but I prefer to be safe when it comes to
my music encoding.</p>

<p>Be sure to compress your audio files according to your
podcast needs, weighing file size vs audio quality and
available bandwidth.</p>

<p>Happy podcasting, all you Signalers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing The Prepare, Produce, Publish E-Book!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/17/announcing-the-prepare-produce-publish-ebook/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-17T13:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/17/announcing-the-prepare-produce-publish-ebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you want to start a podcast, but don&rsquo;t know where to start?
No problem! With nothing more than a laptop and an internet
connection, you can join the new media revolution and publish
your voice, your thoughts and your opinions to the world!</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast" target="_blank" class="center"><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/prepare-produce-publish-cover.png"></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Publish Your First Podcast</h2>

<p>Today, I&rsquo;m happy to announce the availability of my e-book,
&ldquo;<a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast">Prepare, Produce, Publish: Your First Podcast In 3 Easy Steps!</a>&rdquo;</p>

<p>This book is all about getting you started in the world of
podcasting. From the equipment that you need (<em>and don&rsquo;t need!</em>)
to using Audacity for recording your first episode, and how
to publish your podcast through a hosting service, this book
covers it all for for the new podcaster!</p>

<h2>Early Bird Pricing And Updates</h2>

<p>This ebook is currently a work in progress. That means it is
not yet complete, but it still provides a ton of value as-is.
That also means that <strong>you, dear podcaster, get to purchase the
book at a discounted price!</strong> Better hurry, though&hellip; this
discount won&rsquo;t last forever! Once I&rsquo;ve got the book completed,
the price will jump!</p>

<p>In addition to getting it cheaper, you will also get all of
the updates, free! As soon as I publish an update to the book
you will have it available in your downloads, guaranteed. That
means you&rsquo;ll get all of the step by step instructions, tips
and tricks to publish your podcast as I write them!</p>

<h2>Get Your Podcast Published</h2>

<p>I know you&rsquo;ve been thinking about starting a podcast, so
<a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast">get the book and get your podcast
published in record time!</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Audio vs File Compression, And Why You Need Both]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-10T20:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bandwidth for streaming podcasts is expensive, and using it
up with podcast audio that is too quiet, then too loud, then
too quiet again is a giant waste of money. <strong>Fear not!</strong> Just
toss in a little bit of compression and you can <strong>save money,
conserve bandwidth, and please the ears of your listeners</strong>
all at the same time.</p>

<p>But&hellip; audio compression, or file compression? Wait, what&rsquo;s
the difference? I&rsquo;m already exporting to .mp3 files, and
they&rsquo;re compressed, right? Yes, but that&rsquo;s file compression.
Audio compression is something entirely different, and is
just as important. Knowing when you have enough compression
of both kinds is also important, and knowing what they are
and how they affect your podcast is critical.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>File Compression</h2>

<p>Nearly everyone that knows how to use a computer is familiar
with file compression. You&rsquo;ve seen it and its effects more
times than you can count. Ever had a .zip file? Or a .jpg
file (hint: you&rsquo;re looking at some on this site)? These file
extensions are indications of file compression protocols.
Podcasts that use .mp3 files also use compression. Each of
these compression types offers something different, and
specialized, and there are still hundreds (thousands?) of
other file compression types around.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/mp3-export-settings.png"></p>

<p>Delivering audio in a .mp3 file allows files to be much
smaller than other uncompressed formats. But this comes at
a cost. The mp3 format uses a lossy compression algorithm:
a means of compression that reduces the audio quality in order
to reduce the amount of information being stored in the file.
Smaller files come from less information being stored.</p>

<h4>How Much File Compression?</h4>

<p>The effect of a .mp3 file saved at a very low bit rate
is terrible sounding audio in some cases, but not in others.
This is what makes compression somewhat tricky.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re
recording human voices for a podcast, for example, you can
get away with a much lower quality file (lower bit rate).
There isn&rsquo;t a lot of dynamic range of content, or overlapping
content in a human voice &ndash; even with multiple people
speaking at the same time.</p>

<p>When recording musical
instruments, however, low quality audio becomes apparent
very quickly. If you choose a low bit rate for music,
high pitch sounds become distorted in odd ways
and low pitch sounds become muffled and muted. Mid range
sounds can do ok, still, but get mixed up with each other when
multiple instruments are in the same frequency range.  Music
demands a higher bit rate, but not alway the highest.</p>

<h4>Avoid &ldquo;A Copy Of A Copy&rdquo; Syndrome</h4>

<p>One thing you also need to be aware of: if you&rsquo;re importing
existing audio files in to your screencast, be sure they are
high quality to start with.</p>

<p>Why, you might ask? Have you ever made a photocopy of a
photocopy of a photocopy? Compressing already compressed audio
has the same effect. Starting with high quality sound will
ensure the file version sounds as good as possible.</p>

<h2>Audio Compression</h2>

<p>Audio compression can also have a dramatic effect on the
quality of audio, but in a very different way.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/garage-band-compression-settings.png"></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;ve ever heard a song or a podcast or a radio station
where literally everything came out at exactly the same
volume level &ndash; not matter whether the person was wispering,
or the music was supposed to be subdued and quiet &ndash; you&rsquo;ve
heard the ill-effects of over-compressing audio.</p>

<p>On the opposite end of the spectrum, is classical music. If
you&rsquo;ve ever tried to listen to classical music in a car or
on public transport systems, you&rsquo;ve probably been frustrated
by the near impossible to hear quiet moments followed by
ear-splitting loud moments. This is the effect of no audio
compression at all.</p>

<h4>Controlling Signal Levels (Volume)</h4>

<p>Audio compression is a means of flattening the signal level
for the audio track(s) being compressed. It makes the quiet
parts louder so you can still hear them, and makes the loud
parts quieter so they don&rsquo;t blow your ear drums out.</p>

<p>Too much compression makes everything sound flat. It removes
all of the dynamics of the audio, preventing the natural
ebs and flows of volume differences. It tends to make things
sound over-produced. Radio stations tends to use a ton of
audio compression to compensate for road noise and other
ambient noises in the typical radio lisening environment:
transportation. Classical music, on the other hand, tends
to opt for purity and intent of the conductor and
orechestra, leaving off any audio compression of any kind.
Because of this, classical music is usally best experienced
in quiet places.</p>

<h4>Audio Compression And Podcasts</h4>

<p>You need a minimum amount of audio compression in your
podcasts &ndash; whether it&rsquo;s a music podcast or a spoken / voice
podcast. Without it, your podcast will simply come out too
quiet most of the time, with sudden and bothersome loud
moments. But at the same time, you don&rsquo;t want to over-compress
your audio. This tends to create the appearance of yelling
all the time, because there are no dyanmics or variance in
your volume levels.</p>

<h4>Learning Through Practice</h4>

<p>There are no right and wrong settings for everyone, when
it comes to audio compression, though. Each persons voice
and speech patterns are unique, creating a need for variance
in how much compression is used. You&rsquo;ll want to practice some
with different levels of compression to find out what
works best for you.</p>

<h2>Where Do I Go From Here?</h2>

<p>The topics of what settings to change for what purpose in
both audio compression and file compression are worthy of
their own blog posts. Getting the high level idea of what
these things are and how the affect your podcast is an
important step in the right direction, though. Without this
basic understanding, having all the knowledge of what settings
to change won&rsquo;t mean much.</p>

<p>For tips and advice on audio compression settings,
check out <a href="https://gist.github.com/scottburton11/3222152">Scott Burton&rsquo;s post on audio compression</a>.
This is a great starting point with advice on what the different
settings for audio compression will do. This is a post that
deserves your attention &ndash; one that I wanted to write, but
would rather share Scott&rsquo;s quality work.</p>

<p>For info on file compression, bit rates and the effects that
they have on your .mp3 file exports, <strong>be sure to subscribe
the mailing list, below</strong> and the RSS Feed for this blog!
I&rsquo;ll be recording a sample podcast soon, and running it
through various bit rates for .mp3 file export. You won&rsquo;t
want to miss that post!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 3: Tips On Podcasting With Podcaster, John Sonmez]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, I have the pleasure of interview my friend
and fellow podcaster, John Sonmez from <a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a>.
We talk about his podcast at <a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetupAndCode.com</a>
&ndash; a podcast that combines fitness and programming &ndash; and dig in
to his lessons learned, success and failures in podcasting. It&rsquo;s
a great episode full of useful tips for those that are just
starting as well as those that have already started to get on
a roll with a podcast.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52a2b2fd9903dd0200000021/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Podcast Pro-Tip</h2>

<p>Use the &ldquo;clap trick&rdquo; to sync separate tracks recorded from
different computers. One person counts to 3, and on 3, everyone
in the podcast claps. Then you can sync the separate audio
tracks to the clap at the beginning.</p>

<p><strong>Listen to the first minute of the episode for a demonstration
of this technique!</strong></p>

<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>Niche-down to find your target audience &ndash; don&rsquo;t try to be
everything to everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Coordination with cohost requires planning and commitment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>have a backup episode in case you can&rsquo;t make it for some reason</li>
<li>decide on a release cadence that you can handle, and stick with it no matter what</li>
</ul>


<p>Don&rsquo;t wait for perfect. Get something done and released</p>

<p><strong>Nerves are expected when you start</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s new</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s different</li>
<li>that&rsquo;s ok</li>
<li>you will improve over time</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mistakes happen &ndash; move on</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s a conversation between you and the host / guest</li>
<li>keep the content focused and relevant</li>
<li>just relax and have fun</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You know something others don&rsquo;t</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>if it&rsquo;s just your experience and perspective</li>
<li>your perspective is valuable</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Being new gives you a very valuable perspective</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>share your fears and mistakes with others</li>
<li>build the audience of people that are also new</li>
<li>help others learn with you</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>John&rsquo;s 3 lessons for someone just starting:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Streamlining: get all the infrastructure prep work (logo, domain name, blog, etc) done before you start recording. Start out professionally, with intro music, logo, etc (checkout fiverr.com for stuff like this)</li>
<li>Understand the process before you start. Practice by recording yourself and working through the process before you produce a real podcast. iTunes will not host your episodes (see blog.signalleaf.com for info on this)</li>
<li>Set up process, with consistency, ahead of time. Don&rsquo;t be left hanging after you record your first episode. You need to be consistent in order to grow a returning audience.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Have Your Own Tips To Share?</h2>

<p>If you have a podcast, then yes, you have lessons learned and info to
share with a growing audience. I want to interview you on
the Signals And Leaves podcast!</p>

<p><strong>So, <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">get in touch</a>
and let me know you want to be on the show!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Free Hosting Isn't "Free"]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/04/why-free-hosting-isnt-always-free/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-04T21:31:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/04/why-free-hosting-isnt-always-free</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I found <a href="http://webmasters.stackexchange.com/questions/52046/podcast-site-serve-audio-files-with-cdn/55791">a question on the StackExchange network</a>
regarding podcast hosting and the use of a CDN, with one answer
suggesting the use of SoundCloud for hosting.</p>

<blockquote><p>I am managing a small podcast website hosted on a shared server. Currently there are only eight or nine episodes, each of which are about 50 MB, so bandwidth is not really an issue at the moment.</p>

<p>However, looking forward, would it be feasible to use a &ldquo;free&rdquo; CDN like Cloudflare to serve the audio files? If so, how would I set this up?</p>

<p>I took a quick look at it before, and it seems you have to have your whole site routed (is that the right term?) through the CDN rather than just specific files or filetypes. I&rsquo;d like some clarification on this.</p></blockquote>

<p>It&rsquo;s an interesting question and idea, but one that
comes with a lot of potential problems.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you&rsquo;re not familiar with the idea behind a CDN, don&rsquo;t
worry about that. It&rsquo;s not something that most people need to
know about. If you&rsquo;re interested, though, check out
<a href="http://www.kendoui.com/blogs/teamblog/posts/13-11-07/know-when-to-cdn.aspx">my article on using CDNs in web development</a> (external link).</p>

<h2>Reduce Your File Size</h2>

<p>Before I address the hosting concerns, you should really try
to reduce your file size for the podcasts. Unless your podcast
episodes are 2 to 4 hours long, each, you shouldn&rsquo;t be
reaching 50 megs per file. Try reducing the audio quality in
your mp3 files (and use .mp3 file compression if you&rsquo;re not
already &ndash; it&rsquo;s the podcast industry standard). If you have a
45 minute podcast, you should be able to get your .mp3 file
down to around 15 to 20 megs, tops, without any significant
reduction in sound quality for spoken voice podcasts. Music
podcasts may be different, and you probably want higher
quality, but those are the exception where voice based
podcasts tend to be the rule.</p>

<h2>Free Hosting Is Almost Never &ldquo;Free&rdquo;</h2>

<p>When it comes to bandwidth and hosting, you really want to
avoid free if possible.</p>

<p>On the bandwidth side, free tends to be awful. CDNs are not
meant to be used for very large files that are downloaded
frequently, like podcast files. CDNs are typically meant for
smaller files, like static HTML, JavaScript, CSS and images.
You&rsquo;ll quickly realize just how &ldquo;free&rdquo; a free CDN is when
your downloads get throttled down to slow speeds or your
account gets shut off because you&rsquo;re using too much bandwidth.</p>

<p>In addition to bandwidth and even file size limitations on
free accounts, you will likely end up with ads placed on your
content, when using free hosting services for things like
podcasts. Maybe you don&rsquo;t mind ads being placed on your
podcast, to get free hosting. But there are some real dangers
in this <a href="http://schoolofpodcasting.com/how-to-avoid-vibrator-commercials-on-your-podcast-say-no-to-free-media-hosting/">when your podcasts suddenly have ads for sex toys in them</a>!</p>

<p>(Note: that link is mostly safe for work. It&rsquo;s an article
about the dangers of free hosting, including a story that
is rather shocking, but has no unsafe images in it).</p>

<p>Finally, there is always a risk that your free account will
be taken out from under you, for no reason. Service providers
are not obligated to continue providing free service to
anyone, in the vast majority of cases. They may decide that
they can no longer afford it, and yank the rug out from
everyone that is hosted for free, or simply close up shop and
disappear. It happens more than people want to admit.</p>

<h2>SoundCloud Has Limits On Free</h2>

<p>One of the comments on the question suggested using SoundCloud
as a podcast host. This is a common thing to do, actually.
SoundCloud offers a unique spin on hosting audio and even
provides RSS and stats for podcasts. The reponder even note
that StackExchanged used SoundCloud (which may or may not
be accurate anymore&hellip; that should be verified).</p>

<p>StackExchange may use SoundCloud for it&rsquo;s podcast hosting,
but I guarantee they don&rsquo;t use a free account. Perhaps they
have some deal with SoundCloud where they don&rsquo;t get charged
anything, but this type of discount arrangement is very
different than the free account that SoundClod offers.</p>

<p><a href="http://help.soundcloud.com/customer/portal/articles/247820-what-s-the-difference-between-each-subscription-level-">From SoundCloud&rsquo;s website</a>,
you can see exactly what limitations you will run in to with
the free account:</p>

<blockquote><p>Free</p>

<ul>
<li><p>2 total upload hours</p></li>
<li><p>100 downloads/sound</p></li>
<li><p>Unlimited playlist creation</p></li>
<li><p>Some stats (see the amount of plays, downloads, comments and favorites of your tracks)</p></li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<h2>Free Trial and &ldquo;Freemium&rdquo; Are Legit</h2>

<p>There are other types of &ldquo;Free&rdquo; accounts than &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll give you
something for nothing&rdquo;, though.</p>

<p>Many services offer free trials
that give you a set time limit for using the service. This
type of &ldquo;free&rdquo; is usually legit. It gives you a way to try
out a service without having to pay anything, knowing that
if you like the service you&rsquo;ll have to pay to continue with
it. There&rsquo;s nothing wrong with free trials, and I actually
encourage people to try as many free trials as they need to,
to figure out what service fits their needs the best.</p>

<p>Other services, like SoundCloud, offer a &ldquo;freemium&rdquo; service
type. This is a service that gives you free service, typically
supported by ads or other monetiziation means. The free
service will have strict limitations on what you can and
cannot do, but won&rsquo;t stop your service after a certain period
of time. The idea is that after you get in to the service,
you&rsquo;ll be hooked and you&rsquo;ll want to pay for the services to
get the better features.</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s some debate about &ldquo;freemium&rdquo; services these days, with
a lot of companies saying it&rsquo;s not viable, and even some
companies going out of business because of it. Now imaging
how bad that would be if you were a paying customer of a
service and all the free accounts caused the service to go
out of business! I&rsquo;d be pretty upset about that.</p>

<h2>Your Best Option: Paid Podcast Hosting Service</h2>

<p>In the end, your best option is to pay for podcast hosting
services. There are a lot of great services available,
<strong>including my own at <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a></strong>,
LibSyn, Blubrry, and many more. These services start cheap &ndash;
very cheap &ndash; usually with a free trial before you actually
have to pay for anything. My <strong>SignalLeaf</strong> service has a
rather lengthy trial period compared to most. This gives you
plenty of time to figure out if you want to continue with the
service or not.</p>

<p>At only a few $ a month, paid podcast hosting services are
going to give you all the space you need for file storage and
bandwidth, provide an iTunes and other podcast app compatible
RSS feed, and give you all the stats and feedback that you
need for your podcast.</p>

<p>All of these paid services host their files on servers that
are going to stream your audio more reliably than any free
service you would find. By paying a company to host your
files, you are giving them incentive to make sure they are
keeping you happy and doing the best job possible to keep
your podcast rolling smoothly. SignalLeaf, for example,
uses Amazon S3 storage and streaming of all podcast files.
There&rsquo;s no way your listeners are going to use up the
bandwidth of S3. You&rsquo;ll never see a slow-down in delivery,
or have problems with file storage reliability.</p>

<p>Stats are also important if you&rsquo;re looking for motivation
to continue podcasting, or want sponsors. You&rsquo;re not going
to get the stats you need without paying for service, either.
Generating stats is not as simple as most people thing, which
is why it always takes a more expensive paid account to get
great stats.</p>

<hr />

<h2>Start Your Free Trial, Now!</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re serious about your podcasts, do yourself a favor
and get <a href="http://signalleaf.com">a podcast hosting service</a> to
handle the heavy lifting and distribution of your content.
You&rsquo;ll never be happier than if reduce your own burden so
that you can focus on the content, not the content delivery.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 2: Mic Positioning And Room Are More Important]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you think the quality of the microphone is going to make
or break your podcast? If you do, I&rsquo;d like to show you that
it won&rsquo;t. And if you already don&rsquo;t, then why are you still
obsessed with getting &ldquo;the right mic&rdquo;? Is it just another
excuse to not start that podcast?</p>

<p>In Episode 2 of the Signals And Leaves podcast, I&rsquo;ll show you
how the room your in, and the positioning of the mic, will
have far more impact on the quality of the recording that
you are getting.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/528d042ea88e1f020000000f/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>As you can hear in this episode, having a quality mic does
make a difference in the audio recording. But that is not
the most important thing when you&rsquo;re starting your podcast. You
would be better served to find the right room in which to
record, than to go out and spend money on a top quality mic.</p>

<p>Now that doesn&rsquo;t mean a quality mic doesn&rsquo;t make a difference.
You will hear the difference in this episode. But you&rsquo;ll also
hear the difference between an office, an ultra-echoy bathroom,
and a closet with near-perfect sound.</p>

<p>Having a good position for your microphone is also of importance,
and can make a huge difference even if you have a quality
mic to start with. At the end of the episode, I&rsquo;ll give you
several examples of good and bad mic positioning.</p>

<h4>Show Highlights</h4>

<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t worry about the quality of mic</li>
<li>Worry about the room you&rsquo;re recording in</li>
<li>Worry about the microphone positioning</li>
<li>Wait until you have a few episodes under your belt before buying a quality mic</li>
</ul>


<p>When you are ready to buy, I highly recommend
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000JM46FY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000JM46FY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Rode Podcaster</a>.
This is the mic I use, and I love it. This is the industry
standard for podcasting and screencasting. You can&rsquo;t go wrong
with the Rode Podcaster.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B000JM46FY" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>If you need high quality for a little less money, though,
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002VA464S/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B002VA464S&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Blue Yeti</a>
is also a great podcast microphone. I know a lot of people that
use this one, and it&rsquo;s a great mic.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B002VA464S" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Subscribe And Share This Episode!</h2>

<p>If you like this episode, be sure to subscribe to
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the Signals And Leaves RSS feed</a>,
or <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/signals-and-leaves/id739095095">subscribe in iTunes</a>.</p>

<p>And while you&rsquo;re at it, submit this episode to
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/submit">Hacker News</a>
and the <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/podcasts/">/r/podcasts sub-Reddit</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can't I Just Host My Podcast on iTunes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-18T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was talking with someone about a podcast
they are starting, recently, and I asked if they already had a
plan for hosting it. The response I got was surpising:</p>

<blockquote><p>we have not yet gotten to the question of hosting the podcast yet.
i was assuming we would do it though iTunes, but i haven&rsquo;t thought farther than that.</p></blockquote>

<p>This seems to be an common misunderstanding about iTunes,
unfortunately. Your subscribers find you through iTunes, right?
So, isn&rsquo;t that where you host your podcast?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Sorry, but no &ndash; podcasts distribution doesn&rsquo;t work like that.
Instead of uploading podcast episodes directly to iTunes, it&rsquo;s
only a network for finding and subscribing to podcast RSS feeds.
You still need your own host, bandwidth for streaming and RSS
for your podcast.</p>

<h2>iTunes And Google Maps</h2>

<p>Think of iTunes like Google Maps for podcasts. With Google
Maps, you can quickly and easily find
an address and a business, but Google Maps won&rsquo;t actually
take you there. You have to walk, drive, fly, or otherwise get
yourself to the real location that the map shows you.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/google-maps.png" width="400"></p>

<p>Podcasts in iTunes work the same way. iTunes will list your podcast
like Google Maps lists a business with an address and phone
number. You can quickly and easily find a podcast that iTunes
has listed, but your computer is only finding the address and
description of the podcast. The computer then has to travel to
the actual podcast location &ndash;  where the RSS feed is hosted.</p>

<p>When you subscribe to a podcast through iTunes, the podcast
listing that you found in iTunes was only the map for your
computer to find the actual podcast and subscribe to it.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/getupandcode.png" width="400"></p>

<p>In the case of <a href="http://getupandcode.com">Get Up And Code</a>, as
shown in the above screenshot, your computer will be redirected
to the RSS feed hosted at <a href="http://GetUpAndCode.com">http://GetUpAndCode.com</a> to create the
subscription and to get updates from their RSS feed.</p>

<h2>So, How <em>Do</em> I Host My Podcast?</h2>

<p>You can&rsquo;t host your podcast directly in iTunes, but there are
plenty of services and other options for hosting. The choices
come down to a few basic things:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do it all yourself</li>
<li>Get a podcasting plugin for a blogging platform</li>
<li>Pay for a podcast hosting service</li>
</ul>


<h4>DIY</h4>

<p>The &ldquo;do-it-yourself&rdquo; crowd tends to be the software developer and
techie person that can build the software and services needed
for hosting. If you&rsquo;re not a software developer, I don&rsquo;t recommend
this path. If you <em>are</em> a software developer, I still don&rsquo;t
recommend this path. It&rsquo;s tedious and painful, and fraught with
problems.</p>

<h4>Blogging Plugins</h4>

<p>If you&rsquo;re an avid blogger and you&rsquo;re already deeply entrenched
in to WordPress or any of the other major blogging platforms, you
can find plugins to make podcast hosting easy. You can upload a
file, use the <code>&lt;audio&gt;</code> tag in your post and be done with it. But
unless you&rsquo;re hosting your own servers and/or uploading your
episodes to another service, you&rsquo;re probably going to run in to
bandwidth and other limitations.</p>

<p>Everyone that I have spoken to,
that says they are hosting a podcast on WordPress, says they
eventually ran in to problems. It can be done for small podcasts,
and it can be cheap and easy. But with substantial growth in the
populartiy of the podcast comes potential for substantial cost
and problems.</p>

<h4>Podcast Hosting Services</h4>

<p>The last option listed, paying for a podcast host, is going to
be the best option for any serious podcast. You don&rsquo;t want to
manage file security. You don&rsquo;t want to deal with server
configuration. You don&rsquo;t want to build traffic reports, manually.
You just want to podcast.</p>

<p>There are a lot of options for hosting your podcast episodes,
including SignalLeaf. I don&rsquo;t claim
to be the one-and-only solution, or the one that fits everyone&rsquo;s
needs. I do have a very simple, very flexible solution, though.
If you&rsquo;re looking for a podcast host that focuses solely on
providing storage, bandwidth, RSS feed generation and traffic
analysis, then <strong>SignalLeaf is a great choice for you</strong>.</p>

<h2>Start Your Podcast Today!</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re starting a podcast, or are looking for a new host,
then you&rsquo;re in the right place! SignalLeaf offers a range
of flexible plans, with top-of-the-line podcast hosting and
streaming services.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://signalleaf.com/plans">Start Your Free Trial, Today!</a></strong>
You can get your podcast submitted to the iTunes &ldquo;map&rdquo; and
get subscribers driving to your new address, in minutes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome! And Episode 1 Of Signals And Leaves]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> blog!
Consider this the obligatory &ldquo;hello world!&rdquo; blog post for the
new blog: Signals And Leaves. Read on for a little bit of info
on what SignalLeaf is, what it provides, and what I&rsquo;ll be doing
with the Signals And Leaves podcast and blog!</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>About SignalLeaf</h2>

<p><a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> is a small, but growing podcast audio hosting service.
Other podcast hosts want to up-sell you on features like
content management, advertising inserts, specialized podcasting
apps, and other bits that you won&rsquo;t need. SignalLeaf is different
in that I focus solely on four critical features that you need
for your podcast:</p>

<ol>
<li>.mp3 file hosting</li>
<li>RSS feed generation for podcast subscribers</li>
<li>Bandwidth for streaming episodes to your listeners</li>
<li>Traffic and analysis reports</li>
</ol>


<p>This pin-point focus on the services that SignalLeaf offers means
you are free to build a website that fits your needs, without
worrying about whether or not your podcast will fit in to it.
You can use any platform and any tools to build your site, and
embed podcast episodes from SignalLeaf, with ease!</p>

<p>Already have a blog or a site? Setting up a blog with
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-wordpress">WordPress</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-tumblr">Tumblr</a>?
Building a site on your own, using the
tools and skills that you already posess will not stop you from
adding a podcast. Just grab
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-the-signalleaf-media-player">the emded code</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-your-own-media-player">host the episode in your own media player</a>
on your site!</p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re ready to get started with the easiest way to host your
podcast audio and RSS feed, head over to <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a>
and sign up for you free trial!</p>

<h2>About The Blog</h2>

<p>Signals And Leaves is a blog about podcasting, building and running
a podcasting service, and everything that entails. You&rsquo;ll hear tips
and tricks for podcasting. You&rsquo;ll find podcast episodes that SignalLeaf
hosts and produces. You&rsquo;ll get pointers to the right equipment, and
see a lot of other bits about hosting, producing and making the most of
a podcast.</p>

<p>Subscribe to <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" title="">the blog RSS feed</a>
to keep up to date with the latest and greatest in podcast audio hosting,
tips and tricks, and other information to keep you on the forefront
of podcasting!</p>

<h2>About The Podcast</h2>

<p>In addition to this being a blog, I&rsquo;m also running a podcast by the
same name: Signals And Leaves. I&rsquo;ve only recorded one episode so far,
but will be recording and publishing additional episodes, soon.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52374abd66f52c0200000005/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Be sure to subscribe to the podcast through <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the RSS feed</a>
directly, or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">subscribe through iTunes</a>
to hear the latest on what&rsquo;s happening with SignalLeaf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
