<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-17T14:36:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can't I Just Host My Podcast on iTunes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-18T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was talking with someone via email, recently, about a podcast
they are starting. This person clearly had all of the right tools
and skills for recording and editing the podcast, as they were
part of a band that has recorded and released albums. During the
conversation, I asked if they already had a plan for how they
were going to host the podcast. The response I got was not what
I expected:</p>

<blockquote><p>we have not yet gotten to the question of hosting the podcast yet.
i was assuming we would do it though iTunes, but i haven&rsquo;t thought farther than that.</p></blockquote>

<p>While I was surprised at first, this seems to be an
unfortunately common mistake. After all, your subscribers find
you through iTunes, right? So isn&rsquo;t that where you host your
podcast?</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>So, iTunes Won&rsquo;t Host My Podcast?</h2>

<p>I can understand this person&rsquo;s perspective on iTunes. They
are in a band. This band sells music through iTunes. iTunes
hosts the audio files for those song and album sales. Why wouldn&rsquo;t
it work the same way with podcasts?</p>

<p>Sorry, no &ndash; podcasts work a bit different than other audio, in
distribution and hosting. Instead of uploading podcast episodes
directly to iTunes, it is only a network for finding and
subscribing to podcast RSS feeds.</p>

<h2>iTunes And Google Maps</h2>

<p>Think of it like Google Maps&hellip; you can quickly and easily find
an address and a business on Google maps, but Google maps won&rsquo;t
take you there. You have to walk, drive, fly, or otherwise get
yourself to the real location that Google maps showed you.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/google-maps.png" width="400"></p>

<p>Podcasts in iTunes work the same way. iTunes lists your podcast
like Google maps lists a business with an address and phone
number. You can quickly and easily find a podcast that iTunes
has listed, but your computer is only find the address and
description of the podcast. The computer then has to travel to
the actual podcast location &ndash;  where the RSS feed is hosted.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/getupandcode.png" width="400"></p>

<p>When you subscribe to a podcast through iTunes, the podcast
listing that you found in iTunes was only the map for your
computer to find the actual podcast and subscribe to it.</p>

<p>In the case of <a href="http://getupandcode.com">Get Up And Code</a>, as
shown in the above screenshot, your computer will be redirected
to the RSS feed hosted at <a href="http://GetUpAndCode.com">http://GetUpAndCode.com</a> to create the
subscription and to get updates from their RSS feed.</p>

<h2>So, How <em>Do</em> I Host My Podcast?</h2>

<p>You can&rsquo;t host your podcast directly in iTunes, but there are
plenty of services and other options for hosting. The choices
come down to a few basic things:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do it all yourself</li>
<li>Get a podcasting plugin for a blogging platform</li>
<li>Pay for a podcast hosting service</li>
</ul>


<h4>DIY</h4>

<p>The &ldquo;do-it-yourself&rdquo; crowd tends to be the software developer and
techie person that can build the software and services needed
for hosting. If you&rsquo;re not a software developer, I don&rsquo;t recommend
this path. If you <em>are</em> a software developer, I still don&rsquo;t
recommend this path. It&rsquo;s tedious and painful, and wrought with
problems.</p>

<h4>Blogging Plugins</h4>

<p>If you&rsquo;re an avid blogger and you&rsquo;re already deeply entrenched
in to WordPress or any of the other major blogging platforms, you
can find plugins to make podcast hosting easy. You can upload a
file, use the <code>[audio]</code> tag in your post and be done with it. But
unless you&rsquo;re hosting your own servers and/or uploading your
episodes to another service, you&rsquo;re probably going to run in to
bandwidth and other limitations.</p>

<p>Everyone that I have spoken to,
that says they are hosting a podcast on WordPress, says they
eventually ran in to problems. It can be done for small podcasts,
and it can be cheap and easy. But with substantial growth in the
populartiy of the podcast comes potential for substantial cost
and problems.</p>

<h4>Podcast Hosting Services</h4>

<p>The last option listed, paying for a podcast host, is going to
be the best option for any serious podcast. You don&rsquo;t want to
manage file security. You don&rsquo;t want to deal with server
configuration. You don&rsquo;t want to build traffic reports, manually.
You just want to podcast.</p>

<p>There are a lot of options for hosting your podcast episodes,
including <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a>. I don&rsquo;t claim
to be the one-and-only solution, or the one that fits everyone&rsquo;s
needs. I do have a very simple, very flexible solution, though.
If you&rsquo;re looking for a podcast host that focuses solely on
providing storage, bandwidth, RSS feed generation and traffic
analysis, then <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> is probably
a good choice for you.</p>

<h2>Are You Looking For Podcast Hosting?</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for podcast hosting, you&rsquo;re reading the
right blog! I&rsquo;ve got a great service that is already serving
up some amazing podcasts, like <a href="http://getupandcode.com">Get Up And Code</a>.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for something more than what <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a>
provies, though, I still want to help you. I want to understand
your needs &ndash; what you&rsquo;re doing with your podcast, what blogging
platform or existing website you already have, etc. I want to
make sure you find the right solution, not just the
&ldquo;everyone is using them&rdquo; solution.</p>

<p><a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact" title="">Get in touch with me</a> and
I&rsquo;ll do what I can to help you find the solution that is right
for you, even if it isn&rsquo;t <a href="http://signalleaf.">SignalLeaf</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome! And Episode 1 Of Signals And Leaves]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> blog!
Consider this the obligatory &ldquo;hello world!&rdquo; blog post for the
new blog: Signals And Leaves. Read on for a little bit of info
on what SignalLeaf is, what it provides, and what I&rsquo;ll be doing
with the Signals And Leaves podcast and blog!</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>About SignalLeaf</h2>

<p><a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> is a small, but growing podcast audio hosting service.
Other podcast hosts want to up-sell you on features like
content management, advertising inserts, specialized podcasting
apps, and other bits that you won&rsquo;t need. SignalLeaf is different
in that I focus solely on four critical features that you need
for your podcast:</p>

<ol>
<li>.mp3 file hosting</li>
<li>RSS feed generation for podcast subscribers</li>
<li>Bandwidth for streaming episodes to your listeners</li>
<li>Traffic and analysis reports</li>
</ol>


<p>This pin-point focus on the services that SignalLeaf offers means
you are free to build a website that fits your needs, without
worrying about whether or not your podcast will fit in to it.
You can use any platform and any tools to build your site, and
embed podcast episodes from SignalLeaf, with ease!</p>

<p>Already have a blog or a site? Setting up a blog with
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-wordpress">WordPress</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-tumblr">Tumblr</a>?
Building a site on your own, using the
tools and skills that you already posess will not stop you from
adding a podcast. Just grab
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-the-signalleaf-media-player">the emded code</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-your-own-media-player">host the episode in your own media player</a>
on your site!</p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re ready to get started with the easiest way to host your
podcast audio and RSS feed, head over to <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a>
and sign up for you free trial!</p>

<h2>About The Blog</h2>

<p>Signals And Leaves is a blog about podcasting, building and running
a podcasting service, and everything that entails. You&rsquo;ll hear tips
and tricks for podcasting. You&rsquo;ll find podcast episodes that SignalLeaf
hosts and produces. You&rsquo;ll get pointers to the right equipment, and
see a lot of other bits about hosting, producing and making the most of
a podcast.</p>

<p>Subscribe to <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" title="">the blog RSS feed</a>
to keep up to date with the latest and greatest in podcast audio hosting,
tips and tricks, and other information to keep you on the forefront
of podcasting!</p>

<h2>About The Podcast</h2>

<p>In addition to this being a blog, I&rsquo;m also running a podcast by the
same name: Signals And Leaves. I&rsquo;ve only recorded one episode so far,
but will be recording and publishing additional episodes, soon.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52374abd66f52c0200000005/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Be sure to subscribe to the podcast through <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the RSS feed</a>
directly, or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">subscribe through iTunes</a>
to hear the latest on what&rsquo;s happening with SignalLeaf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
