<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tips and tricks | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/tips-and-tricks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T09:22:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 1 Thing You Need To Know About Your RSS Feed]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/03/21/the-1-thing-you-need-to-know-about-your-rss-feed/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-21T08:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/03/21/the-1-thing-you-need-to-know-about-your-rss-feed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of debate around whether or not you should &ldquo;rent
or own&rdquo; your podcast&rsquo;s RSS feed these days. Should you be
completely responsible for it? Should you own it &ndash; host it on
your website? Or should you rent your RSS
feed&rsquo;s delivery through a 3rd party service? While the debate
rages on with good arguments on either side of the fence, there&rsquo;s
ultimately only one thing that matters &ndash; just one thing you
need to ensure, that will make or break your RSS feed and your
podcast.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/rss-icon-itunes.jpg" class="center"></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The 1 Thing You Need To Know</h2>

<p>Let&rsquo;s face it, <strong>the one and only thing that you need to know
about your RSS feed is that it works</strong>. It needs to work
consistently and constantly. It needs to be available at all
times. When someone wants to check for your latest episode,
it can&rsquo;t be down. <strong>Your RSS feed needs to work. Always.</strong></p>

<p>There are a lot of factors that go in to keeping your RSS
feed up all the time, including whether you &ldquo;own&rdquo; or &ldquo;rent&rdquo;
your RSS feed and distribution. I&rsquo;m taking the terms from
real-estate here, where you either rent a
house/apartment/condo/whatever, or you buy
it and own it, paying a mortage (or flat out buy it if you&rsquo;re
wealthy enough). The analogy isn&rsquo;t perfect, but it illustrates
both the befits and drawbacks of both ideas.</p>

<h2>To Own Your RSS Feed?</h2>

<p>Owning your RSS feed means having it served from your website.
When someone wants to subscribe to your RSS feed, they go to
your website and get a URL that points to your domain name
for the feed. The feed is built and served by your website. This
is similar to owning a house. Once you own it, you&rsquo;re responsible
for it.</p>

<h3>Benefits Of Ownership</h3>

<p>There are two primary benfits of owning your RSS feed
distribution:</p>

<ol>
<li>Traffic goes to your site</li>
<li>A 3rd party service going down won&rsquo;t take your feed down</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>The primary benfit is being in complete control over your
feed.</strong> There is never a third party involved in getting your
feed distributed to other people. When you get a lot of traffic
on your blog and / or podcast, you are the one that gets the
traffic on your site.</p>

<p><strong>If a third party site that hosts your
RSS feed goes down for some reason, you may be out of luck
while you wait for it to come back up.</strong> Owning your RSS feed
means you are not waiting on a third party service to fix
their stuff.</p>

<p>There are some other small benefits as well, but these are the
major ones that you&rsquo;ll get. Unfortunately, though, there are also
downsides to ownership.</p>

<h3>Downsides Of Ownership</h3>

<p>While the major benefit of ownership is being in complete
control of your feed, there are downsides as well.</p>

<ol>
<li>You are responsible, not someone else, when it breaks</li>
<li>You may not get the best statistics for your RSS</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>The major downside is that you are
completely responsible for your feed!</strong> Again, it&rsquo;s like home ownership. The moment you go from renting
your home/apartment/whatever, to owning it, you are suddenly
responsible for it. Yes, you can hire someone else to maintain
it for you, but <strong>it&rsquo;s ultimately up to you make sure the
maintenance happens</strong>.</p>

<p>When was the last time you had a plumbing leak in your house?
Was it fun to call plumbers and get charged $150/hr or more?
<strong>When your website goes down, guess who gets to fix it&hellip; or at
least has to call someone to fix it.</strong> And guess how much they&rsquo;ll
charge you to fix it?</p>

<p>The last major downside is statistics. Unless you have a great
log analyzer service, you&rsquo;re not going to get very good statistics
from your own RSS feed. It takes a fair amount of work to
analyze logs from your website and create something meaningful
from it. Chances are, you&rsquo;ll be using a third party for the
analytics, anyways.</p>

<h2>To Rent Your RSS Feed Distribution?</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Renting&rdquo; your RSS feed is similar to renting an apartment or
house. It means you have *a third party involved and the RSS
feed that people subscribe to is not directly on your website**.
There is a service you&rsquo;re using to host your podcast audio,
and generate your RSS feed for you. All of the major podcast
hosts, including SignalLeaf, will do this for you.</p>

<h3>Benefits Of Renting</h3>

<p>There are two primary benefits to renting:</p>

<ol>
<li>You are not responsible for the feed going down</li>
<li>You can get better stats from a 3rd party service</li>
</ol>


<p>Owning your RSS feed delivery sounds great, until you realize
that you are solely responsible for keeping the feed up and
running. If you are distributing the RSS feed from a third party
service, though, then that party becomes responsible.</p>

<p>Services
like FeedBlitz specialize in keeping systems up and running. They
have a very large infrastructure dedicated to this. They will
make sure that your RSS feed is avaialble all the time. How
much money are you willing to spend on your own servers to
ensure they are always up?</p>

<p>Statistics and analytics for your RSS feed are also important.
You need to know how many subscribers you have on your RSS
feed and be able to compare that to your downloads for episodes.
Having your RSS feed hosted by the service that also hosts your
podcast audio means you&rsquo;ll be able to get better stats on your
subscribers.</p>

<h3>Downside Of Renting</h3>

<p>There are 3 major downsides to renting your RSS feed:</p>

<ol>
<li>Third party goes down, you go down</li>
<li>Someone else gets the RSS feed traffic</li>
<li>Changing your RSS feed is hard</li>
</ol>


<p>The primary problem of using a third party is the possibility
for them going down. If they go down, you are waiting for them
to come back up before your RSS works again. I honestly don&rsquo;t
think this is much of a problem. The podcast hosting and
RSS generating services out there are going to be solid. They
won&rsquo;t get much business if they aren&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>The second problem is that someone else gets the RSS feed
traffic. You are trading traffic to your site for the security
of having someone else host your RSS feed, basically. This is
ok by me, as the RSS traffic isn&rsquo;t that important. You need
people to see your website and your content, and for that
you want traffic on your site. But when it comes to RSS? It
doesn&rsquo;t matter as much. RSS is consumed by computers, not by
people.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re using a 3rd party podcast hosting service for your
RSS feed and you want to switch away from them, you may run
in to some problems. Several of the big name players in podcast
hosting make it very difficult for you to migrate somewhere
else and keep your RSS feed and subscribers. It&rsquo;s a difficult
problem to solve, and some of the services out there make it
more difficult on purpose. They don&rsquo;t want you to leave because
they lose money. That&rsquo;s a horrible thing to do to customers,
even if the problem of migrating to another host is difficult.</p>

<h2>The Best Of Both?</h2>

<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of debate about owning vs renting, and for
good reason. There are positives and negatives of both. Personally,
I prefer a middle ground approach where I have a third party
service syndicating my RSS feed.</p>

<h3>Rent The Distribution!</h3>

<p>Two good examples of 3rd parties that let you &ldquo;rent&rdquo; RSS
distribution are Feedburner and FeedBlitz. Both of these services
will take your RSS feed from wherever you generate it, and
syndicate it to as many subscribers as you need.</p>

<p>By having a 3rd party syndication service, you get several
benefits:</p>

<ol>
<li>You&rsquo;re not responsible for the maintenance</li>
<li>You can change the source of your RSS feed any time</li>
<li>If your site goes down, the RSS stays up</li>
</ol>


<p>I&rsquo;m not willing to spend much money on server farms and large
operations to keep my websites up and running, honestly. I just
don&rsquo;t have the money to do this. I&rsquo;d rather pay to rent space
on someone else&rsquo;s service so that they can be responsible
for it. This can be detrimental to my RSS feed, though. So I
prefer to have a 3rd party distribution service, like FeedBlitz,
handle the distribution of my RSS feed.</p>

<p>With a service like FeedBlitz or FeedBurner, migrating to a new
blog platform or website service is also easy. I can change the
source of my RSS any time I want. I don&rsquo;t have to worry about
losing subscribers, because FeedBlitz is going to have the
same URL for my RSS all the time. I just point FeedBlitz at
my new RSS source, and all of my subscribers are instantly
seeing the feed from the new location. The subscribers don&rsquo;t
have to do anything.</p>

<p>Lastly, if my site goes down, the RSS feed for my subscribers
won&rsquo;t go down with it. I can have my blog down for hours or
days on end (which I don&rsquo;t want to do, of course) and my
subscribers will still be able to get to the RSS feed because
the 3rd party syndication service is handling it.</p>

<h2>Remember The 1 Thing You Need To Know</h2>

<p>In the end, there is one thing that you need to know about
your RSS. You need to know that it works. Beyond that, there
is still plenty of room for debate about
whether or not you should own your RSS feed and it&rsquo;s syndication.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re going to own the RSS feed, I personally think it&rsquo;s a
good idea to use a 3rd party syndication service. Even if
you&rsquo;re using a 3rd party syndication, though, I think it&rsquo;s a
good idea to have your podcast RSS served by the podcast host
so that you can get the best possible stats off the RSS feed.
If (when) you need to change podcast hosting services, the
3rd party will be there to ensure you don&rsquo;t lose subscribers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 5 With Rob Conery: Don't Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/26/episode-5-with-rob-conery-dont-suck/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-26T12:28:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/26/episode-5-with-rob-conery-dont-suck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode of the Signals &amp; Leaves podcast, I have the
pleasure of interviewing <a href="https://twitter.com/robconery">Rob Conery</a>
&ndash; a well known software developer,
<a href="http://wekeroad.com">blogger</a>,
<a href="http://tekpub.com">screencaster</a> and
<a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com">podcaster</a>.</p>

<p>Rob has an amazing
ability to create compelling stories out of interviews and
additional information that he gathers while researching a
subject. He has a knack for finding what he calls &ldquo;the truth&rdquo;
in an interview &ndash; that deep down part of the story where
the person talking is lost in thought, expressing their
inner-most sense of themselves in whatever they are talking
about. And I was lucky enough to get Rob to share how he
approaches story tellign in podcast, how he digs further for
the truth of the story, and how he puts it all together to
create something wonderful.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Show</h2>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves/52e5567fd97de30200000004/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>The Interview</h2>

<p>Along the path of this interview, Rob turns the tables on
me and shows how he approaches this by interviewing me about
this podcast. He talks about what it&rsquo;s like to keep digging
and to really listen for that moment when the speaker&rsquo;s voice
changes &ndash; the nuance that says the speaker is finally down to
the point where they are speaking from the heart of the
matter.</p>

<p>There more to it the interview than just the art of story
telling, though. We cover teaching, editing, adding dramatic
pause and affecting the over-all story as well.</p>

<p>Lastly, and perhaps most importantly, you&rsquo;ll also find out
what Rob means when he tells you, &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t suck.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t suck
at podcasting. Don&rsquo;t suck at conversations. Just don&rsquo;t suck.
It sounds like a rude awakening, and it may be for some. But
the point he makes is tremendously valuable.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/robconery">@robconery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wekeroad.com">Rob&rsquo;s Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://tekpub.com">Tekpub.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/">Scott Hanselman</a></li>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com">HanselMinutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/">This American Life</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
