<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: what not to do | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/what-not-to-do/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-06T21:41:32-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Of The Worst Things To Do When Starting A Podcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/06/4-of-the-worst-things-to-do-when-starting-a-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-06T20:32:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/06/4-of-the-worst-things-to-do-when-starting-a-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The web is full of great information on what you should be doing
when starting a podcast. There are hundreds, if not thousands,
of blog posts and web sites dedicated to helping you get up
and running &ndash; this one included. It doesn&rsquo;t take much more than
a google search or asking on twitter to find what you need to
know!</p>

<p>But this isn&rsquo;t another one of those feel-good, tell me what
I need posts. Rather, I want to mention a few of the things
that you should avoid doing when you&rsquo;re starting out. Understanding
what you should <em>not</em> do is just as important as understanding
what you <em>should</em> be doing &ndash; sometimes more important. These are
the things that will drive you to drink, if you&rsquo;re not careful.
These the things that you should avoid doing, at all costs.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/stop_drinking.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>#4: Stop Waiting To Start</h2>

<p><strong>This is the first great mistake that people make when starting
a podcast.</strong> They wait. They wait some more. They push things
back, and they delay yet again.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easy to get sucked in to
the idea that you&rsquo;re not ready. It&rsquo;s easy to fall victim to
procrastination, and to make yourself look busy without making
any actual progress.</p>

<p>Unforunately, it&rsquo;s in our nature to procrastinate. Even the
most amazing podcasters, like <a href="http://eofire.com">John Lee Dumas</a>,
have fallen victim to the delays. In <a href="http://launchingcreative.com/episode-1/">his interview with the Launching Creative podcast</a>,
John talked about how he was delaying and delaying until his
mentor finally said that he would be dropped as a client if he
didn&rsquo;t release the first episode that day. In the end, John
realized that the delays he put on himself were only setting
him back, not helping him.</p>

<p><strong>There is nothing that will demotivate
you faster than not getting your podcast published and live
for the world to hear.</strong> The sense of accomplishment and having
produced something is a tremendously motivating thing. You&rsquo;ll
find that once you start the work &ndash; once you start recording
and publishing episodes &ndash; that you want to do more.</p>

<p>Getting started and getting your first episode published is
by far the most important thing you can do for your podcasting
career or hobby.</p>

<h2>#3: Don&rsquo;t Obsess Over Your Stats (Listeners And Subscribers)</h2>

<p>Unless you&rsquo;re already internet famous, you&rsquo;re not going to launch
to a massive audience. You won&rsquo;t have thousands of downloads,
instantly. Chances are, you&rsquo;re not even going to have hundreds
of downloads until you&rsquo;re at least a few episodes in to the
podcast.</p>

<p><strong>Stop. Watching. Your. Reports.</strong></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the deal, and the reason this is so important: podcasts
are an inconsisten stream of traffic per episode. You might see a
number that you like after the first week of your first episode.
You might even see a bump after the second week. But once you
release that second episode, the numbers won&rsquo;t be as high.
The third episode? Even lower. <strong>THIS IS NORMAL!</strong></p>

<p>The average shelf life of a podcast episode is 6 weeks. <strong>6
weeks.</strong> This means your first episode will continue to accrue
traffic for around 6 weeks. You&rsquo;ll stil get traffic hitting it
after that, but it won&rsquo;t be as steady. During that 6 weeks of
life for your first episode, your other episodes won&rsquo;t have
as much traffice. You&rsquo;ll see a natural dip in the numbers
because those episodes haven&rsquo;t been around as long and won&rsquo;t
instantly catch up or shoot past your first one.</p>

<p><strong>It takes time for the numbers to settle in and level out.
Only after this shelf life will you be able to see that your
audience is growing.</strong> And it&rsquo;s the slow, steady growth after
the 6 week mark that you want to see.</p>

<h2>#2: Don&rsquo;t Wait For Listeners To Find You</h2>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;If you build it, they will come&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>the Field Of Dreams Fallacy
has cursed a generation of movie lovers in to thinking that
they will have instant fans and stardom</strong> if they just build it
and ship it, people will find it and love them. <strong>This couldn&rsquo;t
be further from the truth.</strong> But you know what? That&rsquo;s ok.</p>

<p><strong>You&rsquo;re not doing this for instant
celebrity status</strong>, and the drug-rush of watching your stats
fly off the meter. And believe me &ndash; this is a habbit forming
drug. I suffer from this as much as anyone else I know. It&rsquo;s
the curse of the always-on, data-filled digital lives that
we live. We want to see every time someone hits our site, listens
to our podcast, or tells us something on twitter, facebook,
and every other site in the world.</p>

<p><strong>Get 10 episodes published, first</strong> &ndash; not just &ldquo;done&rdquo;, but
actually published. Talk the episodes on twitter, facebook,
pinterest and everywhere else. Blog about the episodes &ndash; <strong>every
episode gets a blog post</strong>, in fact. Find places where people
that would benefit from your podcast are found, and tell those
people about your podcast. Do this for 10 episodes and then
start looking at your stats. You&rsquo;ll see growth, instead of flat
or falling numbers.</p>

<p>Once you see growth, you know you&rsquo;ve started to show up on
people&rsquo;s radar. <strong>Listeners will start to find you. But that
doesn&rsquo;t mean your done.</strong> The reason people are starting to find
you now is because you did the leg work of putting yourself
in front of them. <strong>Don&rsquo;t stop doing the leg work. Keep it up.
Your audience will grow.</strong></p>

<h2>#1: Don&rsquo;t Stop!</h2>

<p>This, above all other things, is the biggest mistake that new
podcasters make.</p>

<p><strong>The average podcast only makes it to episode 6 or 7 before it
stops.</strong> There are a lot of reasons for this, but in my
experience and in talking with others, it usually comes down to
time committment and what looks like a lack of growth in
audience. It just doesn&rsquo;t seem to be worth the effort, and
your day job is getting stressful again while the spouse and/or
kids are starting to wonder where you&rsquo;re at in the evenings&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>It&rsquo;s easy to get overhwelmed.</strong> And it&rsquo;s easy to think that
you need to have a regular and set schedule in order to be
a podcaster. After all, most of the podcasting industry tells
you this. <strong>Don&rsquo;t believe it for a minute.</strong> This is your
podcast. This is your story; your life; your work. You and only
you are in charge of how often you release an episode.</p>

<p>Just because you missed a week, or you only have time to
release one episode every month, doesn&rsquo;t mean you should
give up. Schedule the time for your podcast, like you would
do with anything else in your life. Set time aside, but
only time that you are comfortable with. <strong>Don&rsquo;t push yourself
to do more just because some podcasting &ldquo;professional&rdquo;
says you have to.</strong> You don&rsquo;t need to stop podcasting just
because you can&rsquo;t get this episode done and released &ldquo;on time&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Most Importantly: Have Fun!</h2>

<p>Podcasting is the new media revolution for this decade. Much
like blogging was in the previous decade, there will be alot of
growth and change in the industry. Join the growing community
and let your voice be heard. Build intimate connections with
your audience and allow them to know you, on your terms. This is
an exciting new media opportunity on many fronts, and <strong>it should
be something you enjoy!</strong> It may be hard work &ndash; well, it <em>will</em>
be hard work at times &ndash; but <strong>nothing worth doing is easy</strong>.</p>

<h2>Want To Know More?</h2>

<p>Like what you read here? Want more info to help you get past your
hurdles and podcast like a pro? <strong>Sign up for the mailing list,
below</strong> and you&rsquo;ll receive the latest news, tips and articles!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
