<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tips | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-31T11:33:41-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Waiting For The Right Equipment. Start Podcasting Now!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/29/stop-waiting-for-the-right-equipment/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-29T06:48:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/29/stop-waiting-for-the-right-equipment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s not shortage of people and websites claiming that they
have &ldquo;the right equipment&rdquo; for you to get started with your
podcast. Even <a href="/equipment">this blog</a>
has an equipment list. And there seems to be a constant clammor
for more, all around the internet. I&rsquo;ll make it simple
for you, though: <strong>start with what you have, or pick something
quickly and move on</strong>.</p>

<p>Choosing the right
equipment or the right software is a waste of time right now.
You need to be more concerned with preparing and producing the
content of your podcast at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The &ldquo;Right Equipment&rdquo; Is The Wrong Idea</h2>

<p>When you were learning to ride a bicycle, did your parents buy
you a $10,000 racing bike and enter you in the Tour de France?
When you were teaching your child to walk, did you buy them a
$300 pair of running shoes and ask them to run the Boston
Marathon? Of course not! The idea of that is ridiculous! Why,
then, do we expect people to buy new equipment and &ldquo;do it
right&rdquo; when they are starting out with podcasting?</p>

<p>Wait&hellip; you don&rsquo;t believe that this is happening? A casual search
on twitter reveals a number of people frustrated or waiting
because they don&rsquo;t have the right equipment, or asking about what
equipment they should get before they start.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> I have been researching this for weeks now and everything I have read has said the complete opposite to not start cheap. Lol</p>&mdash; Michael Wright (@MrWrightNow78) <a href="https://twitter.com/MrWrightNow78/statuses/417126714884780032">December 29, 2013</a></blockquote>


<p>These tweets often look like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>I want to start a podcast, but I don&rsquo;t have the right equipment</p></blockquote>

<p>Or</p>

<blockquote><p>What equipment do I need to start a podcast?</p></blockquote>

<p>These are questions on which people often get stuck. They assume
that you need a setup that looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/recording-studio.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m going to let you in on a little secret&hellip; <strong>your podcast
&ldquo;studio&rdquo; is going to look more like this, when you start</strong>:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/laptop.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Let me make this very clear: <strong>if you have a computer with a mic and an internet connection, you
already have the right equipment.</strong></p>

<h2>A Reward With No Effort</h2>

<p><a href="http://getupandcode.com">John Sonmez</a> summed up the problem quite nicely:</p>

<blockquote><p>Most people have it backwards.
They buy a treadmill thinking they will run because they spent $1k.
Or they buy new running shoes or a guitar.</p>

<p>The ones who actually succeed, run in old sneaker and tell themselves that when they have been running for 3 months they can buy real running shoes.
The ones who don&rsquo;t give up early are the ones who borrow a friend&rsquo;s piece of crap guitar and promise themselves that once they learn 10 songs they&rsquo;ll buy their own guitar.</p>

<p>When you already have the reward, you lack the motivation and you don&rsquo;t appreciate the instrument.
How do you appreciate $5,000 golf clubs if you never played with $50 golf clubs?</p></blockquote>

<p>The same is true of any reward, or any nice equipment for any purpose. Buying
the right equipment now is not a guarantee that you are going to produce a
great podcast. Wait until you have gone through the first experimental stages
and you know that you want to continue, having proven that you can produce
content.</p>

<p><strong>Once you have shown that you can produce content and get it delivered,
reward the effort with better equipment.</strong> But don&rsquo;t rely on the equipment to
make your job easy. It takes effort, no matter what equipment you are using.
The reason others make it look effortless, is not because of the equipment
they have. It is because they have struggled through
the learning curve and have mastered the tools and processes; they have earned
the equipment, the effortless production, and the audience.</p>

<p><strong>So get started now, with what you have.</strong> Earn the rewards of better equipment,
and build your audience and skillset through your efforts.</p>

<h2>A Computer, A Mic, And Internet Connection</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re reading this, you&rsquo;re using a computer.
Your computer may be called an iPhone or an iPad, it may be
an Android or a laptop of some sort. There are a lot of different
computers with a lot of different names. But they are all
computers and most of them can be used for recording your
podcast. <strong>The easiest computer to use for your first episode
is going to be a laptop, but nearly any computer and microphone
will work</strong>.</p>

<p>Speaking of microphones, that is something you need to
have in order to record your podcast. But,
nearly every computer comes with some sort of microphone built
in to it these days. If you have a headset with a mic, for gaming
or to use for Skyp and other chat services, that&rsquo;s even
better! You&rsquo;ll get better sound out of a headset than you will
out of a laptop mic. But <strong>I wouldn&rsquo;t let a laptop mic stop you
from starting your podcast</strong>. If it can record your voice, it can
be used to produce your podcast.</p>

<p>Lastly, <strong>you&rsquo;ll need access to the internet with a
fair upload speed</strong>. Smart phones, tablets, laptops and PCs of all sorts
have built-in internet connections that let us get online and
find everything we never wanted to know, and more! This same
internet connection is needed for uploading your podcast
episode to your podcast hosting service. But don&rsquo;t worry too
much about this. <strong>The connection is only really needed when you
are uploading your episode</strong>. You won&rsquo;t need a connection to
record a podcast, if you are only recording yourself or if
you have all of your guests in the same room as you.</p>

<h2>No More Excuses</h2>

<p>The truth is, <strong>a lot of people use the idea of not having &ldquo;the
right equipment&rdquo; as an excuse</strong> &ndash; even if they don&rsquo;t realize it.
It&rsquo;s easy to hide behind the
idea that you need to spend a lot of money on equipment. It&rsquo;s
easy to say that you&rsquo;ll get started once you save up enough to
get the right microphone. It&rsquo;s easy to put this off, because
it takes no effort. It takes no work. There is no committment
involved in not doing anything. Talk is cheap, and talking
about how you want to do this, but can&rsquo;t because you don&rsquo;t
the right equipment, is the cheapest of the cheap.</p>

<p><strong>The first podcast experience that you have is more about you
than anything else</strong>. It&rsquo;s about you getting comforable with the
idea of recording, of producing something, and putting your
thoughts out there for the world to hear. It&rsquo;s not about the
equipment that you do or don&rsquo;t have.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like <a href="http://jennybrewster.com/podcasting-equipment/">Jenny Brewster</a>
said:</p>

<blockquote><p>Record in the Cupboard if that’s where you’re happy</p></blockquote>

<p>Sure, if you happen to have
some equipment already, it might make your first episode sound
better. But it&rsquo;s not about the quality, when you&rsquo;re starting
out. <strong>Starting is all about getting up and running quickly.</strong></p>

<p>Yes, there is at a bare minimum amount of
equipment that you do need. The good news is that you
have everything you need, already.</p>

<h2>Published And Flawed Is Better Than Not Published</h2>

<p>This really is the point of what I&rsquo;m trying to say: it&rsquo;s far
better to have published a flawed podcast with less than perfect
audio quality, than to wait for the right equipment.</p>

<p><strong>Podcasting is like any other skill &ndash; it takes practices, not
money, to get good at it</strong>. Producing your first podcast may
feel awkward, but this is normal. Everyone goes through this
the first time they record something. But you&rsquo;ll find
that over time, your podcast quality will naturally improve.
You&rsquo;ll get better at speaking. You&rsquo;ll get better at positioning
the microphone. You&rsquo;ll be become more comfortable, and you&rsquo;ll
enjoy the process much more.</p>

<p><em>Don&rsquo;t wait for the right equipment. Use the equipment that you
have right now, and get started!</em></p>

<h3>Want To Know More About Getting Started?</h3>

<p>This blog post is the first chapter from my e-book,
<a href="/how-to-podcast">Prepare, Produce, Publish: Your first podcast, in 3 easy steps!</a>.
If you&rsquo;d like to know more about getting started, <strong>how to record your
first episode, where to publish the files and how to get your
podcast online quickly</strong>, get the e-book! <strong>It&rsquo;s FREE</strong> when you
sign up to receive all the latest podcasting news and tips! <strong>Just drop
your email address in to the form below and you&rsquo;ll receive the e-book
at no charge</strong>.</p>

<script async src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 3: Tips On Podcasting With Podcaster, John Sonmez]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, I have the pleasure of interview my friend
and fellow podcaster, John Sonmez from <a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a>.
We talk about his podcast at <a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetupAndCode.com</a>
&ndash; a podcast that combines fitness and programming &ndash; and dig in
to his lessons learned, success and failures in podcasting. It&rsquo;s
a great episode full of useful tips for those that are just
starting as well as those that have already started to get on
a roll with a podcast.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52a2b2fd9903dd0200000021/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Podcast Pro-Tip</h2>

<p>Use the &ldquo;clap trick&rdquo; to sync separate tracks recorded from
different computers. One person counts to 3, and on 3, everyone
in the podcast claps. Then you can sync the separate audio
tracks to the clap at the beginning.</p>

<p><strong>Listen to the first minute of the episode for a demonstration
of this technique!</strong></p>

<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>Niche-down to find your target audience &ndash; don&rsquo;t try to be
everything to everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Coordination with cohost requires planning and commitment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>have a backup episode in case you can&rsquo;t make it for some reason</li>
<li>decide on a release cadence that you can handle, and stick with it no matter what</li>
</ul>


<p>Don&rsquo;t wait for perfect. Get something done and released</p>

<p><strong>Nerves are expected when you start</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s new</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s different</li>
<li>that&rsquo;s ok</li>
<li>you will improve over time</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mistakes happen &ndash; move on</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s a conversation between you and the host / guest</li>
<li>keep the content focused and relevant</li>
<li>just relax and have fun</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You know something others don&rsquo;t</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>if it&rsquo;s just your experience and perspective</li>
<li>your perspective is valuable</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Being new gives you a very valuable perspective</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>share your fears and mistakes with others</li>
<li>build the audience of people that are also new</li>
<li>help others learn with you</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>John&rsquo;s 3 lessons for someone just starting:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Streamlining: get all the infrastructure prep work (logo, domain name, blog, etc) done before you start recording. Start out professionally, with intro music, logo, etc (checkout fiverr.com for stuff like this)</li>
<li>Understand the process before you start. Practice by recording yourself and working through the process before you produce a real podcast. iTunes will not host your episodes (see blog.signalleaf.com for info on this)</li>
<li>Set up process, with consistency, ahead of time. Don&rsquo;t be left hanging after you record your first episode. You need to be consistent in order to grow a returning audience.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Have Your Own Tips To Share?</h2>

<p>If you have a podcast, then yes, you have lessons learned and info to
share with a growing audience. I want to interview you on
the Signals And Leaves podcast!</p>

<p><strong>So, <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">get in touch</a>
and let me know you want to be on the show!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 2: Mic Positioning And Room Are More Important]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you think the quality of the microphone is going to make
or break your podcast? If you do, I&rsquo;d like to show you that
it won&rsquo;t. And if you already don&rsquo;t, then why are you still
obsessed with getting &ldquo;the right mic&rdquo;? Is it just another
excuse to not start that podcast?</p>

<p>In Episode 2 of the Signals And Leaves podcast, I&rsquo;ll show you
how the room your in, and the positioning of the mic, will
have far more impact on the quality of the recording that
you are getting.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/528d042ea88e1f020000000f/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>As you can hear in this episode, having a quality mic does
make a difference in the audio recording. But that is not
the most important thing when you&rsquo;re starting your podcast. You
would be better served to find the right room in which to
record, than to go out and spend money on a top quality mic.</p>

<p>Now that doesn&rsquo;t mean a quality mic doesn&rsquo;t make a difference.
You will hear the difference in this episode. But you&rsquo;ll also
hear the difference between an office, an ultra-echoy bathroom,
and a closet with near-perfect sound.</p>

<p>Having a good position for your microphone is also of importance,
and can make a huge difference even if you have a quality
mic to start with. At the end of the episode, I&rsquo;ll give you
several examples of good and bad mic positioning.</p>

<h4>Show Highlights</h4>

<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t worry about the quality of mic</li>
<li>Worry about the room you&rsquo;re recording in</li>
<li>Worry about the microphone positioning</li>
<li>Wait until you have a few episodes under your belt before buying a quality mic</li>
</ul>


<p>When you are ready to buy, I highly recommend
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000JM46FY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000JM46FY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Rode Podcaster</a>.
This is the mic I use, and I love it. This is the industry
standard for podcasting and screencasting. You can&rsquo;t go wrong
with the Rode Podcaster.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B000JM46FY" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>If you need high quality for a little less money, though,
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002VA464S/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B002VA464S&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Blue Yeti</a>
is also a great podcast microphone. I know a lot of people that
use this one, and it&rsquo;s a great mic.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B002VA464S" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Subscribe And Share This Episode!</h2>

<p>If you like this episode, be sure to subscribe to
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the Signals And Leaves RSS feed</a>,
or <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/signals-and-leaves/id739095095">subscribe in iTunes</a>.</p>

<p>And while you&rsquo;re at it, submit this episode to
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/submit">Hacker News</a>
and the <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/podcasts/">/r/podcasts sub-Reddit</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
