<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: interview | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/interview/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T09:24:25-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 5 With Rob Conery: Don't Suck]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/26/episode-5-with-rob-conery-dont-suck/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-26T12:28:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/26/episode-5-with-rob-conery-dont-suck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode of the Signals &amp; Leaves podcast, I have the
pleasure of interviewing <a href="https://twitter.com/robconery">Rob Conery</a>
&ndash; a well known software developer,
<a href="http://wekeroad.com">blogger</a>,
<a href="http://tekpub.com">screencaster</a> and
<a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com">podcaster</a>.</p>

<p>Rob has an amazing
ability to create compelling stories out of interviews and
additional information that he gathers while researching a
subject. He has a knack for finding what he calls &ldquo;the truth&rdquo;
in an interview &ndash; that deep down part of the story where
the person talking is lost in thought, expressing their
inner-most sense of themselves in whatever they are talking
about. And I was lucky enough to get Rob to share how he
approaches story tellign in podcast, how he digs further for
the truth of the story, and how he puts it all together to
create something wonderful.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Show</h2>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves/52e5567fd97de30200000004/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>The Interview</h2>

<p>Along the path of this interview, Rob turns the tables on
me and shows how he approaches this by interviewing me about
this podcast. He talks about what it&rsquo;s like to keep digging
and to really listen for that moment when the speaker&rsquo;s voice
changes &ndash; the nuance that says the speaker is finally down to
the point where they are speaking from the heart of the
matter.</p>

<p>There more to it the interview than just the art of story
telling, though. We cover teaching, editing, adding dramatic
pause and affecting the over-all story as well.</p>

<p>Lastly, and perhaps most importantly, you&rsquo;ll also find out
what Rob means when he tells you, &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t suck.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t suck
at podcasting. Don&rsquo;t suck at conversations. Just don&rsquo;t suck.
It sounds like a rude awakening, and it may be for some. But
the point he makes is tremendously valuable.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/robconery">@robconery</a></li>
<li><a href="http://wekeroad.com">Rob&rsquo;s Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://tekpub.com">Tekpub.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/">Scott Hanselman</a></li>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com">HanselMinutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/">This American Life</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 4 With Craig McKeachie]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/14/episode-4-with-craig-mckeachie/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-14T07:53:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/14/episode-4-with-craig-mckeachie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Signals And Leaves, Episode 4 with <a href="http://www.funnyant.com/">Craig McKeachie</a>.</strong></p>

<p>Craig is starting up a new podcast on front-end web development
and is going through all the usual steps of getting started,
getting episodes recorded and getting them published.</p>

<p>This episode was recorded live at <a href="http://codemash.org">CodeMash 2014</a>
in a room that was full of noise from ventilation and other
environmental things. I used <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a>
to clean up the noise, which worked surprisingly well. There is
some noise leftover during louder portions of the audio, though.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves/52d548eba8606a0200000004/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h3>Podcast Pro-tip</h3>

<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t forget your guests' name or credentials.</strong></p>

<p>This one is rather embarassing, I must say. Right as I was
starting the episode with Craig, I forgot his name. My brain
went completely blank. We laught it off at the beginning of
the episode, but it makes for a bad start to the episode.</p>

<h3>Equipment</h3>

<p>This episode was recorded entirely with a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003IJ3WIW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B003IJ3WIW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">Roland R05</a>.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B003IJ3WIW" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h3>Notes</h3>

<p>Podcasting is a great way to build an audience. It creates a
more intimate connection with listeners, vs written words.</p>

<p>Having multiple forms of media, such as book, blog, podcast,
etc, helps you build authority.</p>

<p>Podcasts introduce conversation instead of monologue. It&rsquo;s
easier to generate ideas, create something more valuable and
get more out of a conversation than a monologue, at times.</p>

<p>Choosing a name is hard &ndash; don&rsquo;t want to be too narrow, but
also want to identify and serve your audience, and deliver
value.</p>

<p>Getting feedback from trusted resources can give you confidence.
Even if you figure things out, find resources that teach you
and verify what you&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p>Podcast hosting eats up a lot of bandwidth. Be sure you have
a host that can handle the bandwidth. Find <a href="http://signalleaf.com">a podcast host</a>
when possible.</p>

<p>Average life of a podcast episode is 6 weeks. Bandwidth is
typically measured per month, but bandwidth for an episode can
be estimated from the 6 week download trend for past episodes.</p>

<p>Be careful of Feedburner and other free services. Feedburner
limits you to 512K feed size, and will drop episodes to keep
it small. FeedBlitz and other paid services won&rsquo;t introduce
this type of limit.</p>

<p>Your podcast needs RSS that is compatible with as many devices
and directories as possible. If your podcast hosting doesn&rsquo;t
ensure this, you will want to use a third party feed distribution
system like FeedBlitz.</p>

<p>Find a podcast / RSS host that provides the analytics you
need. <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> gives you a breakdown of
RSS vs embeded player vs downloads, for traffic reports.</p>

<p>Trade iTunes directory reviews with other podcasters. Find podcasts
that you&rsquo;re interested in. Listen to a few episodes, then contact
the author and ask them to review your podcast in exchange for
you reviewing them.</p>

<p>You need a blog for your podcast, whether it&rsquo;s part of your
primary website or a separate blog. Write a post for each
episode with a short list of notes from the episode, at least.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<p><a href="http://funnyant.com">Craig McKeachie / FunnyAnt</a></p>

<p><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com">Cliff Ravenscraft / Podcast Answerman</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.softwarebyrob.com/">Rob Wahling</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Pat Flynn / Smart Passive Income</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mixergy.com">Mixergy</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.entrepreneuronfire.com/">Entrepreneur On Fire</a></p>

<p><a href="http://jsjabber.com">JavaScript Jabber</a></p>

<p><a href="http://feedblitz.com">FeedBlitz</a></p>

<p><a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetUpAndCode.com</a></p>

<p><a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 3: Tips On Podcasting With Podcaster, John Sonmez]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, I have the pleasure of interview my friend
and fellow podcaster, John Sonmez from <a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a>.
We talk about his podcast at <a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetupAndCode.com</a>
&ndash; a podcast that combines fitness and programming &ndash; and dig in
to his lessons learned, success and failures in podcasting. It&rsquo;s
a great episode full of useful tips for those that are just
starting as well as those that have already started to get on
a roll with a podcast.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52a2b2fd9903dd0200000021/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Podcast Pro-Tip</h2>

<p>Use the &ldquo;clap trick&rdquo; to sync separate tracks recorded from
different computers. One person counts to 3, and on 3, everyone
in the podcast claps. Then you can sync the separate audio
tracks to the clap at the beginning.</p>

<p><strong>Listen to the first minute of the episode for a demonstration
of this technique!</strong></p>

<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>Niche-down to find your target audience &ndash; don&rsquo;t try to be
everything to everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Coordination with cohost requires planning and commitment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>have a backup episode in case you can&rsquo;t make it for some reason</li>
<li>decide on a release cadence that you can handle, and stick with it no matter what</li>
</ul>


<p>Don&rsquo;t wait for perfect. Get something done and released</p>

<p><strong>Nerves are expected when you start</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s new</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s different</li>
<li>that&rsquo;s ok</li>
<li>you will improve over time</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mistakes happen &ndash; move on</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s a conversation between you and the host / guest</li>
<li>keep the content focused and relevant</li>
<li>just relax and have fun</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You know something others don&rsquo;t</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>if it&rsquo;s just your experience and perspective</li>
<li>your perspective is valuable</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Being new gives you a very valuable perspective</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>share your fears and mistakes with others</li>
<li>build the audience of people that are also new</li>
<li>help others learn with you</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>John&rsquo;s 3 lessons for someone just starting:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Streamlining: get all the infrastructure prep work (logo, domain name, blog, etc) done before you start recording. Start out professionally, with intro music, logo, etc (checkout fiverr.com for stuff like this)</li>
<li>Understand the process before you start. Practice by recording yourself and working through the process before you produce a real podcast. iTunes will not host your episodes (see blog.signalleaf.com for info on this)</li>
<li>Set up process, with consistency, ahead of time. Don&rsquo;t be left hanging after you record your first episode. You need to be consistent in order to grow a returning audience.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Have Your Own Tips To Share?</h2>

<p>If you have a podcast, then yes, you have lessons learned and info to
share with a growing audience. I want to interview you on
the Signals And Leaves podcast!</p>

<p><strong>So, <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">get in touch</a>
and let me know you want to be on the show!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
