<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tricks | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/tricks/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T14:41:51-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 3: Tips On Podcasting With Podcaster, John Sonmez]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, I have the pleasure of interview my friend
and fellow podcaster, John Sonmez from <a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a>.
We talk about his podcast at <a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetupAndCode.com</a>
&ndash; a podcast that combines fitness and programming &ndash; and dig in
to his lessons learned, success and failures in podcasting. It&rsquo;s
a great episode full of useful tips for those that are just
starting as well as those that have already started to get on
a roll with a podcast.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52a2b2fd9903dd0200000021/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Podcast Pro-Tip</h2>

<p>Use the &ldquo;clap trick&rdquo; to sync separate tracks recorded from
different computers. One person counts to 3, and on 3, everyone
in the podcast claps. Then you can sync the separate audio
tracks to the clap at the beginning.</p>

<p><strong>Listen to the first minute of the episode for a demonstration
of this technique!</strong></p>

<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>Niche-down to find your target audience &ndash; don&rsquo;t try to be
everything to everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Coordination with cohost requires planning and commitment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>have a backup episode in case you can&rsquo;t make it for some reason</li>
<li>decide on a release cadence that you can handle, and stick with it no matter what</li>
</ul>


<p>Don&rsquo;t wait for perfect. Get something done and released</p>

<p><strong>Nerves are expected when you start</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s new</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s different</li>
<li>that&rsquo;s ok</li>
<li>you will improve over time</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mistakes happen &ndash; move on</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s a conversation between you and the host / guest</li>
<li>keep the content focused and relevant</li>
<li>just relax and have fun</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You know something others don&rsquo;t</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>if it&rsquo;s just your experience and perspective</li>
<li>your perspective is valuable</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Being new gives you a very valuable perspective</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>share your fears and mistakes with others</li>
<li>build the audience of people that are also new</li>
<li>help others learn with you</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>John&rsquo;s 3 lessons for someone just starting:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Streamlining: get all the infrastructure prep work (logo, domain name, blog, etc) done before you start recording. Start out professionally, with intro music, logo, etc (checkout fiverr.com for stuff like this)</li>
<li>Understand the process before you start. Practice by recording yourself and working through the process before you produce a real podcast. iTunes will not host your episodes (see blog.signalleaf.com for info on this)</li>
<li>Set up process, with consistency, ahead of time. Don&rsquo;t be left hanging after you record your first episode. You need to be consistent in order to grow a returning audience.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Have Your Own Tips To Share?</h2>

<p>If you have a podcast, then yes, you have lessons learned and info to
share with a growing audience. I want to interview you on
the Signals And Leaves podcast!</p>

<p><strong>So, <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">get in touch</a>
and let me know you want to be on the show!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
