<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: podcasting | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/podcasting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T14:42:09-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[50 Reasons Why You Need To Blog Every Podcast Episode]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/26/50-reasons-why-you-need-to-blog-every-podcast-episode/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-26T13:44:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/26/50-reasons-why-you-need-to-blog-every-podcast-episode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blogging is soooo last decade, right? It&rsquo;s the old, new media
revolution. Everyone built a blog and wrote about what they had
for breakfast. And didn&rsquo;t blogging get replaced by social media
sites dedicated to your favorite food pics?</p>

<p>Truth is, blogging is more important than ever. If you&rsquo;re
trying to build an audience of any kind, you need a blog. Of
course you might not want to fill your blog will your instamatic
style, vintage food photos &ndash; unless your blog is focused on
that. Your blog should be focused and reflect the content that
the audience want, wants to read. And yes, your audience of
podcast listeners also need you to have a blog.</p>

<p>If aren&rsquo;t already doing this, you need to start blogging
every episode of your podcast. And I&rsquo;ve got 50 reasons why
you need to start, today.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/signals-and-leaves-blog.png" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Reason #1: Summary, Show Notes And Transcript</h2>

<p>The most important thing to do with each podcast episode is
blog an episode player, show summary and show notes at a minimum.</p>

<p>The summary is usually just a paragraph or two that explains what the episode is about.
You&rsquo;ll want to include an introduction for your guest, the
range of topics covered, and any interesting bits of information
that the episode contains. You can get in to as much detail
as you want, but remember that this is supposed to be a summary.
People will read this to get an idea of whether or not they
want to listen to the episode.</p>

<p>Beyond a summary, show notes are a great idea. This will be
more detailed items from the discussions and points in the
show. The major difference here, is that the notes don&rsquo;t need
to be standard prose. They can be bullet points, links, or
anything else that makes sense. Think of this as taking notes
in a meeting or class &ndash; you don&rsquo;t write down everything, only
the important points that will remind you what to look at
later.</p>

<p>Lastly, a transcript of the episode can go a long way if you
have the time do it or the money to outsource having this
done. Having a transcript with your show notes and links will
provide an alternative way for your audience to get the
information they need. It also lets people copy &amp; paste
quotable things, instead of having to transcribe for
themselves.</p>

<h2>Reason #2: Search Engine Optimization (SEO)</h2>

<p>The more information you pack in to your summary, show notes
and transcript, the better you will rank in search engine
traffic. Google and other search engines need content to
index. Content for podcast episodes comes from the show
notes, links and transcripts.</p>

<p>If you have at least a section for a summary and notes /
links, then search engines will have something more valuable
by which you can be found. You&rsquo;ll start ranking higher in
search results, concerning the subject matter of your podcast.
Higher search engine traffic means building a larger audience.
Building a larger audience means getting better sponsors
(if that&rsquo;s your thing) and having more influence and credibility.</p>

<h2>Reason #50%: Half Of Your Audience Will Listen via The Blog Post</h2>

<p>Ok, I lied. This is actually the #1 reason that you should
blog every episode. While #1 and #2 listed above are great
reasons, they ultimately lead to this one very important
statistic:</p>

<p><strong>50% of your audience will listen via your blog</strong></p>

<p>I first heard about this via <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat Flynn&rsquo;s blog post on
redesigning his website</a>.
In that post, he talks about how the first version of
the site redesign dropped his podcast listening traffic
by 50%!</p>

<p><sub>(Image from <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat&rsquo;s blog post</a>)</sub>
<img src="http://cdn.smartpassiveincome.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/redesigndrop2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Following up on that thought, I dug in to the podcasts that
I&rsquo;m hosting on <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> and
confirmed this statistic in a majority of cases.</p>

<p>My own Signals And Leaves podcast, for example, shows a 51%
bias for listening to episodes via my blog posts.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/signals-and-leaves-51percent-embed.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>After seeing that confirmed on my podcast, I dug in to a few
others and saw the trend.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-52percent-embed.png" alt="" />
<img src="/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-56percent-embed.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Of course, not every podcast shows this trend. One in particular
doesn&rsquo;t use the embedded player that I provide. Instead,
they post to Facebook and want people to listen via RSS. They&rsquo;ve
experimented with an embedded player a few times, but
haven&rsquo;t used it much.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-65percent-rss.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>But with a majority of the podcasts that I analyzed having
50% + of their plays coming through their website, it&rsquo;s
rather plain to see that a blog post per episode is absolutely
critical for your audience.</p>

<h2>How Do I Get Embed vs RSS Reports?</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in getting the same level of reporting
that I&rsquo;ve shown here &ndash; the ability to know what percentage
of podcasts are coming from your blog posts, direct downloads
or through your RSS feed &ndash; you&rsquo;re in luck! <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a>
provides these reports for you, when you take advantage of
the SignalLeaf generated RSS feed and the SignalLeaf Player
for your blog posts.</p>

<p><strong> <a href="https://www.signalleaf.com/#plans">Sign up for SignalLeaf today</a>, and start seeing where your episode plays
are happening.</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Reports Do You Need For Your Podcast?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/14/what-reports-do-you-need-for-your-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T08:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/14/what-reports-do-you-need-for-your-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_podcast_report.png" width="300"></p>

<p>For some, podcasting is a creative outlet. It provides a way for
them to build an audience and create relationships and connections
with other like minded people. For the creative types that do
this for fun, having reports to show them how many listeners
they are getting is nice. They get to see how many people they
are potentially influencing, and it may help to drive them to
do more or do better.</p>

<p>For others, though, podcasting is more than just a hobby or an
outlet. It&rsquo;s a way of creating income, of sustaining themselves
or their family. For these podcaster, reports are critical.
They need to see how many downloads an individual episode has.
They need to see trends on what episodes are most effective.
They need to report these numbers to sponsors and potential
sponsors, so they can continue to bring in the income they
need.</p>

<p>With two very distinct audiences to serve, a report system for
a podcast can become overwhelming or underwhelming quickly. A
podcaster looking for simple reports may not care about having
everything. A podcaster that needs everything may get frustrated
at not having enough. Targeting different levels of reprots at
these two different audiences becomes important. But just having
this split doesn&rsquo;t answer the one fundamental question:</p>

<blockquote><p>What reports do you need?</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<h2>SignalLeaf&rsquo;s Current Reports</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m currently offering two different plans in SignalLeaf, to
differentiate between the two different types of reports that
people will need. This boils down to basic reports and advanced
reports, with the goal of serving the two identified audience
groups from above.</p>

<h3>The Basic Reports</h3>

<p>The cheapest plan offers a few very basic reports. At the
podcast, it will give you a total count of plays broken down
by type (rss, downloaded and SignalLeaf player). It will also
show you the total RSS subscriber count.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/basic_podcast_report.png"></p>

<p>At the episode level, this plan offers episode totals, broken
down by the same categories of RSS, downloads and use of the
SignalLeaf player.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/basic_episode_report.png"></p>

<h3>The Advanced Reports</h3>

<p>At the mid level and advanced plans, you&rsquo;ll get a bit more
information and breakdown in both the podcast and episode
reports. You&rsquo;ll get the same basic information, of course, but
the advanced reports add a little more.</p>

<p>The podcast level report offers a 30 day subscriber history,
so you can see the most recent trend of your subscriber count.
You will hopefully be seeing growth over time, but you will
likely see the numbers bouncing up and down on any individual
day. Not everyone has their podcast player open every day,
which means they are not always checking for new episodes.</p>

<p>Additionally, the advanced report will show you current trends
for episodes at a weekly and monthly level. You&rsquo;ll be able to
see which episodes are getting the most plays for these two
time periods.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_podcast_report.png"></p>

<p>At the episode level, you&rsquo;ll get teh same episode totals, but
you&rsquo;ll also see weekly and monthly counts for the episode.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/advanced_episode_report.png"></p>

<h2>Totals: A Breakdown By Listen Type</h2>

<p>One of the advantages that SignalLeaf&rsquo;s reports have over others,
is the breakdown of listens by type: RSS, Download and use of
the SignalLeaf player.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/listen_breakdown.png"></p>

<p>This gives you a more accurate picture of how people are finding
and listening to your podcast and episodes. Getting this breakdown
does require you to take advantage of all of SignalLeaf&rsquo;s
features, though. If you&rsquo;re hosting your own RSS feed and
providing your own media player for blog posts through
PowerPress, for example, you won&rsquo;t be able to get this kind
of breakdown. SignalLeaf&rsquo;s RSS, player and direct download
links all contain a tag that tells me what type of listen
is being used. This allows me to capture all of the information
I need for this report, but it means you have to use the
RSS and media player provided by SignalLeaf to take advantage
of it.</p>

<h3>Why Would You Want To?</h3>

<p>A while back, Pat Flynn from
<a href="http://smartpassiveincome.com">Smart Passive Income</a> went through
<a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">a major redesign of the site</a>.
In the process of doing this, <strong>the first version of his
redesign caused a more than 50% drop in his listens!</strong></p>

<p><sub>(Image from <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat&rsquo;s blog post</a>)</sub>
<img src="http://cdn.smartpassiveincome.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/redesigndrop2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Clearly, this is not what he wanted. And clearly, it would have
been nice to prevent this. But Pat did the right thing, and
fixed the site design so that podcast episodes were easier to
find and play. He quickly reacted, fixed the problem and got
his plays back up to where they should be.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the important lesson, though: <strong>if Pat had been using
a report setup like SignalLeaf provides, he would have known
that his audience was largely finding and listening to episodes
through his website, before going through this redesign!</strong>
Having this information could have helped him make better
decisions up front, instead of having to see this massive
drop in plays, after the first release of the website.</p>

<p>Now
that&rsquo;s not to say it would have prevent the drop. You make
decisions based on the information you have, and you adjust
from there. But having this information up front may have
helped. Knowing where the majority of your audience listens
to your episodes will help you to optimize that experience.
Knowing, not guessing or assuming, is important.</p>

<h2>Building Reports Based On Needs</h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the thing: <strong>I understand that these reports are not nearly
as &ldquo;complete&rdquo; as some other services out there.</strong> This is somewhat
intentional. Honestly, I have a lot more data availabe than what
I&rsquo;m currently showing. But <strong>throwing more data at you, just for the
sake of having more reports is not the answer.</strong></p>

<p>The reports that I have in place, and the breakdown of listens
are here because I saw the need for this based on customer
feedback. This is the key and critical part of the reports
that I&rsquo;m building &ndash; <strong>they are based on your neeeds, not just
tossing more information out there in the hopes that I get
soemthing right</strong> and provide some value.</p>

<p><strong>I want to know what reports you need.</strong> I want to know what
information you need to see, and why. I want to know that the
reports you are getting are serving you the way you need
them to serve you. And I want to build new and better reports
based on your needs that are not yet being met.</p>

<p>So drop a comment here. Send me <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">an email</a>.
Get in touch over <a href="http://twitter.com/signalleaf">twitter</a> or
<a href="https://plus.google.com/+DerickBailey/posts/HoCLiT4TJqH">Google+</a> and let me know:</p>

<blockquote><p>What reports do you want and need for your podcast?</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[4 Of The Worst Things To Do When Starting A Podcast]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/06/4-of-the-worst-things-to-do-when-starting-a-podcast/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-06T20:32:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/06/4-of-the-worst-things-to-do-when-starting-a-podcast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The web is full of great information on what you should be doing
when starting a podcast. There are hundreds, if not thousands,
of blog posts and web sites dedicated to helping you get up
and running &ndash; this one included. It doesn&rsquo;t take much more than
a google search or asking on twitter to find what you need to
know!</p>

<p>But this isn&rsquo;t another one of those feel-good, tell me what
I need posts. Rather, I want to mention a few of the things
that you should avoid doing when you&rsquo;re starting out. Understanding
what you should <em>not</em> do is just as important as understanding
what you <em>should</em> be doing &ndash; sometimes more important. These are
the things that will drive you to drink, if you&rsquo;re not careful.
These are the things that you should avoid doing, at all costs.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/stop_drinking.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>#4: Stop Waiting To Start</h2>

<p><strong>This is the first great mistake that people make when starting
a podcast.</strong> They wait. They wait some more. They push things
back, and they delay yet again.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easy to get sucked in to
the idea that you&rsquo;re not ready. It&rsquo;s easy to fall victim to
procrastination, and to make yourself look busy without making
any actual progress.</p>

<p>Unforunately, it&rsquo;s in our nature to procrastinate. Even the
most amazing podcasters, like <a href="http://eofire.com">John Lee Dumas</a>,
have fallen victim to the delays. In <a href="http://launchingcreative.com/episode-1/">his interview with the Launching Creative podcast</a>
[starting at 31:25], John talked about how he was delaying and delaying until his
mentor finally said that he would be dropped as a client if he
didn&rsquo;t release the first episode that day. In the end, John
realized that the delays he put on himself were only setting
him back, not helping him.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Get out there. Launch. Fail. Make mistakes. Improve.&rdquo; &ndash; John Lee Dumas</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>There is nothing that will demotivate
you faster than not getting your podcast published and live
for the world to hear.</strong> The sense of accomplishment and having
produced something is a tremendously motivating thing. You&rsquo;ll
find that once you start the work &ndash; once you start recording
and publishing episodes &ndash; you&rsquo;ll want to do more.</p>

<p>Getting started and getting your first episode published is
by far the most important thing you can do for your podcasting
career or hobby.</p>

<h2>#3: Don&rsquo;t Obsess Over Your Stats (Listeners And Subscribers)</h2>

<p>Unless you&rsquo;re already internet famous, you&rsquo;re not going to launch
to a massive audience. You won&rsquo;t have thousands of downloads,
instantly. Chances are, you&rsquo;re not even going to have hundreds
of downloads until you&rsquo;re at least a few episodes in to the
podcast.</p>

<p><strong>Stop. Watching. Your. Reports.</strong></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the deal, and the reason this is so important: podcasts
are an inconsistent stream of traffic per episode. You might see a
number that you like after the first week of your first episode.
You might even see a bump after the second week. But once you
release that second or third episode, the numbers won&rsquo;t be as high.
And the next episode? Even lower. <strong>THIS IS NORMAL!</strong></p>

<p>The average shelf life of a podcast episode is 6 weeks. <strong>6
weeks.</strong> This means your first episode will continue to accrue
traffic for around 6 weeks. You&rsquo;ll stil get traffic hitting it
after that, but it won&rsquo;t be as steady. During that 6 weeks of
life for your first episode, your other episodes won&rsquo;t have
as much traffic. You&rsquo;ll see a natural dip in the numbers
because those episodes haven&rsquo;t been around as long and won&rsquo;t
instantly catch up or shoot past your first one.</p>

<p><strong>It takes time for the numbers to settle in and level out.
Only after the shelf life of your first episode will you be able
to see that your audience is growing.</strong> And it&rsquo;s the slow, steady
growth of a continuing podcast, week after week, that you want to see.</p>

<h2>#2: Don&rsquo;t Wait For Listeners To Find You</h2>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;If you build it, they will come&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>the Field Of Dreams Fallacy
has cursed a generation of movie lovers in to thinking that
they will have instant fans and stardom.</strong> The idea is that
if you just build it and ship it, people will find it and love
you. <strong>This couldn&rsquo;t be further from the truth.</strong> But you
know what? That&rsquo;s ok.</p>

<p><strong>You&rsquo;re not doing this for instant
celebrity status</strong>, and the drug-rush of watching your stats
fly off the meter. And believe me &ndash; this is a habbit forming
drug. I suffer from this as much as anyone else I know. It&rsquo;s
the curse of the always-on, data-filled digital lives that
we live. We want to see every time someone hits our site, listens
to our podcast, or tells us something on twitter, facebook,
and every other site in the world.</p>

<p><strong>Get 10 episodes published, first</strong> &ndash; not just &ldquo;done&rdquo;, but
actually published. Talk about the episodes on twitter, facebook,
pinterest and everywhere else. Blog about the episodes &ndash; <strong>every
episode gets a blog post</strong>, in fact. Find places with people
that would benefit from your podcast and tell those
people about it. Do this for 10 episodes and then
start looking at your stats. You&rsquo;ll see growth, instead of flat
or falling numbers.</p>

<p>Once you see growth, you know you&rsquo;ve started to show up on
people&rsquo;s radar. <strong>Listeners will start to find you. But that
doesn&rsquo;t mean your done.</strong> The reason people are starting to find
you now is because you did the leg work of putting yourself
in front of them. <strong>Don&rsquo;t stop doing the leg work. Keep it up.
Your audience will grow.</strong></p>

<h2>#1: Don&rsquo;t Stop!</h2>

<p>This, above all other things, is the biggest mistake that new
podcasters make.</p>

<p><strong>The average podcast only makes it to episode 6 or 7 before it
stops.</strong> There are a lot of reasons for this, but in my
experience and in talking with others, it usually comes down to
time committment and what looks like a lack of growth in
audience. It just doesn&rsquo;t seem to be worth the effort, and
your day job is getting stressful again while the spouse and/or
kids are starting to wonder where you&rsquo;re at in the evenings&hellip;</p>

<p><strong>It&rsquo;s easy to get overhwelmed.</strong> And it&rsquo;s easy to think that
you need to have a regular and set schedule in order to be
a podcaster. After all, most of the podcasting industry tells
you this. <strong>Don&rsquo;t believe it for a minute.</strong> This is your
podcast; this is your story; your life; your work. You and only
you are in charge of how often you release an episode.</p>

<p>Just because you missed a week (or 7), or you only have time to
release one episode every month, doesn&rsquo;t mean you should
give up. Schedule the time for your podcast, like you would
do with anything else in your life. Set time aside, but
only time that you are comfortable with. <strong>Don&rsquo;t push yourself
to do more just because some podcasting &ldquo;professional&rdquo;
says you have to.</strong> You don&rsquo;t need to stop podcasting just
because you can&rsquo;t get this episode done and released &ldquo;on time&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>Most Importantly: Have Fun!</h2>

<p>Podcasting is the new media revolution for this decade. Much
like blogging was in the previous decade, there will be alot of
growth and change in the industry. Join the growing community
and let your voice be heard. Build intimate connections with
your audience and allow them to know you, on your terms. This is
an exciting new media opportunity on many fronts, and <strong>it should
be something you enjoy!</strong> It may be hard work &ndash; well, it <em>will</em>
be hard work at times &ndash; but <strong>nothing worth doing is easy</strong>.</p>

<h2>Want To Know More?</h2>

<p>Like what you read here? Want more info to help you get past your
hurdles and podcast like a pro? <strong>Sign up for the mailing list,
below</strong> and you&rsquo;ll receive the latest news, tips and articles!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Remove Background Noise With Audacity]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/31/how-to-remove-background-noise-with-audacity/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T09:50:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/31/how-to-remove-background-noise-with-audacity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Noise from ventilation systems, cars driving down the street,
keeping yourself warm with a heater or even the hum of
flourescent lighting &ndash; these are all sources of background
noise that can make or break your audio quality.</p>

<p>Having a
constant hum or buzz in the background can be very distracting
and cause people to turn away from your podcast. Fortunately,
the <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a> audio
editing app can help you get rid of the noise in a few&hellip;
not quite so straight forward steps. Not to worry, though &ndash;
while the 2 step process may be a little bit odd when you
first see it, it is not difficult to understand or accomplish.</p>

<p><a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net"><img src="/images/blog_posts/Audacity-logo.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Video</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve put together a short video to demonstrate how to use
Audacity to clean up your audio. It&rsquo;s 7 minutes of step by
step instructions, including a demonstration of the original
audio and the cleaned up audio. Check it out on
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sT-Yk9zHKf4">my Youtube channel</a>,
or watch it here, embedded in this blog post.</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/sT-Yk9zHKf4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h2>The Audio</h2>

<p>In addition to the video on how to use Audacity to clean up
your audio, I&rsquo;ve also got two podcast episodes to demonstrate
the difference.</p>

<h4>The Original</h4>

<p>In this original source file, you will hear a constant hum
in the background, from a ventilation intake right outside of
my office. You may have to turn up the volume a bit to hear
it, but it is unmistakably there.</p>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves-Special-Editions/52ebcc6c4d17c40200000010/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h4>The Cleaned Up</h4>

<p>Now in this second version of the same audio file, I&rsquo;ve used
Audacity to clean up the background noise. The effect is
dramatic &ndash; the noise is gone during the quiet periods of the
episode. But, it is not perfect. If you have high quality
headphones, you will be able to hear a little bit of
distortion or noise in the low-end frequencies while I am
speaking. You may not hear it if your headset is not of
high enough quality, or if there is too much noise where you
are listening, but it is there.</p>

<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves-Special-Editions/52ebccbd4d17c40200000012/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h4>Additional Cleanup?</h4>

<p>Note that it is possible to do additional cleanup of the
remaining low frequency noise during my speaking. I left this
as-is, though, to demonstrate some of the limitations of what
the noise removal tool are. I may, at some other point, show
how to do additional processing to clean this up a bit more,
but that will be another post for another time.</p>

<h2>Professional Audio Cleanup</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s fairly simple to add at least a modest amount of audio
clean to your process, as you&rsquo;ve seen here. However, there
are some limitations to what Audacity can do, and it does take
a lot of practice and experience to really get things perfect.
You may find yourself in a situation where you don&rsquo;t have time
to learn all the tricks, or you need some additional expertise
in cleaning up and doing post-production audio work. If that&rsquo;s
the case, you might want to look in to an audio production
service such as <a href="http://www.podcastfasttrack.com/">PodcastFastTrac</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.podcastfasttrack.com/"><img src="/images/blog_posts/podcastfasttrack.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>PodcastFastTrack is a service that can handle all of your
podcast production needs, including editing, splicing in music
and intros, audio clean up and more. <strong>The combination of
post-production work from PodcastFastTrack, plus hosting
services from <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a></strong> may be
just what you need to keep yourself production and focused on
your podcast, instead of having to worry about the technical
and production side of thigs.</p>

<h2>Want To Know More?</h2>

<p><strong>Be sure to subscribe to my mailing list</strong>, below, if you&rsquo;d like
to get more tips, hear interviews from other podcasters, and
keep up to date with the podcasting industry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Other Podcasters' Resources]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-11T09:18:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have <a href="/equipment">my own equipment list</a>, my <a href="/how-to-podcast">how to get started</a>
and more info on this blog. It&rsquo;s the place where I&rsquo;m putting toghether info
from my experiences and experiments, to try and help people that are new
to podcasting get up and running quickly. But there&rsquo;s also a ton of other
resources out there, from other podcasters. I&rsquo;ve oftend looked at these
blog posts and page for equipment ideas, how-to info, and more. And I wanted
to share some of these so that you could also benefit from the knowledge
and experience that I&rsquo;ve been able to benefit from.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Scott Hanselman</h2>

<p><a href="http://hanselman.com">Scott Hanselman</a> is a well known software developer and technologist, and is
a host of several podcasts that I know and love, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">Hanselminutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com/">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratchetandthegeek.com/">Ratchet &amp; the Geek</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you&rsquo;re in to technology and/or software development, you should check out the
podcasts that Scott hosts. They&rsquo;re great.</p>

<p>He also has a great blog posts about the equipment, software, process and
services that he uses for his podcats, titled:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/HowToStartYourFirstPodcastEquipmentEditingPublishingAndMore.aspx">How to start your first podcast &ndash; equipment, editing, publishing and more</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The title says it all, really &ndash; if you want to know what Scott uses and how he
works, check out this post. It is full of equipment recommendations, quick tips
and ideas that will help you get things up and running pretty quickly.</p>

<h2>Cliff Ravenscraft</h2>

<p>Cliff Ravenscraft is known as the <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/">Podcast Answerman</a>
for a good reason. His podcast, podcast tutorials, courses and other information
have become one of the defacto-standards in the podcasting industry. If you&rsquo;re
not familiar with Cliffs work, you need to check it out. He has a great list of
equipment, videos, tips and other resources all over his site, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/equipment/">Equipment</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/resources/">Resources</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/atoz/">Podcasting, A to Z</a> (paid course)</li>
</ul>


<p>And be sure to check out <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/category/podcastanswerman/">Cliff&rsquo;s podcast</a>
which is a wealth of knowledge and information on all things podcasting.</p>

<h2>Pat Flynn</h2>

<p>Pat Flynn&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Smart Passive Income</a> podcast,
blog and other resources are a place that I like to go when I&rsquo;m looking for
information on running and growing a small business. His podcast episodes and
blog posts have provided a lot of inspriation for me and ideas for figuring out
what I&rsquo;m doing with SignalLeaf, and more.</p>

<p>In addition to his podcast on small business, Pat has a great <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/resources/">resources</a>
 page that lists not only info about podcasting, but about small business and
services that he uses and recommends for online business and blogging.</p>

<p>For his recommendations and tutorials on how to get started in podcasting,
checkout his page:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/how-to-start-a-podcast-podcasting-tutorial/">How to Start a Podcast – Pat’s Complete Step-By-Step Podcasting Tutorial</a></p></blockquote>

<p>This page covers podcasting with a series of videos and other links to podcasting
resources, including Pat&rsquo;s podcast equipment list in video #1.</p>

<h2>Ray Ortega</h2>

<p>Ray Ortega runs <a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/">The Podcasters' Studio</a>
as well as <a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">The Podcasters' Roundtable</a>.
If you&rsquo;re a podcaster, or want to become one, you should be looking at what
Ray is producing.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s Podcasters' Roundtable is a great format where he gets multiple podcasters
together on Google+ to discuss thoughts on specific podcasting topics, often
leading to debates and disagreements &ndash; though always professional and
courteous. If you&rsquo;d like to hear a wide range of opinions and debates on
podcasting topics, you should check out the Podcasters' Roundtable.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s other podcast, The Podcasters' Studio, focuses on all things podcasting.
He shares his experience and knowlege so, and offers tips on how to get your
podcast to the next level. This is one podcast you don&rsquo;t want to miss, when
you have yours up and running and you want to know what the pros are doing
to keep things running smoothly.</p>

<p>Check out Ray&rsquo;s recommended gear and his podcasts, here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://rayortega.com/gear/">Recommended Gear</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/thepodcastersstudio/">The Podcasters' Studio</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/podcastquicktips/">Podcast Quick Tips</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">Podcasters' Roundtable</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>What Resources Do You Pay Attention To?</h2>

<p>I know there are a ton of other great resources out there &ndash; including some that
I&rsquo;ve looked at but am not listing here. I&rsquo;d love to hear what your favorite
reosources are. <strong>Drop a comment below and link back to your site&rsquo;s equipment
list, your podcast tips, and your favorite resources from your favorite
podcasters!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
