<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: podcast | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/podcast/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-31T11:26:56-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[MP3 Bit Rates, File Size, And Audio Quality]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-18T07:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/18/mp3-bit-rates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In <a href="/blog/2013/12/10/audio-vs-file-compression/">a previous blog post</a>
I talked about the need for both file and audio compression
on your podcasts. At the end of that post, I linked out to
<a href="https://gist.github.com/scottburton11/3222152">an article from Scott Burton on audio compression</a>,
but did not have any information on MP3 file compression at
the time.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/c-clamp-mp3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Well, I have all the MP3 file compression information, along with
bit rates and my own judgement on audio quality vs file size now.
And you might be surprised at the results! I know I was!</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Episode Content And Bit Rates</h2>

<p>I recorded a 32 minute podcast episode that contains 2 things:</p>

<ol>
<li>A musical introduction</li>
<li>A lengty spoken track</li>
</ol>


<p>The musical introduction takes not quite a minute, with the
spoken audio taking up the rest of the 32 minutes. The spoken
audio is not a complete episode, however. It is only a 1+
minute description of the episode&rsquo;s purpose, repeated over
and over and over again to get a podcast episode of
approximately average length. In other words, <strong>don&rsquo;t bother
listening past the first minute and a half</strong>. It just repeats
for a long time to make the point of file size vs content
length.</p>

<p>After recording the episode, I exported it under 10
separate bit rate settings, using <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Aadacity</a>.
With all of these bit rate exports, I create a special
podcast on SignalLeaf just for these episodes. You can
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/52b10a635b56000200000011/rss">subscribe to the podcast RSS feed</a>
and listen to each of the episodes in iTunes and other
podcast players, or you can use the embedded players here.</p>

<h2>Constant Bit Rate Versions</h2>

<p>These episodes were exported at a constant bit rate &ndash; a rate that stays the same
throughout the entire encoding, regardless of the amount of data that there is to
encode.</p>

<h4>16K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10ade4cacd40200000050/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 16K Constant bit rate with 20K sampling (max supported by 16K file bit rate). The effect is quite horrible. Everything sounds muffled, warbly, and like its in a tin can with ear muffs. The file is quite small, at 3.9Megs, though.</p>

<h4>32K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10cf04cacd40200000051/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 32K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. The effect is still pretty bad. Everything sounds warbly and slightly muffled, though not as bad as the 16K file. The highs are especially off, and a lot of the stereo effect in the opening music is gone. The file is still pretty small, at 7.7Megs.</p>

<h4>64K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10d824cacd40200000053/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 64K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. The quality drop in this file is negligible. There are some points in the opening music where some slight warbles can be heard on the high end sounds. Additional guitar sounds and other instruments tend to have a more pronounced warbled sound at this bit rate. The file size is still quite reasonable and may be considered &ldquo;small&rdquo; by some standards, at 15.5Megs.</p>

<h4>128K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b10e6e5b56000200000017/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 128K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. The net effect of this bit rate is no noticeable degradation in audio quality, throughout the podcast episode. If additional instrumentation were present, there would be little to no loss of audio quality. The quality comes at a trade off in file size, though, with the file being 31Megs in size. This size is hardly acceptable for a podcast that is only 32 minutes in length.</p>

<h4>256K Constant</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b110185b56000200000018/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Episode exported at 256K Constant bit rate with 44.1K sampling. At 62 megs, this file size is completely unacceptable for distributing a podcast of only 32 minutes in length. The sound quality, however, is near impeccable. There is little chance that anyone would be able to pick up any distortions in the quality of audio.</p>

<h2>Variable Bit Rate Versions</h2>

<p>Variable bit rate encoding allows the bit rate to change based on the amount of information
that needs to be encoded. If there is less audio signal to encode, the bit rate goes down.
If there is more, it goes up. This can reduce the file size while still maintaining quality,
in many cases.</p>

<h4>48K &ndash; 85K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b111a44cacd40200000059/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 48K-85K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is very little distortion in this file, even in the musical introduction. A direct comparison of the 64K Constant bit rate yields a slight increase in audio quality over that export. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 15.5Megs down to 13Megs. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is quite nice.</p>

<h4>80K &ndash; 120K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b115e44cacd4020000005a/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 80K-120K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is little to no perceivable distortion in this audio even in the musical introduction. A larger assortment of musical instruments comprising a full band or orchestra may exhibit some minor issues, but not enough to cause serious displeasure. A direct comparison of the 128K Constant bit rate yields approximately the same audio quality, though it is technically slightly less. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 31Megs down to 18.4Megs for a mostly spoken audio file. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is quite nice.</p>

<h4>145K &ndash; 185K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b117d94cacd4020000005c/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 145K-185K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is little to no perceivable distortion in this audio even in the musical introduction. A larger assortment of musical instruments comprising a full band or orchestra may exhibit some minor issues, but not enough to cause serious displeasure. A direct comparison of the 128K Constant bit rate yields a technically higher quality audio file, but with little perceivable difference (if any). The file size, in comparison, dropped from 31Megs down to 26Megs for a mostly spoken audio file. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is acceptable for music based podcasts, but may be slightly larger than desired for spoken podcasts.</p>

<h4>170K &ndash; 210K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b119354cacd4020000005e/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 170K-210K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. There is little to no perceivable distortion in this audio even in the musical introduction. A larger assortment of musical instruments comprising a full band or orchestra should not exhibit any noticeable distortion, except in extreme cases. A direct comparison of the 128K Constant bit rate yields a higher quality that is imperceptibly improved with a spoken podcast. A full orchestra or other large arrangement of instruments may show some perceived improvements. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 31Megs down to 30.4Megs for a mostly spoken audio file &ndash; a negligible difference, at best. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate may be acceptable for music based podcasts, but is too large for spoken podcasts.</p>

<h4>220K &ndash; 260K Variable</h4>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/52b10a635b56000200000011/52b11a315b56000200000022/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Exported at 220K-260K Variable bit rate with 44.1K sampling. Good luck finding any perceivable audio quality problems with this one. A direct comparison of the 256K Constant bit rate yields approximately the same audio quality, though it is technically slightly less. The file size, in comparison, dropped from 62Megs down to 39.2Megs for a mostly spoken audio file &ndash; a significant reduction. The audio quality vs file size at this bit rate is not acceptable for streaming. The file is simply too large for the amount of content contained within it.</p>

<h2>The (Somewhat Surprising) Results</h2>

<p>As you would expect, the low-end results of the 16K bit rate
are attrocious. If it wasn&rsquo;t for the ridiculously small
file size, this would never even be an option. In fact, I&rsquo;m
going to call it not an option anyways, in spite of the file
size. The audio quality is simply horrible. I wouldn&rsquo;t inflict
that on anyone.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve always known that a variable bit rate .mp3 file was going
to be smaller, but I had never directly compared the file size
and audio quality with a constant/variable counterpart before.
The ability to keep roughly the same file size while increasing
the over-all quality was a nice effect when comparing 64K Constant
to 80-120K Variable, for example. The Variable is slightly
larger, but with the increase of quality and negligible file size
gain, this was a huge win for variable bit rates!</p>

<p>The other surprising result is how little difference there is,
if there is any perceivable difference, between 128K and
anything above it. At least with spoken podcasts I don&rsquo;t see
any need to ever use anything above 128K Constant rate, or
the near equivalent quality of 80K-120K Variable rate.</p>

<h2>Revised Recommendation: 96K or 128K Constant Bit Rate</h2>

<p>I had originally written this post to recommend 80K-120K
Variable Bit rate, based on the audio quality and file size.
But I need to revise that based on some conversation with
<a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/">Ray Ortega</a> and Rob Walch
(from <a href="http://libsyn.com">LibSyn</a>) over on <a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/+DerickBailey/posts/AWQvwWf5c4n">my Google+ post</a>.</p>

<p>Rob points out several problems with audio players as recent
as IOS6, and links to several posts where problems and solutions
are discussed.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://forum.audacityteam.org/viewtopic.php?f=16&amp;t=4249">MP3 Export, CBR=Good VBR=Bad Length</a> (from the Audacity forums)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.schillmania.com/projects/soundmanager2/doc/technotes/">SoundManager 2: Technical Nodes</a></li>
</ul>


<p>In the SoundManager 2 note, specifically, Rob points out the
following for the SoundManager 2, HTML5 player.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;MP3 Format Caveats</p>

<p>Additionally, some very low and very high bitrate MP3s, and Variable Bitrate (VBR) MP3s may play either too quickly or too slowly (see &ldquo;the chipmunk problem&rdquo;); if you are encountering this issue, try re-encoding at a different bitrate (between 64 kbps and 192 kbps, for example.) Using Constant Bitrate (CBR) encoding may also alleviate this problem."</p></blockquote>

<p>Given that, I&rsquo;m going to revise my recommendation:</p>

<p><strong>Use 128K or 96K Constant Bit Rate</strong> unless you have a good
reason not to.</p>

<h4>On Variable Bit Rates</h4>

<p>Even after revising my recommendation, I&rsquo;m going to leave
this note here, as to what my original recommendation was. At
the very least, it will let you the reader see where I was
coming from originally vs now.</p>

<blockquote><p>If I were going to recommend one signal bit rate to encode
your podcast .mp3 files, it would be 80K-120K Variable bit
rate. The audio quality vs file size is superb, with little
to not distortion or wobbles in a mostly spoken podcast.</p>

<p>If you press me hard enough, I&rsquo;ll admit that I want the
145K-185K Variable rate for music based podcasts. The additional
layers of sound found in music can present some warbles
and distortion on the high end frequencies at lower rates.
Honestly it&rsquo;s probably not going to bother anyong at the
80K &ndash; 120K rate, but I prefer to be safe when it comes to
my music encoding.</p></blockquote>

<p>And even at this, there are podcasters out there who have
switched over to variable bit rates with no issues.
<a href="https://twitter.com/jongalloway">John Galloway</a>
for example, has been serving more than 9,000 listeners of
his podcast in variable bit rate for over a year.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> Thanks. I was using CBR until last year for that reason, but switched to VBR and didn&#39;t get one complaint. Roughly 9k listeners.</p>&mdash; Jon Galloway (@jongalloway) <a href="https://twitter.com/jongalloway/statuses/414159229755219968">December 20, 2013</a></blockquote>


<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> I think the turnover rate in MP3 players - esp with phones - is high enough that it&#39;s no longer an issue.</p>&mdash; Jon Galloway (@jongalloway) <a href="https://twitter.com/jongalloway/statuses/414159430633021440">December 20, 2013</a></blockquote>




<script async src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<h2>One Size Does Not Fit All</h2>

<p>Clearly there is some dispute over the constant bit rate
vs variable bit rate. I&rsquo;m inclined to lean toward what
Rob Walch from LibSyn is saying at this point. But I&rsquo;m also
a technologist that understands the curve of old technology
falling off the market and being replaced by newer standards.
In the end, you should compress your audio files according to
your podcast needs, weighing file size vs audio quality and
available bandwidth. Whether this means constant or variable
bit rates is up to you.</p>

<p>Happy podcasting, all you Signalers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 3: Tips On Podcasting With Podcaster, John Sonmez]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-07T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/07/episode-3-tips-on-podcasting-with-podcaster-john-sonmez</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this episode, I have the pleasure of interview my friend
and fellow podcaster, John Sonmez from <a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a>.
We talk about his podcast at <a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetupAndCode.com</a>
&ndash; a podcast that combines fitness and programming &ndash; and dig in
to his lessons learned, success and failures in podcasting. It&rsquo;s
a great episode full of useful tips for those that are just
starting as well as those that have already started to get on
a roll with a podcast.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52a2b2fd9903dd0200000021/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Podcast Pro-Tip</h2>

<p>Use the &ldquo;clap trick&rdquo; to sync separate tracks recorded from
different computers. One person counts to 3, and on 3, everyone
in the podcast claps. Then you can sync the separate audio
tracks to the clap at the beginning.</p>

<p><strong>Listen to the first minute of the episode for a demonstration
of this technique!</strong></p>

<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>Niche-down to find your target audience &ndash; don&rsquo;t try to be
everything to everyone.</p>

<p><strong>Coordination with cohost requires planning and commitment</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>have a backup episode in case you can&rsquo;t make it for some reason</li>
<li>decide on a release cadence that you can handle, and stick with it no matter what</li>
</ul>


<p>Don&rsquo;t wait for perfect. Get something done and released</p>

<p><strong>Nerves are expected when you start</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s new</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s different</li>
<li>that&rsquo;s ok</li>
<li>you will improve over time</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Mistakes happen &ndash; move on</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>it&rsquo;s a conversation between you and the host / guest</li>
<li>keep the content focused and relevant</li>
<li>just relax and have fun</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>You know something others don&rsquo;t</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>if it&rsquo;s just your experience and perspective</li>
<li>your perspective is valuable</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Being new gives you a very valuable perspective</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>share your fears and mistakes with others</li>
<li>build the audience of people that are also new</li>
<li>help others learn with you</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>John&rsquo;s 3 lessons for someone just starting:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Streamlining: get all the infrastructure prep work (logo, domain name, blog, etc) done before you start recording. Start out professionally, with intro music, logo, etc (checkout fiverr.com for stuff like this)</li>
<li>Understand the process before you start. Practice by recording yourself and working through the process before you produce a real podcast. iTunes will not host your episodes (see blog.signalleaf.com for info on this)</li>
<li>Set up process, with consistency, ahead of time. Don&rsquo;t be left hanging after you record your first episode. You need to be consistent in order to grow a returning audience.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Have Your Own Tips To Share?</h2>

<p>If you have a podcast, then yes, you have lessons learned and info to
share with a growing audience. I want to interview you on
the Signals And Leaves podcast!</p>

<p><strong>So, <a href="http://signalleaf.com/help/contact">get in touch</a>
and let me know you want to be on the show!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 2: Mic Positioning And Room Are More Important]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-20T08:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/20/episode-2-the-mic-positioning-and-room-is-more-important</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Do you think the quality of the microphone is going to make
or break your podcast? If you do, I&rsquo;d like to show you that
it won&rsquo;t. And if you already don&rsquo;t, then why are you still
obsessed with getting &ldquo;the right mic&rdquo;? Is it just another
excuse to not start that podcast?</p>

<p>In Episode 2 of the Signals And Leaves podcast, I&rsquo;ll show you
how the room your in, and the positioning of the mic, will
have far more impact on the quality of the recording that
you are getting.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/528d042ea88e1f020000000f/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Show Notes</h2>

<p>As you can hear in this episode, having a quality mic does
make a difference in the audio recording. But that is not
the most important thing when you&rsquo;re starting your podcast. You
would be better served to find the right room in which to
record, than to go out and spend money on a top quality mic.</p>

<p>Now that doesn&rsquo;t mean a quality mic doesn&rsquo;t make a difference.
You will hear the difference in this episode. But you&rsquo;ll also
hear the difference between an office, an ultra-echoy bathroom,
and a closet with near-perfect sound.</p>

<p>Having a good position for your microphone is also of importance,
and can make a huge difference even if you have a quality
mic to start with. At the end of the episode, I&rsquo;ll give you
several examples of good and bad mic positioning.</p>

<h4>Show Highlights</h4>

<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t worry about the quality of mic</li>
<li>Worry about the room you&rsquo;re recording in</li>
<li>Worry about the microphone positioning</li>
<li>Wait until you have a few episodes under your belt before buying a quality mic</li>
</ul>


<p>When you are ready to buy, I highly recommend
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000JM46FY/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000JM46FY&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Rode Podcaster</a>.
This is the mic I use, and I love it. This is the industry
standard for podcasting and screencasting. You can&rsquo;t go wrong
with the Rode Podcaster.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B000JM46FY" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>If you need high quality for a little less money, though,
<a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B002VA464S/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B002VA464S&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">the Blue Yeti</a>
is also a great podcast microphone. I know a lot of people that
use this one, and it&rsquo;s a great mic.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B002VA464S" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h2>Subscribe And Share This Episode!</h2>

<p>If you like this episode, be sure to subscribe to
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the Signals And Leaves RSS feed</a>,
or <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/signals-and-leaves/id739095095">subscribe in iTunes</a>.</p>

<p>And while you&rsquo;re at it, submit this episode to
<a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/submit">Hacker News</a>
and the <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/podcasts/">/r/podcasts sub-Reddit</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome! And Episode 1 Of Signals And Leaves]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-14T20:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/14/welcome-and-episode-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the new <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> blog!
Consider this the obligatory &ldquo;hello world!&rdquo; blog post for the
new blog: Signals And Leaves. Read on for a little bit of info
on what SignalLeaf is, what it provides, and what I&rsquo;ll be doing
with the Signals And Leaves podcast and blog!</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>About SignalLeaf</h2>

<p><a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> is a small, but growing podcast audio hosting service.
Other podcast hosts want to up-sell you on features like
content management, advertising inserts, specialized podcasting
apps, and other bits that you won&rsquo;t need. SignalLeaf is different
in that I focus solely on four critical features that you need
for your podcast:</p>

<ol>
<li>.mp3 file hosting</li>
<li>RSS feed generation for podcast subscribers</li>
<li>Bandwidth for streaming episodes to your listeners</li>
<li>Traffic and analysis reports</li>
</ol>


<p>This pin-point focus on the services that SignalLeaf offers means
you are free to build a website that fits your needs, without
worrying about whether or not your podcast will fit in to it.
You can use any platform and any tools to build your site, and
embed podcast episodes from SignalLeaf, with ease!</p>

<p>Already have a blog or a site? Setting up a blog with
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-wordpress">WordPress</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-with-tumblr">Tumblr</a>?
Building a site on your own, using the
tools and skills that you already posess will not stop you from
adding a podcast. Just grab
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-the-signalleaf-media-player">the emded code</a>
or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/use-your-own-media-player">host the episode in your own media player</a>
on your site!</p>

<p>When you&rsquo;re ready to get started with the easiest way to host your
podcast audio and RSS feed, head over to <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf.com</a>
and sign up for you free trial!</p>

<h2>About The Blog</h2>

<p>Signals And Leaves is a blog about podcasting, building and running
a podcasting service, and everything that entails. You&rsquo;ll hear tips
and tricks for podcasting. You&rsquo;ll find podcast episodes that SignalLeaf
hosts and produces. You&rsquo;ll get pointers to the right equipment, and
see a lot of other bits about hosting, producing and making the most of
a podcast.</p>

<p>Subscribe to <a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/atom.xml" title="">the blog RSS feed</a>
to keep up to date with the latest and greatest in podcast audio hosting,
tips and tricks, and other information to keep you on the forefront
of podcasting!</p>

<h2>About The Podcast</h2>

<p>In addition to this being a blog, I&rsquo;m also running a podcast by the
same name: Signals And Leaves. I&rsquo;ve only recorded one episode so far,
but will be recording and publishing additional episodes, soon.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.signalleaf.com/embed/523736d466f52c0200000003/52374abd66f52c0200000005/" width="400" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>Be sure to subscribe to the podcast through <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">the RSS feed</a>
directly, or <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/podcasts/523736d466f52c0200000003/rss">subscribe through iTunes</a>
to hear the latest on what&rsquo;s happening with SignalLeaf.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
