<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ebook | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/ebook/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-31T10:20:45-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare, Produce, Publish: Stop Waiting And Start Podcasting!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/17/announcing-the-prepare-produce-publish-ebook/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-17T13:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/17/announcing-the-prepare-produce-publish-ebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You want to start a podcast. You&rsquo;ve got something to say,
and you know that people want to hear it. So what are you
waiting for? <strong>Stop wasting your time, waiting for the right mic or the
right co-host!</strong></p>

<p>With nothing more than a laptop and an
internet connection, you can join the new media revolution and publish
your voice, your thoughts and your opinions to the world!</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/how-to-podcast" target="_blank" class="center"><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/prepare-produce-publish-cover.png"></a></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Publish Your First Podcast, TODAY</h2>

<p>Today. I mean, today! With my e-book,
&ldquo;<a href="https://leanpub.com/prepare-produce-publish/packages/book/purchases/new">Prepare, Produce, Publish: Your First Podcast In 3 Easy Steps!</a>&rdquo;,
you will be up and running and have your first episode
published in no time at all!</p>

<p>This book is all about getting you started in the world of
podcasting &ndash; from the equipment that you need (<em>and don&rsquo;t need!</em>)
to using Audacity for recording your first episode, and how
to publish your podcast through a hosting service, this book
covers it all for for the new podcaster.</p>

<h2>GET IT FREE! WITH FREE UPDATES!</h2>

<p>This e-book, which would cost $10 if you decide to buy it,
can be yours for free by <a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/mailing-list">signing up for the SignalLeaf mailing list</a>!</p>

<p>In addition to this informational and step-by-step guide
to publishing your first podcast, you&rsquo;ll get updates and
news from the podcasting world. From blog posts, to tips
and tricks, from podcasters and professionals to those that
are just starting out, you&rsquo;ll hear all the latest news
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/mailing-list">right here</a>.</p>

<h2>A Work In Progress</h2>

<p>This ebook is currently a work in progress. That means it is
not yet complete, but it still provides a ton of value as-is.
That also means that <strong>you, dear podcaster, get to purchase the
book at a discounted price!</strong> Better hurry, though&hellip; this
discount won&rsquo;t last forever! Once I&rsquo;ve got the book completed,
the price will jump!</p>

<p>In addition to getting it cheaper, you will also get all of
the updates, free! As soon as I publish an update to the book
you will have it available in your downloads, guaranteed. That
means you&rsquo;ll get all of the step by step instructions, tips
and tricks to publish your podcast as I write them!</p>

<h2>Get Your Podcast Published</h2>

<p>I know you&rsquo;ve been thinking about starting a podcast, so
<a href="http://www.signalleaf.com/help/mailing-list">join the SignalLeaf mailing list</a>
and get the guide to publishing
your podcast, FREE!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
