<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SEO | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/seo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-26T14:32:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[50 Reasons Why You Need To Blog Every Podcast Episode]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/26/50-reasons-why-you-need-to-blog-every-podcast-episode/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-26T13:44:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/02/26/50-reasons-why-you-need-to-blog-every-podcast-episode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blogging is soooo last decade, right? It&rsquo;s the old, new media
revolution. Everyone built a blog and wrote about what they had
for breakfast. And didn&rsquo;t blogging get replaced by social media
sites dedicated to your favorite food pics?</p>

<p>Truth is, blogging is more important than ever. If you&rsquo;re
trying to build an audience of any kind, you need a blog. Of
course you might not want to fill your blog will your instamatic
style, vintage food photos &ndash; unless your blog is focused on
that. Your blog should be focused and reflect the content that
the audience want, wants to read. And yes, your audience of
podcast listeners also need you to have a blog.</p>

<p>If aren&rsquo;t already doing this, you need to start blogging
every episode of your podcast. And I&rsquo;ve got 50 reasons why
you need to start, today.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/signals-and-leaves-blog.png" alt="" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Reason #1: Summary, Show Notes And Transcript</h2>

<p>The most important thing to do with each podcast episode is
blog an episode player, show summary and show notes at a minimum.</p>

<p>The summary is usually just a paragraph or two that explains what the episode is about.
You&rsquo;ll want to include an introduction for your guest, the
range of topics covered, and any interesting bits of information
that the episode contains. You can get in to as much detail
as you want, but remember that this is supposed to be a summary.
People will read this to get an idea of whether or not they
want to listen to the episode.</p>

<p>Beyond a summary, show notes are a great idea. This will be
more detailed items from the discussions and points in the
show. The major difference here, is that the notes don&rsquo;t need
to be standard prose. They can be bullet points, links, or
anything else that makes sense. Think of this as taking notes
in a meeting or class &ndash; you don&rsquo;t write down everything, only
the important points that will remind you what to look at
later.</p>

<p>Lastly, a transcript of the episode can go a long way if you
have the time do it or the money to outsource having this
done. Having a transcript with your show notes and links will
provide an alternative way for your audience to get the
information they need. It also lets people copy &amp; paste
quotable things, instead of having to transcribe for
themselves.</p>

<h2>Reason #2: Search Engine Optimization (SEO)</h2>

<p>The more information you pack in to your summary, show notes
and transcript, the better you will rank in search engine
traffic. Google and other search engines need content to
index. Content for podcast episodes comes from the show
notes, links and transcripts.</p>

<p>If you have at least a section for a summary and notes /
links, then search engines will have something more valuable
by which you can be found. You&rsquo;ll start ranking higher in
search results, concerning the subject matter of your podcast.
Higher search engine traffic means building a larger audience.
Building a larger audience means getting better sponsors
(if that&rsquo;s your thing) and having more influence and credibility.</p>

<h2>Reason #50: 50% Of Your Audience Will Listed via The Blog Post</h2>

<p>Ok, I lied. This is actually the #1 reason that you should
blog every episode. While #1 and #2 listed above are great
reasons, they ultimately lead to this one very important
statistic:</p>

<p><strong>50% of your audience will listen via your blog</strong></p>

<p>I first heard about this via <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat Flynn&rsquo;s blog post on
redesigning his website</a>.
In that post, he talks about how the first version of
the site redesign dropped his podcast listening traffic
by 50%!</p>

<p><sub>(Image from <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/spi-theme-design/">Pat&rsquo;s blog post</a>)</sub>
<img src="http://cdn.smartpassiveincome.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/redesigndrop2.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Following up on that thought, I dug in to the podcasts that
I&rsquo;m hosting on <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> and
confirmed this statistic in a majority of cases.</p>

<p>My own Signals And Leaves podcast, for example, shows a 51%
bias for listening to episodes via my blog posts.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/signals-and-leaves-51percent-embed.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>After seeing that confirmed on my podcast, I dug in to a few
others and saw the trend.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-52percent-embed.png" alt="" />
<img src="/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-56percent-embed.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Of course, not every podcast shows this trend. One in particular
doesn&rsquo;t use the embedded player that I provide. Instead,
they post to Facebook and want people to listen via RSS. They&rsquo;ve
experimented with an embedded player a few times, but
haven&rsquo;t used it much.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/podcast-report-65percent-rss.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>But with a majority of the podcasts that I analyzed having
50% + of their plays coming through their website, it&rsquo;s
rather plain to see that a blog post per episode is absolutely
critical for your audience.</p>

<h2>How Do I Get Embed vs RSS Reports?</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re interested in getting the same level of reporting
that I&rsquo;ve shown here &ndash; the ability to know what percentage
of podcasts are coming from your blog posts, direct downloads
or through your RSS feed &ndash; you&rsquo;re in luck! <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a>
provides these reports for you, when you take advantage of
the SignalLeaf generated RSS feed and the SignalLeaf Player
for your blog posts.</p>

<p><strong> <a href="https://www.signalleaf.com/#plans">Sign up for SignalLeaf today</a>, and start seeing where your episode plays
are happening.</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
