<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: microphone | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/microphone/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-06T21:53:27-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Other Podcasters' Resources]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-11T09:18:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have <a href="/equipment">my own equipment list</a>, my <a href="/how-to-podcast">how to get started</a>
and more info on this blog. It&rsquo;s the place where I&rsquo;m putting toghether info
from my experiences and experiments, to try and help people that are new
to podcasting get up and running quickly. But there&rsquo;s also a ton of other
resources out there, from other podcasters. I&rsquo;ve oftend looked at these
blog posts and page for equipment ideas, how-to info, and more. And I wanted
to share some of these so that you could also benefit from the knowledge
and experience that I&rsquo;ve been able to benefit from.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Scott Hanselman</h2>

<p><a href="http://hanselman.com">Scott Hanselman</a> is a well known software developer and technologist, and is
a host of several podcasts that I know and love, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">Hanselminutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com/">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratchetandthegeek.com/">Ratchet &amp; the Geek</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you&rsquo;re in to technology and/or software development, you should check out the
podcasts that Scott hosts. They&rsquo;re great.</p>

<p>He also has a great blog posts about the equipment, software, process and
services that he uses for his podcats, titled:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/HowToStartYourFirstPodcastEquipmentEditingPublishingAndMore.aspx">How to start your first podcast &ndash; equipment, editing, publishing and more</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The title says it all, really &ndash; if you want to know what Scott uses and how he
works, check out this post. It is full of equipment recommendations, quick tips
and ideas that will help you get things up and running pretty quickly.</p>

<h2>Cliff Ravenscraft</h2>

<p>Cliff Ravenscraft is known as the <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/">Podcast Answerman</a>
for a good reason. His podcast, podcast tutorials, courses and other information
have become one of the defacto-standards in the podcasting industry. If you&rsquo;re
not familiar with Cliffs work, you need to check it out. He has a great list of
equipment, videos, tips and other resources all over his site, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/equipment/">Equipment</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/resources/">Resources</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/atoz/">Podcasting, A to Z</a> (paid course)</li>
</ul>


<p>And be sure to check out <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/category/podcastanswerman/">Cliff&rsquo;s podcast</a>
which is a wealth of knowledge and information on all things podcasting.</p>

<h2>Pat Flynn</h2>

<p>Pat Flynn&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Smart Passive Income</a> podcast,
blog and other resources are a place that I like to go when I&rsquo;m looking for
information on running and growing a small business. His podcast episodes and
blog posts have provided a lot of inspriation for me and ideas for figuring out
what I&rsquo;m doing with SignalLeaf, and more.</p>

<p>In addition to his podcast on small business, Pat has a great <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/resources/">resources</a>
 page that lists not only info about podcasting, but about small business and
services that he uses and recommends for online business and blogging.</p>

<p>For his recommendations and tutorials on how to get started in podcasting,
checkout his page:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/how-to-start-a-podcast-podcasting-tutorial/">How to Start a Podcast – Pat’s Complete Step-By-Step Podcasting Tutorial</a></p></blockquote>

<p>This page covers podcasting with a series of videos and other links to podcasting
resources, including Pat&rsquo;s podcast equipment list in video #1.</p>

<h2>Ray Ortega</h2>

<p>Ray Ortega runs <a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/">The Podcasters' Studio</a>
as well as <a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">The Podcasters' Roundtable</a>.
If you&rsquo;re a podcaster, or want to become one, you should be looking at what
Ray is producing.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s Podcasters' Roundtable is a great format where he gets multiple podcasters
together on Google+ to discuss thoughts on specific podcasting topics, often
leading to debates and disagreements &ndash; though always professional and
courteous. If you&rsquo;d like to hear a wide range of opinions and debates on
podcasting topics, you should check out the Podcasters' Roundtable.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s other podcast, The Podcasters' Studio, focuses on all things podcasting.
He shares his experience and knowlege so, and offers tips on how to get your
podcast to the next level. This is one podcast you don&rsquo;t want to miss, when
you have yours up and running and you want to know what the pros are doing
to keep things running smoothly.</p>

<p>Check out Ray&rsquo;s recommended gear and his podcasts, here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://rayortega.com/gear/">Recommended Gear</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/thepodcastersstudio/">The Podcasters' Studio</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/podcastquicktips/">Podcast Quick Tips</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">Podcasters' Roundtable</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>What Resources Do You Pay Attention To?</h2>

<p>I know there are a ton of other great resources out there &ndash; including some that
I&rsquo;ve looked at but am not listing here. I&rsquo;d love to hear what your favorite
reosources are. <strong>Drop a comment below and link back to your site&rsquo;s equipment
list, your podcast tips, and your favorite resources from your favorite
podcasters!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
