<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: itunes | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/itunes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-20T16:08:58-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can't I Just Host My Podcast on iTunes?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-18T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/11/18/cant-i-just-host-my-podcast-on-itunes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was talking with someone about a podcast
they are starting, recently, and I asked if they already had a
plan for hosting it. The response I got was surpising:</p>

<blockquote><p>we have not yet gotten to the question of hosting the podcast yet.
i was assuming we would do it though iTunes, but i haven&rsquo;t thought farther than that.</p></blockquote>

<p>This seems to be an common misunderstanding about iTunes,
unfortunately. Your subscribers find you through iTunes, right?
So, isn&rsquo;t that where you host your podcast?</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Sorry, but no &ndash; podcasts distribution doesn&rsquo;t work like that.
Instead of uploading podcast episodes directly to iTunes, it&rsquo;s
only a network for finding and subscribing to podcast RSS feeds.
You still need your own host, bandwidth for streaming and RSS
for your podcast.</p>

<h2>iTunes And Google Maps</h2>

<p>Think of iTunes like Google Maps for podcasts. With Google
Maps, you can quickly and easily find
an address and a business, but Google Maps won&rsquo;t actually
take you there. You have to walk, drive, fly, or otherwise get
yourself to the real location that the map shows you.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/google-maps.png" width="400"></p>

<p>Podcasts in iTunes work the same way. iTunes will list your podcast
like Google Maps lists a business with an address and phone
number. You can quickly and easily find a podcast that iTunes
has listed, but your computer is only finding the address and
description of the podcast. The computer then has to travel to
the actual podcast location &ndash;  where the RSS feed is hosted.</p>

<p>When you subscribe to a podcast through iTunes, the podcast
listing that you found in iTunes was only the map for your
computer to find the actual podcast and subscribe to it.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.signalleaf.com/images/blog_posts/getupandcode.png" width="400"></p>

<p>In the case of <a href="http://getupandcode.com">Get Up And Code</a>, as
shown in the above screenshot, your computer will be redirected
to the RSS feed hosted at <a href="http://GetUpAndCode.com">http://GetUpAndCode.com</a> to create the
subscription and to get updates from their RSS feed.</p>

<h2>So, How <em>Do</em> I Host My Podcast?</h2>

<p>You can&rsquo;t host your podcast directly in iTunes, but there are
plenty of services and other options for hosting. The choices
come down to a few basic things:</p>

<ul>
<li>Do it all yourself</li>
<li>Get a podcasting plugin for a blogging platform</li>
<li>Pay for a podcast hosting service</li>
</ul>


<h4>DIY</h4>

<p>The &ldquo;do-it-yourself&rdquo; crowd tends to be the software developer and
techie person that can build the software and services needed
for hosting. If you&rsquo;re not a software developer, I don&rsquo;t recommend
this path. If you <em>are</em> a software developer, I still don&rsquo;t
recommend this path. It&rsquo;s tedious and painful, and fraught with
problems.</p>

<h4>Blogging Plugins</h4>

<p>If you&rsquo;re an avid blogger and you&rsquo;re already deeply entrenched
in to WordPress or any of the other major blogging platforms, you
can find plugins to make podcast hosting easy. You can upload a
file, use the <code>&lt;audio&gt;</code> tag in your post and be done with it. But
unless you&rsquo;re hosting your own servers and/or uploading your
episodes to another service, you&rsquo;re probably going to run in to
bandwidth and other limitations.</p>

<p>Everyone that I have spoken to,
that says they are hosting a podcast on WordPress, says they
eventually ran in to problems. It can be done for small podcasts,
and it can be cheap and easy. But with substantial growth in the
populartiy of the podcast comes potential for substantial cost
and problems.</p>

<h4>Podcast Hosting Services</h4>

<p>The last option listed, paying for a podcast host, is going to
be the best option for any serious podcast. You don&rsquo;t want to
manage file security. You don&rsquo;t want to deal with server
configuration. You don&rsquo;t want to build traffic reports, manually.
You just want to podcast.</p>

<p>There are a lot of options for hosting your podcast episodes,
including SignalLeaf. I don&rsquo;t claim
to be the one-and-only solution, or the one that fits everyone&rsquo;s
needs. I do have a very simple, very flexible solution, though.
If you&rsquo;re looking for a podcast host that focuses solely on
providing storage, bandwidth, RSS feed generation and traffic
analysis, then <strong>SignalLeaf is a great choice for you</strong>.</p>

<h2>Start Your Podcast Today!</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re starting a podcast, or are looking for a new host,
then you&rsquo;re in the right place! SignalLeaf offers a range
of flexible plans, with top-of-the-line podcast hosting and
streaming services.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://signalleaf.com/plans">Start Your Free Trial, Today!</a></strong>
You can get your podcast submitted to the iTunes &ldquo;map&rdquo; and
get subscribers driving to your new address, in minutes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
