<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pop culture | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/pop-culture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-14T09:28:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Podcast Spotlights: Pop Culture, Video Games And Being A Prepared Idiot]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/16/podcast-spotlights-pop-culture/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-16T08:17:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/16/podcast-spotlights-pop-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s good to be heard, to have your voice out there and share
your knowledge and experience with the world. Even better is
having some traffic so that you can know that you are being
heard. Sharing your favorite podcasts with your friends and
fellow bloggers and readers helps you become an authority on
the things you love, but also helps to spread the love by
giving those that deserve an audience a chance to be heard by
more people.</p>

<p>With that in mind, I&rsquo;ve got a few new podcasts that I want to
share with you today. With these, you&rsquo;ll pick up on some
pop culture references, plenty of video games, and you may even
walk away being a little more prepared for life.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The Prepared Idiot</h2>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/prepared-idiot.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Richard Barna is putting together a great show under the nanme
<a href="http://preparedidiot.com">The Prepared Idiot</a> &ndash; A how-to guide
for life, &ldquo;Asking the dumb questions so you don&rsquo;t have to!&rdquo;
He&rsquo;s got a few episodes recorded already, but only has one up
on the site and in <a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/The-Prepared-Idiot/rss">his RSS feed</a>,
but even the prologue episode is worth a listen to get you
in the mood for the great topics that he has lined up.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a huge fan of this approach to teaching and engaging people.
I use the tactic of asking the dumb questions, myself. If you
are wondering, I guarantee someone else is wondering the same
thing. Speaking up and asking the questions helps others more
than you think, and Richard&rsquo;s approach to his podcast is going
to be great because of this.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://preparedidiot.com">PreparedIdiot.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/The-Prepared-Idiot/rss">RSS Feed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-prepared-idiot/id796449625?mt=2">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/preparedidiot">Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/preparedidiot">Twitter</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>FragCast</h2>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/frag-castle.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>The guys at <a href="http://fragcastle.com/">FragCastle.com</a> have put
together a podcast to talk about their life and business as
independent game developers. Having won a game development
challenge sponsored by GitHub, these guys definitely know how
to get a game done and released.</p>

<p>In the first episode, they talk about their history, where they
came from, where they are goign and more. I was especially fond
of the story behind the game titled &ldquo;Rock Kickass&rdquo;, and the
stories about PAX and working on a game to demo at that
event.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re in to video games and indy games especially, you&rsquo;ll
want to check out the FragCast.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://fragcastle.com">FragCastle.com</a></li>
<li><a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/FragCast/rss">RSS Feed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/fragcast/id796282162?mt=2">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/FragCastle">Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/fragcastle">Twitter</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCB8a1AS5k43x5aaxrdX4SJw">YouTube</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>World Conquest</h2>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/world-conquest.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>&ldquo;Two guys talk about movies, video games, comics, nonsense, etc.
Yes, it&rsquo;s really that good.&rdquo; :) The description says it all.</p>

<p>This is two guys putting together
a fun, pop-culture, video game filled podcast and it&rsquo;s a ton of
fun. The first episode provides a little bit of background on the hosts &ndash;
cousins that developed their own little language to talk to each
other. They go in to a lot of talk about video games &ndash; everything
from Contra to Metal Gear and Guitar Hero.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for an entertaining podcast that brings back
memories from childhood video games and movies, you&rsquo;ll want to
check this one out.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.facebook.com/WCpodcast">Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/world-conquest/id796625394?mt=2">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://media.signalleaf.com/World-Conquest/rss">RSS Feed</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>More To Come</h2>

<p>This is the first post of podcast spotlights, but many more will
come. If you want to stay up to date with all the latest news
and spotlights, sign up for the mailing list below!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
