<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: equipment | Signals And Leaves]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/categories/equipment/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T09:22:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Derick Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Episode 4 With Craig McKeachie]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/14/episode-4-with-craig-mckeachie/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-14T07:53:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/14/episode-4-with-craig-mckeachie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Signals And Leaves, Episode 4 with <a href="http://www.funnyant.com/">Craig McKeachie</a>.</strong></p>

<p>Craig is starting up a new podcast on front-end web development
and is going through all the usual steps of getting started,
getting episodes recorded and getting them published.</p>

<p>This episode was recorded live at <a href="http://codemash.org">CodeMash 2014</a>
in a room that was full of noise from ventilation and other
environmental things. I used <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/">Audacity</a>
to clean up the noise, which worked surprisingly well. There is
some noise leftover during louder portions of the audio, though.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://media.signalleaf.com/player/Signals-And-Leaves/52d548eba8606a0200000004/" width="500" height="70" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<p>&nbsp;</p>

<h3>Podcast Pro-tip</h3>

<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t forget your guests' name or credentials.</strong></p>

<p>This one is rather embarassing, I must say. Right as I was
starting the episode with Craig, I forgot his name. My brain
went completely blank. We laught it off at the beginning of
the episode, but it makes for a bad start to the episode.</p>

<h3>Equipment</h3>

<p>This episode was recorded entirely with a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B003IJ3WIW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B003IJ3WIW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=signalleaf-20">Roland R05</a>.</p>

<iframe src="http://rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&bc1=000000&IS2=1&bg1=FFFFFF&fc1=000000&lc1=0000FF&t=signalleaf-20&o=1&p=8&l=as4&m=amazon&f=ifr&ref=ss_til&asins=B003IJ3WIW" style="width:120px;height:240px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>


<h3>Notes</h3>

<p>Podcasting is a great way to build an audience. It creates a
more intimate connection with listeners, vs written words.</p>

<p>Having multiple forms of media, such as book, blog, podcast,
etc, helps you build authority.</p>

<p>Podcasts introduce conversation instead of monologue. It&rsquo;s
easier to generate ideas, create something more valuable and
get more out of a conversation than a monologue, at times.</p>

<p>Choosing a name is hard &ndash; don&rsquo;t want to be too narrow, but
also want to identify and serve your audience, and deliver
value.</p>

<p>Getting feedback from trusted resources can give you confidence.
Even if you figure things out, find resources that teach you
and verify what you&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p>Podcast hosting eats up a lot of bandwidth. Be sure you have
a host that can handle the bandwidth. Find <a href="http://signalleaf.com">a podcast host</a>
when possible.</p>

<p>Average life of a podcast episode is 6 weeks. Bandwidth is
typically measured per month, but bandwidth for an episode can
be estimated from the 6 week download trend for past episodes.</p>

<p>Be careful of Feedburner and other free services. Feedburner
limits you to 512K feed size, and will drop episodes to keep
it small. FeedBlitz and other paid services won&rsquo;t introduce
this type of limit.</p>

<p>Your podcast needs RSS that is compatible with as many devices
and directories as possible. If your podcast hosting doesn&rsquo;t
ensure this, you will want to use a third party feed distribution
system like FeedBlitz.</p>

<p>Find a podcast / RSS host that provides the analytics you
need. <a href="http://signalleaf.com">SignalLeaf</a> gives you a breakdown of
RSS vs embeded player vs downloads, for traffic reports.</p>

<p>Trade iTunes directory reviews with other podcasters. Find podcasts
that you&rsquo;re interested in. Listen to a few episodes, then contact
the author and ask them to review your podcast in exchange for
you reviewing them.</p>

<p>You need a blog for your podcast, whether it&rsquo;s part of your
primary website or a separate blog. Write a post for each
episode with a short list of notes from the episode, at least.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<p><a href="http://funnyant.com">Craig McKeachie / FunnyAnt</a></p>

<p><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com">Cliff Ravenscraft / Podcast Answerman</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.softwarebyrob.com/">Rob Wahling</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Pat Flynn / Smart Passive Income</a></p>

<p><a href="http://mixergy.com">Mixergy</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.entrepreneuronfire.com/">Entrepreneur On Fire</a></p>

<p><a href="http://jsjabber.com">JavaScript Jabber</a></p>

<p><a href="http://feedblitz.com">FeedBlitz</a></p>

<p><a href="http://getupandcode.com">GetUpAndCode.com</a></p>

<p><a href="http://simpleprogrammer.com">SimpleProgrammer.com</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Other Podcasters' Resources]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-11T09:18:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2014/01/11/other-podcasters-resources</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have <a href="/equipment">my own equipment list</a>, my <a href="/how-to-podcast">how to get started</a>
and more info on this blog. It&rsquo;s the place where I&rsquo;m putting toghether info
from my experiences and experiments, to try and help people that are new
to podcasting get up and running quickly. But there&rsquo;s also a ton of other
resources out there, from other podcasters. I&rsquo;ve oftend looked at these
blog posts and page for equipment ideas, how-to info, and more. And I wanted
to share some of these so that you could also benefit from the knowledge
and experience that I&rsquo;ve been able to benefit from.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Scott Hanselman</h2>

<p><a href="http://hanselman.com">Scott Hanselman</a> is a well known software developer and technologist, and is
a host of several podcasts that I know and love, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://hanselminutes.com/">Hanselminutes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thisdeveloperslife.com/">This Developer&rsquo;s Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratchetandthegeek.com/">Ratchet &amp; the Geek</a></li>
</ul>


<p>If you&rsquo;re in to technology and/or software development, you should check out the
podcasts that Scott hosts. They&rsquo;re great.</p>

<p>He also has a great blog posts about the equipment, software, process and
services that he uses for his podcats, titled:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.hanselman.com/blog/HowToStartYourFirstPodcastEquipmentEditingPublishingAndMore.aspx">How to start your first podcast &ndash; equipment, editing, publishing and more</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The title says it all, really &ndash; if you want to know what Scott uses and how he
works, check out this post. It is full of equipment recommendations, quick tips
and ideas that will help you get things up and running pretty quickly.</p>

<h2>Cliff Ravenscraft</h2>

<p>Cliff Ravenscraft is known as the <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/">Podcast Answerman</a>
for a good reason. His podcast, podcast tutorials, courses and other information
have become one of the defacto-standards in the podcasting industry. If you&rsquo;re
not familiar with Cliffs work, you need to check it out. He has a great list of
equipment, videos, tips and other resources all over his site, including:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/equipment/">Equipment</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/resources/">Resources</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/atoz/">Podcasting, A to Z</a> (paid course)</li>
</ul>


<p>And be sure to check out <a href="http://podcastanswerman.com/category/podcastanswerman/">Cliff&rsquo;s podcast</a>
which is a wealth of knowledge and information on all things podcasting.</p>

<h2>Pat Flynn</h2>

<p>Pat Flynn&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/">Smart Passive Income</a> podcast,
blog and other resources are a place that I like to go when I&rsquo;m looking for
information on running and growing a small business. His podcast episodes and
blog posts have provided a lot of inspriation for me and ideas for figuring out
what I&rsquo;m doing with SignalLeaf, and more.</p>

<p>In addition to his podcast on small business, Pat has a great <a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/resources/">resources</a>
 page that lists not only info about podcasting, but about small business and
services that he uses and recommends for online business and blogging.</p>

<p>For his recommendations and tutorials on how to get started in podcasting,
checkout his page:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.smartpassiveincome.com/how-to-start-a-podcast-podcasting-tutorial/">How to Start a Podcast – Pat’s Complete Step-By-Step Podcasting Tutorial</a></p></blockquote>

<p>This page covers podcasting with a series of videos and other links to podcasting
resources, including Pat&rsquo;s podcast equipment list in video #1.</p>

<h2>Ray Ortega</h2>

<p>Ray Ortega runs <a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/">The Podcasters' Studio</a>
as well as <a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">The Podcasters' Roundtable</a>.
If you&rsquo;re a podcaster, or want to become one, you should be looking at what
Ray is producing.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s Podcasters' Roundtable is a great format where he gets multiple podcasters
together on Google+ to discuss thoughts on specific podcasting topics, often
leading to debates and disagreements &ndash; though always professional and
courteous. If you&rsquo;d like to hear a wide range of opinions and debates on
podcasting topics, you should check out the Podcasters' Roundtable.</p>

<p>Ray&rsquo;s other podcast, The Podcasters' Studio, focuses on all things podcasting.
He shares his experience and knowlege so, and offers tips on how to get your
podcast to the next level. This is one podcast you don&rsquo;t want to miss, when
you have yours up and running and you want to know what the pros are doing
to keep things running smoothly.</p>

<p>Check out Ray&rsquo;s recommended gear and his podcasts, here:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://rayortega.com/gear/">Recommended Gear</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/thepodcastersstudio/">The Podcasters' Studio</a></li>
<li><a href="http://thepodcastersstudio.com/category/podcasts/podcastquicktips/">Podcast Quick Tips</a></li>
<li><a href="http://podcastersroundtable.com/">Podcasters' Roundtable</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>What Resources Do You Pay Attention To?</h2>

<p>I know there are a ton of other great resources out there &ndash; including some that
I&rsquo;ve looked at but am not listing here. I&rsquo;d love to hear what your favorite
reosources are. <strong>Drop a comment below and link back to your site&rsquo;s equipment
list, your podcast tips, and your favorite resources from your favorite
podcasters!</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Waiting For The Right Equipment. Start Podcasting Now!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/29/stop-waiting-for-the-right-equipment/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-29T06:48:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.signalleaf.com/blog/2013/12/29/stop-waiting-for-the-right-equipment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There&rsquo;s not shortage of people and websites claiming that they
have &ldquo;the right equipment&rdquo; for you to get started with your
podcast. Even <a href="/equipment">this blog</a>
has an equipment list. And there seems to be a constant clammor
for more, all around the internet. I&rsquo;ll make it simple
for you, though: <strong>start with what you have, or pick something
quickly and move on</strong>.</p>

<p>Choosing the right
equipment or the right software is a waste of time right now.
You need to be more concerned with preparing and producing the
content of your podcast at this point.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>The &ldquo;Right Equipment&rdquo; Is The Wrong Idea</h2>

<p>When you were learning to ride a bicycle, did your parents buy
you a $10,000 racing bike and enter you in the Tour de France?
When you were teaching your child to walk, did you buy them a
$300 pair of running shoes and ask them to run the Boston
Marathon? Of course not! The idea of that is ridiculous! Why,
then, do we expect people to buy new equipment and &ldquo;do it
right&rdquo; when they are starting out with podcasting?</p>

<p>Wait&hellip; you don&rsquo;t believe that this is happening? A casual search
on twitter reveals a number of people frustrated or waiting
because they don&rsquo;t have the right equipment, or asking about what
equipment they should get before they start.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/SignalLeaf">@SignalLeaf</a> I have been researching this for weeks now and everything I have read has said the complete opposite to not start cheap. Lol</p>&mdash; Michael Wright (@MrWrightNow78) <a href="https://twitter.com/MrWrightNow78/statuses/417126714884780032">December 29, 2013</a></blockquote>


<p>These tweets often look like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>I want to start a podcast, but I don&rsquo;t have the right equipment</p></blockquote>

<p>Or</p>

<blockquote><p>What equipment do I need to start a podcast?</p></blockquote>

<p>These are questions on which people often get stuck. They assume
that you need a setup that looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/recording-studio.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m going to let you in on a little secret&hellip; <strong>your podcast
&ldquo;studio&rdquo; is going to look more like this, when you start</strong>:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog_posts/laptop.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Let me make this very clear: <strong>if you have a computer with a mic and an internet connection, you
already have the right equipment.</strong></p>

<h2>A Reward With No Effort</h2>

<p><a href="http://getupandcode.com">John Sonmez</a> summed up the problem quite nicely:</p>

<blockquote><p>Most people have it backwards.
They buy a treadmill thinking they will run because they spent $1k.
Or they buy new running shoes or a guitar.</p>

<p>The ones who actually succeed, run in old sneaker and tell themselves that when they have been running for 3 months they can buy real running shoes.
The ones who don&rsquo;t give up early are the ones who borrow a friend&rsquo;s piece of crap guitar and promise themselves that once they learn 10 songs they&rsquo;ll buy their own guitar.</p>

<p>When you already have the reward, you lack the motivation and you don&rsquo;t appreciate the instrument.
How do you appreciate $5,000 golf clubs if you never played with $50 golf clubs?</p></blockquote>

<p>The same is true of any reward, or any nice equipment for any purpose. Buying
the right equipment now is not a guarantee that you are going to produce a
great podcast. Wait until you have gone through the first experimental stages
and you know that you want to continue, having proven that you can produce
content.</p>

<p><strong>Once you have shown that you can produce content and get it delivered,
reward the effort with better equipment.</strong> But don&rsquo;t rely on the equipment to
make your job easy. It takes effort, no matter what equipment you are using.
The reason others make it look effortless, is not because of the equipment
they have. It is because they have struggled through
the learning curve and have mastered the tools and processes; they have earned
the equipment, the effortless production, and the audience.</p>

<p><strong>So get started now, with what you have.</strong> Earn the rewards of better equipment,
and build your audience and skillset through your efforts.</p>

<h2>A Computer, A Mic, And Internet Connection</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re reading this, you&rsquo;re using a computer.
Your computer may be called an iPhone or an iPad, it may be
an Android or a laptop of some sort. There are a lot of different
computers with a lot of different names. But they are all
computers and most of them can be used for recording your
podcast. <strong>The easiest computer to use for your first episode
is going to be a laptop, but nearly any computer and microphone
will work</strong>.</p>

<p>Speaking of microphones, that is something you need to
have in order to record your podcast. But,
nearly every computer comes with some sort of microphone built
in to it these days. If you have a headset with a mic, for gaming
or to use for Skyp and other chat services, that&rsquo;s even
better! You&rsquo;ll get better sound out of a headset than you will
out of a laptop mic. But <strong>I wouldn&rsquo;t let a laptop mic stop you
from starting your podcast</strong>. If it can record your voice, it can
be used to produce your podcast.</p>

<p>Lastly, <strong>you&rsquo;ll need access to the internet with a
fair upload speed</strong>. Smart phones, tablets, laptops and PCs of all sorts
have built-in internet connections that let us get online and
find everything we never wanted to know, and more! This same
internet connection is needed for uploading your podcast
episode to your podcast hosting service. But don&rsquo;t worry too
much about this. <strong>The connection is only really needed when you
are uploading your episode</strong>. You won&rsquo;t need a connection to
record a podcast, if you are only recording yourself or if
you have all of your guests in the same room as you.</p>

<h2>No More Excuses</h2>

<p>The truth is, <strong>a lot of people use the idea of not having &ldquo;the
right equipment&rdquo; as an excuse</strong> &ndash; even if they don&rsquo;t realize it.
It&rsquo;s easy to hide behind the
idea that you need to spend a lot of money on equipment. It&rsquo;s
easy to say that you&rsquo;ll get started once you save up enough to
get the right microphone. It&rsquo;s easy to put this off, because
it takes no effort. It takes no work. There is no committment
involved in not doing anything. Talk is cheap, and talking
about how you want to do this, but can&rsquo;t because you don&rsquo;t
the right equipment, is the cheapest of the cheap.</p>

<p><strong>The first podcast experience that you have is more about you
than anything else</strong>. It&rsquo;s about you getting comforable with the
idea of recording, of producing something, and putting your
thoughts out there for the world to hear. It&rsquo;s not about the
equipment that you do or don&rsquo;t have.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s like <a href="http://jennybrewster.com/podcasting-equipment/">Jenny Brewster</a>
said:</p>

<blockquote><p>Record in the Cupboard if that’s where you’re happy</p></blockquote>

<p>Sure, if you happen to have
some equipment already, it might make your first episode sound
better. But it&rsquo;s not about the quality, when you&rsquo;re starting
out. <strong>Starting is all about getting up and running quickly.</strong></p>

<p>Yes, there is at a bare minimum amount of
equipment that you do need. The good news is that you
have everything you need, already.</p>

<h2>Published And Flawed Is Better Than Not Published</h2>

<p>This really is the point of what I&rsquo;m trying to say: it&rsquo;s far
better to have published a flawed podcast with less than perfect
audio quality, than to wait for the right equipment.</p>

<p><strong>Podcasting is like any other skill &ndash; it takes practices, not
money, to get good at it</strong>. Producing your first podcast may
feel awkward, but this is normal. Everyone goes through this
the first time they record something. But you&rsquo;ll find
that over time, your podcast quality will naturally improve.
You&rsquo;ll get better at speaking. You&rsquo;ll get better at positioning
the microphone. You&rsquo;ll be become more comfortable, and you&rsquo;ll
enjoy the process much more.</p>

<p><em>Don&rsquo;t wait for the right equipment. Use the equipment that you
have right now, and get started!</em></p>

<h3>Want To Know More About Getting Started?</h3>

<p>This blog post is the first chapter from my e-book,
<a href="/how-to-podcast">Prepare, Produce, Publish: Your first podcast, in 3 easy steps!</a>.
If you&rsquo;d like to know more about getting started, <strong>how to record your
first episode, where to publish the files and how to get your
podcast online quickly</strong>, get the e-book! <strong>It&rsquo;s FREE</strong> when you
sign up to receive all the latest podcasting news and tips! <strong>Just drop
your email address in to the form below and you&rsquo;ll receive the e-book
at no charge</strong>.</p>

<script async src="http://blog.signalleaf.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
